PAUL: Alright guys, so I hope I am audible to everyone.
PAUL: Because we'll be starting this, we're starting the next…
PAUL: Guys, from next class, I will start from 9-5, okay?
PAUL: Because this is the first class, so just I'm waiting for others, but I hope from next class you guys will be ready from
PAUL: I'm vital.
PAUL: Alright, so… okay, I feel a little bit less alert on this camera, just okay.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I hope, this one is better somehow.
PAUL: Alright, so today's agenda, so a few things that I have already published in Notion. That will be the main document hub for this entire course, or at least the time that I will be taking all the classes.
PAUL: Today's agenda is pretty much simple, it's all about the installation, because from tomorrow, we will start the actual content. Today, we'll be focusing on installation of the tools. As I know, in this course, there are a lot of beginners.
PAUL: Okay, so the main focus will be, like, what are the tools that I will be installing? Because I use a very specific
PAUL: setup tools, okay, in other courses also, that's why we always see the first class, basically, like, after the introduction, a class, just to do the installation of things. So, majorly, we'll be using VS Code, but sometimes I do use different types of IDEs.
PAUL: Okay. So, we will have just a complete checklist that everything is installed by the end of this session, because from tomorrow's session, we'll be just doing the execution.
PAUL: Alright, so the timer has completed, so let me just stop sharing the screen.
PAUL: Okay, and now we will officially start the class.
PAUL: Alright, so I think I can start sharing my… Okay, so stick top 3.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, the first link that I'll be sharing, okay, so, like, this will be the main hub. The other links will be updated in your course dashboard also, okay? But, I'm sharing this link. Everybody, please do bookmark.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, this will be the main content, and majorly all the research papers, the external links that I'll be sharing, everything will be available.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that you guys, keep this bookmark.
PAUL: So, let me just, share this link in the chat so that you guys can access it.
PAUL: Okay, and just let me know that, yes, you guys can… Okay, am I on mute?
PAUL: Please let me know that I hope that I am not on mute, as Push Sengal is telling.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, you can hear. You're fine. Please have a check to your audio.
PAUL: Alright, okay, so everybody just see the link is working or not.
PAUL: the link that I have shared, again, I am sharing. I know people will be joining a bit late, okay? So, like, this will be the main homepage that I'll be, like, maintaining it in Notion for everything, okay? Like, going forward, like, inside the
PAUL: this particular part, if you have some type of PDF, you will get the link, additional links of research papers and everything, I'll be mentioning in this Notion database. So, going forward, it becomes easier. It means that
PAUL: without opening the leisure website, I can say. You can watch the video, or you can keep everything in one place. Okay, so I think that it'd be much better to easily access the course resources.
PAUL: Alright, so today, so this, as you can see here, very specifically, the software, okay, I will just increase the font. I hope it's, now better visible. Okay, so this checklist that Google will follow today. Okay, most of the things are already installed in my system.
PAUL: Okay, so what I can do, because right now, as we know that, there are multiple operating systems.
PAUL: Okay, so I will take 3 major operating systems for now, okay, like Windows, majorly, I think you guys will be on Windows or Mac, okay? But I know that few people might be using Linux.
PAUL: Okay, so Linux, that's why I will keep it at the end. In the chat, let me know if anybody is using Linux.
PAUL: Can you please share the link again? Yes, for sure. Yes, anybody on Linux right now? Using any Ubuntu-based flavor, or anything?
PAUL: Abhishek Singh, yes. Vivesh, yes. Satesh, Tivari, yes, okay? Like, I know there are students from other courses also, okay, so, like, if everything is installed, it's great, okay, but right now, the main idea is to
PAUL: Like, many students are new here. Can we… WSL? Yes, WSL is also fine. Like, in Windows, if you have very specifically WSL, that also works, okay? Now, the priority will be, like, Windows.
PAUL: Okay, then, Mac, and then finally I will come to Linux. Because I think that major, most of the students will be on Windows. Okay, then comes the Mac priority, and finally on Linux, okay? So,
PAUL: we can, start the installation. Okay, so the first thing is, you need a Python distribution, okay?
PAUL: So, like, I feel that, like, Anaconda, you can use, because right now, even, UV, majorly, I will be using UV. Anaconda is a big package. Okay, a lot of things. Like, how many of you have Anaconda installed in your system? Please let me know with a yes. If it's not, please let me know with a no in the chat.
PAUL: then I will get an idea. Because, like, people have been using Annaponda for many, many years. Like, I feel that I've been using it from back 2016.
PAUL: Okay? No. Alright, fine.
PAUL: Okay, so the anaconda distribution, as you can see simply here.
PAUL: Okay, so you can simply click on Get Started. Okay.
PAUL: Like, it is not necessary. Okay, so I have already, shared the link.
PAUL: If you go to the software checklist.
PAUL: Okay, so this will be the main checklist that you have. Okay, and here you will be getting the link. Okay, so if you click on this link, you will be getting the distributors directly. So I have already given the link, guys.
PAUL: Okay, now the question comes, there are two distributors, okay, the mean anaconda, so this site, the left-hand side that you have.
PAUL: Where do I find the checklist, okay? So, see, the link that I have provided you, okay, so if you go to this particular link.
PAUL: And here, you will be getting, like, 8 November 2025 tools and installation. So this is basically the checklist that you have, okay?
PAUL: Is this part clear, from where we'll be getting the checklist?
PAUL: Please share it with me again, okay, alright?
PAUL: I'm again sharing the link. Everybody, please access. People who are joining late, just be sure from next class to join by 9-5. I will start the class from 9.5.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, I hope everybody got the software checklist.
PAUL: H?
PAUL: Okay, Amit, great. Like, if you have many contacts, you don't need to do anything.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Alright, so now I have opened the checklist page. Now, in this particular checklist page, so we will start with the Python distribution. This is the first step. The idea is, like.
PAUL: you can, do step-by-step, like, all the major tools that we'll be using. As in this course, we will be widely using AWS, so it's the AWS CLI also. I have kept it.
PAUL: So, let's jump into… so, as you can see here, the link is here. Okay, so for Anaconda. And the other link that I have given for, Python.
PAUL: Why I've given two links? So, let's try to understand. So, Python, if you directly just install Python, it's a lightweight package. Okay, it means that at every point of time, you need to install the packages, very specific.
PAUL: Okay, okay, like, it's pure Python compiler and nothing here. But with Anaconda, okay, you will have a very specific environment called as the base environment, okay, and within that particular environment, you will be having the default packages, okay?
PAUL: So, like, I feel that if you're a beginner, okay, so always start with Anacondo, but if you're an intermediate user, you can always work with Python.
PAUL: Now, this particular package is a big package, okay? So, if I just…
PAUL: click on here, okay, and if I… you can see, for 3 operating systems, like Windows… Okay, so I will just do it for Mac for now. You can see this is close to 754MB, and after installation, it will become, like, close to 8GB or 10GB space that will take.
PAUL: Okay? So, for that, so, according to your operating system, please do download.
PAUL: Like, I hope for Mac users, you know that whether you are on an Apple Silicon chip or an Intel chip. Based on that, you can do your, downloads. For Windows, it's pretty much simple. There is a single link going, so no confusion. You can directly download this. Okay, and for Linux users.
PAUL: Okay, so the first link, majorly, that we'll be working with. I hope that everybody is on X86-based systems, okay? So please do the download for
PAUL: Now, this is a bigger package. If you don't need this, okay, if you feel that, no, I am an intermediate user, then I can directly start working with Python, in that particular case, what you can do, you can just go to the Python version, okay, so, like,
PAUL: you can use 3.14, it is the latest one, okay? But, somewhere, because I feel that we can work with 3.13. Majorly in this course, I'll be working with 3.12 and 3.13.
PAUL: Okay, because I feel that 3.13 is much more stable, but there are few, like, till now, bugs are there. So, in this course, we won't be using 3.15. Okay, it's a pre-release. So, either you install Anaconda or directly Python.
PAUL: You don't need to install both.
PAUL: I repeat myself, you don't need to install both.
PAUL: If you have a lot of memory, okay, in your system, your RAM is good, you have more than 500GB, okay, you can simply install Anaconda. But if you have lesser RAM and everything, then I feel that you can directly download the Python. So, totally up to you. This is a simple choice that I give you.
PAUL: Okay, so after, like, when you will be installing Anaconda, it will take around close to, I feel that, 7 to 10G, depends upon the operating system.
PAUL: You can, directly download 3.13. 3.13, that will be majorly using, okay? Because, as you can see, this was last year.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, 3.14 is the major one. So, most of the things we'll be doing on 3.13, as it's pretty much stable now, I feel. Okay, and sometimes we might use 3.14, there is no restriction. Like, majorly for this course, 3.13 and 3.14.
PAUL: Okay, anything above 3.11 is our priority.
PAUL: I've been working with 3.12 for the past 1 year. Okay, so I know most of the things that support, so you guys can install 3. So, as you can see here, are you looking for a specific version? Okay, so yes, so simply the idea is, you will be clicking on this link. Okay, the download option is there.
PAUL: Okay, if you want to only install Python.
PAUL: Okay? Now, for using Anaconda, okay, so simply, like, if I… okay, I will show you step-by-step how to do the installation. So right now, I am on Mac, so I cannot show you the…
PAUL: Windows installation, I'll be taking a volunteer, and I'll be showing you step-by-step. So, initially, let me just do the installation for Mac, okay? So, as you can see here, 64 feet, I will just click on this, okay, and it will take some time.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see here, for me it's showing close to 5 minutes, close to 1 GB.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone please start the download process. Okay, I will wait for 5 minutes.
PAUL: whoever wants to install Anaconda. I will prefer Anaconda. If you have RAM, at least more than 8GB of RAM in your system, and you have space, at least more than
PAUL: 200 to 300 GB.
PAUL: If you have something less than 50 GB, that is… then I will suggest directly start working with Python, okay?
PAUL: Yes, Krishna, that is fine, it's just a warning, okay? So, not a big deal. We'll be using 3.13 and 3.14.
PAUL: Because, finally, like, once this is available, then I'll be letting know, like, I'll be using a lot in this course UV. That will be the next thing, okay, UV.
PAUL: Okay, so this will be the third step. So, first of all, just install Python.
PAUL: Okay, so for me, it's right now getting installed. So everybody, please do download.
PAUL: Please start the download process if you want to install an account.
PAUL: Okay, Adam?
PAUL: from the class, anybody whose system is keen, you have a good internet, okay, and you feel that you can share your screen, okay? And the idea is that in your system, the Anaconda is downloaded, but not installed till.
PAUL: Okay, you guys can raise your hand. You can let me know in the chat, yes, Paul, like, I can share my screen, okay? The idea is you should have a good internet.
PAUL: I have already shared the checklist with you, please.
PAUL: Okay, I'm sharing the link again, okay? Ricky? Alright, I have good internet.
PAUL: You can make, alright? So, like, I can take one or two participants for Windows and Linux very specifically.
PAUL: Okay, Ricky is there, so… I will just unmute Ricky.
Ricky: Yeah, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes, Ricky, I can hear you, okay? Just wait, I will add you to the panel list. In the meantime, just be sure Anaconda is downloaded in your system, okay?
Ricky: Yeah, I have already downloaded.
PAUL: Alright, then I will add you to Pamelist.
PAUL: It's pretty much straightforward, just one or two options that needs to be selected.
PAUL: Alright, I will stop sharing. Ricky, please start sharing your story.
PAUL: Already downloaded, great, first I will go ahead with Windows. Okay. Then I will come to Mac, and finally I will come to Linux.
PAUL: Yes, or Ricky, I think you can start sharing.
Ricky: Let me know if you can see my screen.
PAUL: Alright, okay, so just wait. So, you have double-click on that, okay, and right now…
PAUL: This is the first step. So, right now, the destiny… go back, go back, go back, okay, go back, start, yes. So, this is, how it starts, okay? This is the initial screen. I think everybody can see the screen.
PAUL: Or let me know that whether it's getting downloaded, till now for somebody.
PAUL: Should we download Minicanta? Yes, you can do Miniconda also, I have no issues with that. If you have lesser RAM, lesser memory in your system, yes, you can go ahead with Minicanta. Minicanta is a lighter version of Anaconda.
PAUL: Okay, no problem with the nightly.
PAUL: Yes, so for everybody, please let me know that the download has been done. Can we proceed ahead with the installation?
PAUL: for Windows. Right now, we are doing it for the Windows.
PAUL: Yes, Anaconda Navigator comes with Anaconda, so don't win.
PAUL: Alrighty, Mac for you, I will come to Mac after this. Okay, Muthraser, don't worry. So, we will start with the installation of
PAUL: Honda in Windows right now. After that, we will jump to
PAUL: Mac, and then finally, Linux. Alright, so let's start. So, the first option, as you can see, Welcome Anaconda 3, 64-bit fine. Go to Next.
PAUL: Okay, just do, yes, I agree.
PAUL: Okay, so I think just me works for me most of the time. If you have multiple users, then you can select the all user option, or just go with just me, okay? Now, this is a very, very important part. At any point of time, you have to remember this particular path. By default, Anaconda 3 gets installed in your
PAUL: user, or basically, right now, the user is Ricky. So, sorry, whatever the username. Like, he, users.
PAUL: your username, and within that Anaconda folder, or basically the Anaconda 3 folder, will be available.
PAUL: Okay? So, always remember this path. Okay, you can, give a custom destination also. If you feel that in your C drive, you have less.
PAUL: amount of, I can say, storage, okay, and you feel that your D drive is completely, like, you have a lot of storage, you can do the installation there also. So this is totally up to you.
PAUL: Okay? So, totally up to you.
PAUL: Alright, I will look into that. Okay, Balaji just wait, don't worry about that, I will come to everyone.
PAUL: Anaconda… it will be 3, guys, Ranjit. It will be Anaconda 3, not 2.7.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, Mandeep, I'm getting your messages, just wait.
PAUL: Alright, now, just click on Next. As you can see here, it will take around 5.2GB very specifically.
PAUL: Okay, now from here, very specifically, you can register these things, okay? So, first of all, add Anaconda 3 to my path, select this option, very, very important.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, by default, it will be added to your system variable. It means that everywhere it can be accessed.
PAUL: Then comes register Anaconda 3 as my default Python. So here, as you can see, 3.13 is there.
PAUL: Please select that.
PAUL: view, okay, a version of… fine, that is, okay? So, the first two options. And finally, clear the path…
PAUL: package catcher upon completion, even select this option. So right now, all the options that we are
PAUL: Okay, it generally reduces and it cleans some unwanted files after the installation.
PAUL: Increase the font size, so this window font, I don't think it can be increased, guys. Okay, it's pretty much standard. I think Ricky is using a monitor very specifically, that's right.
PAUL: It's looking a little small, but I hope that you are selecting these three options, okay? Select the last option also, here's the catch-up.
PAUL: Ricky, select the last option, please. Clear the… yeah, just select that option.
PAUL: Okay, all these three options are selected.
PAUL: Why this option is not recommended? It means that if you have a default Python compiler, then it becomes a conflict. Okay, so right now, the idea is that there is no compiler.
PAUL: Okay? And Anaconda 3 Python, the Python that comes from Anaconda, it becomes the default.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why it's telling not recommended.
PAUL: Okay, and but in our case, we know that we don't have multiple micros.
PAUL: Okay? Now, just click on Install. Okay, now we will start the installation, guys. So, yes, click on Install. It will take some time.
PAUL: As you can see, a lot of packages that are getting Streamlit, XRA, Dask, okay, Data Shader, Imbalanced Learn, IMLearn, basically, Panel, so these all packages comes pre-installed with Anaconda. Okay, in the default environment, I'll be talking about the default environment, which is basically the base environment.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody for Windows, please do the installation. Okay, don't focus on the chats, a lot of things are going on. You people might face some issues, don't worry, I will come to the issues, okay?
PAUL: All right, R, Rajendra, due to low disk space, I am within 3.12. Okay, fine, not an issue. I already installed grade 1?
PAUL: Cynthia, you are asking a quick question. I had Python 3 router with Anaconda. Is that gonna create conflicts? No. If you have already Python, then why you were installed Anaconda?
PAUL: Okay, if you already have Python in your system, don't install anaconda.I.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, the idea is you should have only one, whether that, pure Python, okay, or the anaconda. That is always the priority. I have Python 3.10. 3.10 is fine, not an issue. You can upgrade Python 3.10 to 3.13A. Shasha.
PAUL: Okay? So, if you are having… just be sure, yes, 3.9, like, somebody told I'm using 3.9.
PAUL: please upgrade that 3.9 to 3.13. Okay, you can do an upgrade, or simply delete that, okay? You can do the uninstallation, or a simple upgrade is also fine.
PAUL: Deepak is asking, can't we use VS Code instead? We will come to VS Code. VS Code is an IDE. First, we need the compiler. Once we have the compiler, then we will come to the ID.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: Arshu Navine is Arab can't see the live chat. Just click on the chat option, you will be able to see.
PAUL: Hutch.
PAUL: I have 3.11, Russia, fine, 3.11 is also fine.
PAUL: Ramatrishna 3.13, alright, 3.13 is fine, okay? So, as you can see here, right now, on the screen, the installation is done, it's showing completed, okay? So, just click on next.
PAUL: Okay, and click on Next.
PAUL: Okay, so welcome to Anaconda. I think a webpage will open and launch Anaconda Navigator, okay? So, welcome to already, you can click on Finish, not a problem.
PAUL: Okay, so I think one page will open. Okay, just close this page. That is of no use.
PAUL: And the Araconda Navigator will open.
PAUL: This hole… Just wait, I think it will open, yes.
PAUL: Okay, it will take some time. This is a heavy package, so it takes few seconds, depending upon your system rank.
PAUL: Alright, Vikram, so if you have just clicked on the install, after that, just next, next turn, okay, your content navigator will open. Don't worry about it.
PAUL: Hari Kumar is asking how to enable. What you want to enable, Hari, please let me know. For Mac, I will come, don't worry.
PAUL: Okay, in Mac, it's pretty much direct, you don't have to click on anything or anything.
PAUL: the chat option, Hari, okay? I think that how to enable… by default, it is enabled for all participants, the chat option. So really, you don't need to worry about that.
PAUL: Okay, it means that I don't… I cannot close the chat option.
PAUL: Everybody should be able to see the charts.
PAUL: Anaconda is blocked in my office, Sarania. Alright, fine, if Anaconda is not there, just check, you can use Python or not, Sarania, in that particular… because I know if you're doing it in office laptop, sometimes it might be blocked.
PAUL: You cannot use in-office laptops. If it's a personal laptop, no issue. In that case, just check, do you have access to Python or not?
PAUL: Okay, because in this class, I will be coming to local, and then I will be coming to online IDs also. Like, directly from where you can get an access to the compiler.
PAUL: Okay, so it's telling, it's not recommended right now, you don't need to, okay.
PAUL: Okay, so, yeah, remind me later if Pentru.
PAUL: Alright, so sign-up is not required, okay, later on you can do this stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, signing is not required.
PAUL: Simply, the idea is that, okay, it should be available. Now, click on the Windows button.
PAUL: Windows button and search for Anaconda Prompt.
PAUL: Okay, yes, and a contact prompt is there, the first one. Okay.
PAUL: Now, simply type your conda.
PAUL: And hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so simply you can see that, yes, Conda is available.
PAUL: Okay, as simple as that. So, right now, if you, write Honda and hit enter in the Anaconda prompt, okay, if you don't get
PAUL: Like, these options very specifically, it means that there is some type of issue.
PAUL: Okay, that issue I will look into for now, but don't worry.
PAUL: We'll be using Anaconda or Python ID. See, Anaconda or Python is basically the distribution provider. The ID is like VS Code.
PAUL: Okay, VIN, sir, cursor, those are IDs.
PAUL: Junaid, don't get confused. Right now, we are working just with the compiler, or basically the Python distribution provider, who is providing the Python.
PAUL: Okay? Just be clear on these small, small concepts, always.
PAUL: Again, can you use Google Collab? Amigen, I… I will be using Google Collab, but rarely in this course.
PAUL: Okay? Because I need a full IDE access most of the time. If it is a Jupyter notebook.
PAUL: Okay, then also I will prefer using my local system, because in Google Collab, the version of the packages are totally different, probably the one that I will be using, okay? So, majorly, it will be local stuff, guys.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone, please check and let me know in Windows that when you open Anaconda prompt and you type Conda and hit enter, you are getting all those options. Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Signet is not required in Beij.
PAUL: Yes, Sanjay, I will come.
PAUL: to Mac. First, Windows, then Mac, then Linux. So, Mac guys, please wait. I will come to you in 5 minutes.
PAUL: Thanks, I can see these commands in the conduct prompt. Alright, Amit, great. Yes, got all these options.
PAUL: Okay, VS code with, is good enough. Yes, it is good enough, Amit.
PAUL: Okay,
PAUL: Alright, Sanjay, all options not coming, okay? Sanjay, or… see, these options should come. Like, all options, like, probably one or two options might change because of an OS, but at least these options should be visible. Sanjay, please have a check. When you…
PAUL: like, type Conda and hit enter. Okay? Got them all, okay, Kamachi, great.
PAUL: Sorry, I'm in the installation status already, background. Okay, I will just wait 2 or 3 minutes. Starting from base itself, great, Sanjay. Yeah, starting from base, if it is, fine.
PAUL: Okay, you will see this base within the packets. One thing you can do, Ricky, just place your Ctrl plus plus, so that the font is bigger in this window.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Control++.
PAUL: Ready? Yes, just make it and make this window a bit thick.
PAUL: Don't send messages in that, message forum right now, Rajesh Kuman. Okay. So, right now, I'm not looking there, I'm just looking into the Zoom chat.
PAUL: I'll be looking there probably after the class, so sending the message. Okay, just send your message here, because once 10 people type, it's very hard for me.
PAUL: Okay, so this option, you should be able to see base. Okay.
PAUL: Now, base is basically the environment here, at any point of time, okay? So, I'll be coming to creating virtual environments later on, but at least it should be available in your system.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, others, please let me know, whoever is having problem, don't worry, okay? Like, after…
PAUL: the class, everyone, I'll be asking you to share your screen, whoever is having the problem, okay? Right now, I don't want to look into the problems, because others for whom it is working, then there will be an interruption in the flow of the class.
PAUL: Okay, somebody needs the Notion link, alright. Notion link, again, I'll be sharing.
PAUL: Please let me know for how many of you it's working fine in Windows with AS. Okay, because now I'll be jumping to Mac.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes. If somebody just let me know with a no, then I will understand that, okay.
PAUL: That is, like, how many…
PAUL: Of you, for how many of you, it is not working? Rajesh, Kumar, no, alright. I will come to you, Rajesh, don't worry. Sade, alright. Like,
PAUL: Because the Navigator needs to be upgraded to 2.7, not… it is not compulsory, Sanjay, okay? It is not compulsory to do the upgrade.
PAUL: Mohammad, does my chat visible? Everybody's chat is visible too, okay? Don't worry about that. If anybody's having the problem, I will come, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so 2.7 is fine directly if you're using.
PAUL: What does mean Notion? Can you tell me Notion? Notion is just,
PAUL: I can say your document hub for this course, where I'll be mentioning all the URLs and links.
PAUL: Okay, please continue with the other ways. Alright, so for Windows, it's done. Now I will take whoever is having the issues, don't worry, I will come to you, and I will ask you to share yours, okay? So, once this part is done.
PAUL: How to go to Anaconda prompt? Just click on the Windows button and type Anaconda's ACE prompt.
PAUL: Cynthia Banachi. Okay?
PAUL: I hope this part is clear. Just press the Windows button, and I'm going to pop down.
PAUL: Gaganpreet, I just want to have the acknowledgement of the… yes, I have been trying to connect to the chair, but my…
PAUL: I was never concerned. Gagan, Preet, I will come to you. Okay, right now, you please do the installation, don't worry, I'm looking into the chat. Okay.
PAUL: Is Anaconda preferred over UV? It totally depends, Sam. Like, in my system, I don't have Anaconda, okay? I've been using Anaconda for the past…
PAUL: more than 6 years. Okay, now I'm just using UV.
PAUL: The reason is I have less storage in my Mac.
PAUL: That's fine.
PAUL: If I will have in my main PC, I have used… I'm using an app.
PAUL: But right now, on this laptop, I have lesser one, that's why you need very specific.
PAUL: I got the command prompt, what should I type now? Just press type conda and hit enter.
PAUL: Okay? The command was only conduct.
PAUL: Okay? Just crawl, Ricky, just crawl above, okay, and show others what… okay, you have to just write conda, and hit enter, C-O-N-D-A, and hit enter.
PAUL: Karthik here is saying, but UV is only virtual environment, or it also acts as a distribution of Python? Yes, using UV, you can access any distribution of Python, Kartik here.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right, so No, Sayed Noor is asking, well, sir, I have VS Code with Jupyter extension, is that fine for this course? Yes, that is fine. The idea is you should have Python. If you don't have Python, then your Jupyter notebook, cannot access the Python compile.
PAUL: Vijay, don't worry, so right now, we are just talking about the installation of Windows, now I will jump to Mac, okay? I think for everybody, okay,
PAUL: And for Windows, at least it's done. Few people are having the issues. I will come to them later on.
PAUL: Jill, how to do the upgrade to Python? Simply, like, you can use a command, or you can directly install 3.13 and remove the older version. Both the ways are fine.
PAUL: All right. So, Ricky, I think you can stop sharing, now we'll jump to Mac.
PAUL: All right, you stay in the paralleliston notification.
PAUL: Alright, now let me start sharing my screen.
PAUL: Okay, so share… I think this is my desktop. 3, okay? In my case, you can see simply, the Anaconda as it is available here directly.
PAUL: Okay, so what I will do…
PAUL: I will just go into my Downloads folder.
PAUL: Okay? So, I think everybody can see my downloads folder. This, I cannot make it bigger. I hope that for Mac users, you have this .ekj format, okay? And right now, I am on Mac M1 Pro, so you can be on any
PAUL: Apple check, okay? So, it's pretty much standard, you just need to do this, okay? So, you will be getting this screen once you click on this.
PAUL: Okay, so this package will allow a program, you have to just click on allow.
PAUL: Okay? And then, once you have done the allow in Mac, it's pretty much simple, it's continue that you have to do.
PAUL: Now, these are some, things. What are the packages that…
PAUL: comes pre-installed with Anaconda, list of packages are being shown here. As you can see here, scikit-lun for machine learning, Seabon for visualization, setup tools.
PAUL: 6, okay? So, so many packages that come pre-installed, okay? So, what you can do, simply, you can click on continue. I hope my screen is visible, and everybody can follow, because, see, guys, this font, I cannot increase. Okay, you have to understand.
PAUL: This is the default one, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, my site, Anaconda installation is done great, it's already there in the laptop, okay, alright, great, then, no issues. So right now, I'm doing it for the Mac. Please, everyone, whoever is using Mac, please follow the steps, okay? I will just, again, start from…
PAUL: back, okay, so you will see something like Introduction. From introduction, you can simply click on continue. In Mac, it's very, very easy, so no such options like selecting those, okay? So, as you can see, continue.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see, to continue, okay, so just click on Agree.
PAUL: Okay, and here comes… okay, you can install for all users in this computer, or install on a specific disk. Use the first option, okay, because I think everybody will have a single disk only. Okay, you can use the first option.
PAUL: Alright, so for Mac, you can do it for all users, and then you can just click on continue.
PAUL: is, it's pretty much standard, guys. Next, next, next.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, Hari Ada's chat, you won't be able to see.
PAUL: Okay, people can't install when they can use Google Collab. People who can't install. Tama Krishna will come to you. Who cannot install anything in their local, then will be moving to a browser-based ID.
PAUL: Okay, I will be coming to that, don't worry about that.
PAUL: Okay, so do we need to click on sign in? Sign-in is not required again, Yogesh. Okay. How can I add the Notion link? Notion link, I've already shared. Again, I'm sharing. Keep it bookmarked.
PAUL: For accessing the future resources.
PAUL: Okay, Sachin, you can do an upgrade, I have no issues with that.
PAUL: Can you place the package link here? See the package link?
PAUL: Okay, so yes, I can share the link, but exactly… I'm sharing the web page link, okay? So, from this particular web page link, you can access it.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on your operating system.
PAUL: Okay, and always use a graphical installer. The graphical installer is much easier.
PAUL: Yes, Arj Naveen, you need to download the distribution. If you don't have a system, that is the first thing that I have to
PAUL: Alright, Salman, if you're in your local, if you have done it using Homebrew, great. I have no issue if you are working with Python 3.13.7.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Yes, Minu, your chat is visible. Guys, don't think that your chat is not visible. Ten now, like, 20 people have told.
PAUL: Okay, yes, your chats are visible, but the flow of the chats is pretty much high. So, like, the major things when I look into, I'm looking into that.
PAUL: Harsh Navin Mini Content Installer is basically, if you have less amount of RAM in your system, less amount of storage, only for the iPad
PAUL: Because in Anaconda, a lot of other stuff, that comes into the picture. Like, spider ID comes, okay, a lot of other things. But in Minicanta, it's only the pure quanta.
PAUL: Nothing.
PAUL: Rajkuma just joined, is it distribution installation? Yes, right now we are just doing the distribution installation.
PAUL: The idea is that at least you have 8GB of RAM in your system, and more than 30GB available.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's get back here, okay? Now, as you can see here, once I click on continue, for my Mac, the installation will start. Okay? Because I don't want to install in my system.
PAUL: So, you can see for Mac also, it will be taking close to 5GB. Okay, so once I click on the install, the installation will start. So, everyone in Mac, you can click on this install option, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay, please click on this install option.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see right now, as it's asking me for the password, but I only be doing the installation.
PAUL: Okay, but you guys, please do the installation.
PAUL: Yes, installation will take time. Average, like, I feel like 3 to 4 minutes, not more than that.
PAUL: Okay, so finally, like, this is not required, you can click on continue.
PAUL: Okay, the installation of it, fine. I don't want to install it in my local.
PAUL: Because I'm pretty much advanced user, so… Alright.
PAUL: So, map, pretty much easy. Just click, click, click. There are no options to select.
PAUL: Okay, so that's fine.
PAUL: Installation is done, so I think for everybody, for Mac, it will be done.
PAUL: Okay, after Mac, I'll be coming to Linux, guys, now. I know there are a few folks who are using Linux, so for them.
PAUL: Yes, Sita comes, so when I can see your chat.
PAUL: Prasada's asking, I have VS code including IP1 installed as Chris Python code, and I've been using that. Yes, that's fine, Prasad. The main idea is you should have Python in your system.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, like, if I open my terminal, okay? So, this is the main idea for Mac users or for Windows users, okay? So…
PAUL: If I just write here Python, and probably with a version here.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see, right now, Python is not found in my system. Probably I will check with Python 3.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see in my system, right now I do have a 3.11.6.
PAUL: Okay? So… so I think in your case, if you have done the installation, directly you can write here something like Python 3. Okay, I don't think you need to write even Python 3, only Python also works, majorly in most of the systems.
PAUL: Okay? And you will see that, yes, my compiler is now available.
PAUL: Okay, and here you can execute any command, something like that, okay, like, print whatever the stuff that you want to do. Okay, these things are not necessary, I'm just showing.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see now Hello is getting better.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the main idea, that Python should be available in your system.
PAUL: However, through Anaconda, through the pure Python package, anywhere.
PAUL: Okay, I hope this part is clear for Matt.
PAUL: the installation is available. Similarly.
PAUL: in your Mac, once you open your terminal, okay, so once the installation is done, simply, okay, so you can just, write Conda, okay, and you can hit it. So in my system, I don't have Conda, but I hope that after the installation in your system, you'll be having Conda.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see right now, for me, content not found.
PAUL: But in your case, it will be showing all those options as it was showing in.
PAUL: Very specifically, Windows.
PAUL: Okay, so Mac users, anybody want to share their screen? Okay, I will allow one Mac user who has done the installation right now.
PAUL: Okay, if anybody is interested.
PAUL: Are you using Atlas? No, I am not using ATLOS.
PAUL: I've done Manoj, or Muttasa, anyone, like, if you want to share your screen, you can raise your hand.
PAUL: Okay? For Mac users.
PAUL: Okay, then I will come to Linux. So, Linux users, be ready that everything is downloaded.
PAUL: Okay, so whoever I think from the chat, I can add one.
PAUL: Muddhasar Hakim, alright, I will add you to the panelist.
PAUL: I will stop sharing my screen, and Muntasari can start sharing.
Mudassar Hakim: Yup.
Mudassar Hakim: Again, no.
PAUL: Yes, you can start sharing.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
Mudassar Hakim: So I have Brykel installed.
PAUL: Gonda?
PAUL: Just increase the form. Okay, press Command+++ a little bit.
PAUL: Okay, so guys, see, like, once you have done the installation, okay, you will see this base option. Okay, first, this base will come just like Windows base, okay?
PAUL: and then within that, you will have your main pipeline. So, like, once you just write content, hit enter, you'll be getting all these options, just like Windows. Pretty much standard thing.
PAUL: Okay, Sanjay, in your Mac, if it is getting filled, just check that
PAUL: you are on which? Whether you are using Intel, and you have downloaded, Apple Silicon chip version. Okay, just be sure. If you are on silicon chips, please use the silicon version only.
PAUL: Okay? So, just have a check. Then, it will fail.
PAUL: Okay, Kushagra, Hepal, I have, everything installed, what will be discussing anything? Today, it's all about installation. Okay, from tomorrow, will we start the main content, introduction to that.
PAUL: Okay, so if you have everything in your system, there are other things in the checklist, okay? So please have a look.
PAUL: If you are fine, simply, like, you can skip.
PAUL: Alright, so for Mac, it's pretty much standard, guys. I hope that for everybody it is… accessible.
PAUL: Why did the class hours change? Fikri Musa?
PAUL: Nothing has changed. We started from 9AM IST.
PAUL: So, Agathika, 3 hours only installation? Yes, there are many students I know who will be facing the issue. And to resolve their queries, it will take time.
PAUL: Okay, alright, so this is the first, okay? Alright, now for Mac, I hope that, yes, Amit Khan, I will assist you, don't worry. Everybody who's having the problem, I will assist you, but at the end of this class, okay? Okay, so Mac is done. I will come to Linux. Moda, sir, you can stop sharing your screen.
PAUL: Yes, it's done format. Okay, now I'll be coming to Linux. Linux, guys, please let me know, because for you, you have to share your screen. Whoever is on Linux, please let me know in the chat that, yes.
PAUL: I have a good internet, okay, and that I can share my screen. Mac, sorry, Linux users, anybody on Uber to…
PAUL: Azorin OS, any flavor of Ubuntu you are.
PAUL: Please let me know in the chat, Linux users.
PAUL: Yes, Arshad.
PAUL: Don't worry about that, you'll be getting the links.
PAUL: I'm sharing the link, just, keep that bookmarked, okay?
PAUL: may already have Python. Okay, Vivesh, if you have Zorin, great. Okay, and you are already using Python, great. Then I think nothing is required. Linux users, anybody who want to share the screen?
PAUL: Okay, then I will skip Linux, because really, it's like, looks like nobody wants to share their screen, so I hope that it is installed.
PAUL: pinning option is not there, Abigail question, okay?
PAUL: In Zoom chat, I cannot do a PIN, so I hope you understand.
PAUL: Alright, so no Linux users, so I will skip the Linux part, because nobody is, letting me know in the chat. So, simply now, I will come to the IDE part.
PAUL: Okay, so now I will start sharing my screen.
PAUL: Alright, Abhishek, if it's already installed, it's great. Dinesh, I am using Linux. I hope you can do the niche if it is installed, otherwise you can simply use your…
PAUL: Alright, so the first checklist that we have, it is done. Okay, the Python distribution part.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Majorly, okay, now, I will come to… I doubt.
PAUL: Package managers, okay?
PAUL: So, like, whatever you want to install. So, for example, if you want to install any package, the standard format that you have, okay? So, let me just tell you about the package managers.
PAUL: So, what are package managers? Who will be providing the Python packages? So, for example, in this course, we'll be working with different type of frameworks, like Langchain, Langraph. Okay, now, Langchain is a package. Langgraph is a package. Okay, so whenever I'm talking about these, these are packages. So, you can get the packages, for example.
PAUL: Okay, so Lunch and GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, you will be seeing that it will be having, most of the times, it will be having a GitHub repo. If it is an open source project, okay, and you'll be getting some type of, command to do the installation. So right now, as you can see here, fip install line.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, so…
PAUL: Everybody, please focus on the package managers. This we'll be using every day in the class, okay? So, package managers…
PAUL: Okay, so the first one is pip, okay? Now, pip directly works with Python. It means that
PAUL: You don't need to install anything. Like, if you have Anaconda, then also you will be able to use PIP.
PAUL: The other package manager is Fonder.
PAUL: The commands are sample commands I will be just writing, like, fifth, install.
PAUL: Pandas. Okay, Pandas is a package.
PAUL: For working with different types of data manipulation work. Okay, and how the command looks like. The idea is to just to show you, you don't need to execute anything. Just look here, and nothing, okay?
PAUL: Okay, and finally comes, like, if you are working with Conda, no, Conda is only available for Anaconda users or Minicanta.
PAUL: Okay? If you have installed Anaconda or Miniconda, okay, then only you will be able to see this.
PAUL: Otherwise, like, most of the times, you can work with PIP. PIP does the job most of the times. In this course, I'll be using PIP.
PAUL: Okay? Because I feel that, like, the Conda package manager, it has, like, lesser access to recent packages, whereas pip is the mean Python
PAUL: Package manager. Okay, pip is the default Python package manager. Always remember, this is the default one if you are working with Python.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So these two are the major package managers that will be working in this course, and majorly will be working with this. Always.
PAUL: Okay, for data science courses, like pure data science, if I'm teaching machine learning, then probably
PAUL: I might work with Conda, okay, but for now, I don't feel Conda is required. In your course, majorly, you guys will be working with PI.
PAUL: Okay? And finally.
PAUL: Okay, there is a third one, which is UV. I will come to UV in the second half, like, once we have the break, like, after 10.40. Okay, now, UV is also providing, but you have to understand, UV always uses PIM.
PAUL: Okay, like, UV?
PAUL: Okay, you have to just add one thing, like this one.
PAUL: Okay, so by default, UV uses APR quanta style.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: And UV is based on a different programming language. So, that's why I'll be talking about these things later. It is based on Rust. Rather, it is not built on Python. So, I feel that UV is a little bit for advanced users, or intermediate, at least not for beginner to start.
PAUL: Okay, so the beginners, always, I prefer these two. Like, once you are comfortable, like, after one month, start working with you.
PAUL: Okay? So that's why the programming language is different, so if you get any error, it becomes hard for you to trace back. Okay? But this is also one option. But UV uses PIP, you have to understand this.
PAUL: Okay, so I'll be coming to this in the second half, so don't worry about that. Right now, I want to tell you about the package managers, because every day we'll be working with package managers. It means that every day for any type of project that I will be using, okay, I'll be sharing you a list of packages.
PAUL: Okay? A list of it means that there will be 20 packages, 30 packages, and you have to do the installation of those packages. Okay? So…
PAUL: We'll be talking about that later, but majorly in this course, we'll be using FIP, okay? And, like, UV also, if somebody is already using UV, or, like, if you love UV. I love UV because it is very, very fast as compared to FIP.
PAUL: That is the only downfall. So, in the second app, I'll be talking about these.
PAUL: Alright, so the package manager part is done. Now, the next part is working with IDEs. IDEs are the most important thing.
PAUL: Like, see, I have given so many options.
PAUL: Karthik is asking, what is the difference between packages and modules?
PAUL: Packages are… which are published and available online. Okay, it means that anybody can do the installation. Modules are pretty much local. You need to convert your modules into packages, Karthi.
PAUL: I hope I have made my point clear.
PAUL: Okay? Sanjay's reversed the path issues on… upon map, okay, I will look into that for Ironman, very specific.
PAUL: If we add pandas, yes, that is the advanced one balance. Okay, so…
PAUL: I'll be coming to that for the second half, so don't worry. Do you want to install Pandas? No, no, nothing you have to install. I was just showing you some boilerplates, okay? You don't have to install anything.
PAUL: Okay? Now, these things that I have told, it is applicable for any operating system, okay?
PAUL: any operating system, whether you are on Windows, whether you are on Mac, whether you are on Linux, it doesn't matter. These things are standard.
PAUL: Okay, like, these are common standards for Python templates.
PAUL: All right, now coming to the IDEs part. Now, see, nasally you can work with VS Code. Okay, so really, like.
PAUL: VS Code, by default, if you don't have in your system, you can simply do the installation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, I think that most of you will be having VS Code. VS Code is totally free.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, in this course.
PAUL: Like, you have to understand that in this course, I might be using different IDs, but at the end of the day, most of the IDs are based on VSP.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, I use, the Insiders Build also, as you can see here.
PAUL: Okay, as you can see, the inside is built. This version is a little bit the development version, but…
PAUL: For early adopters, if you are a developer who knows things much more, for them, I prefer. Otherwise, use the default PS Code. Majorly, in this course, we'll be working with PS code. So, if you look here, in this checklist, I've given so many IDs. Like, you can work with cursor also.
PAUL: Okay? You can work with Vince Up also, Trey also, okay? So, this is the first link, you can directly click on this link, and you can download for your ways. So, the downloadable links are provided directly, okay? In the Notion.
PAUL: you can directly click on that, and you can start downloading, if you don't have. Because I feel that most of you will have VS Code in your system. How many of you don't have VS Code? Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: So Agartika, can you use Jupyter Notebooks? Yes, you can install. Jupyter Notebook is just a package.
PAUL: an extension.
PAUL: I don't, I don't have VS Code, I don't have BS Code. Alright, then download the VS Code. Okay, so the link I have already provided in the Notion, you can open this, you can click here. Okay, okay, now this is for cursor, sorry. I have done it for VS Code, yes.
PAUL: Now you can download based on your operating system. Okay, so it's showing me for a macOS,
PAUL: Similarly, like, you will be having it for Windows and Linux.
PAUL: everyone, like, Visual Studio Code is the most common.
PAUL: Yes, Anjay, like, I have a lot of… so if you look into my… okay, if I show you…
PAUL: my applications, okay, so I do use a lot of IDEs, Soon…
PAUL: And M3, most of them looks fine. I use Kiro also. Kiro is also good, I feel, which comes from Amazon.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see Visual Studio, these two things that I work with a lot.
PAUL: then, probably, like, I think I have Winsub also in my system.
PAUL: Okay, so majorly, most of the things are there, so you can use any one. The idea is to explore things.
PAUL: So… I think I have cursor. Yes. So, you can work with cursors also. Okay, so this is also a great idea.
PAUL: Okay, you don't need a paid plan.
PAUL: Okay, so at any point of time, a paid plan is not required, you can always work with the free plan in this particular course, okay? So this is how it looks like. Basically the cursor.
PAUL: then…
PAUL: And you don't need to install all the IDs. I'm giving you the option, like, you can use VS Code majorly in this course. I'll be using, VS Code, but yes, Cursor, the free version you guys can use, Vince Up, the free version you can use. There is track…
PAUL: Okay, there is PyCharm, okay, even you have Kiro, I don't know how many of you know about KiroID,
PAUL: Okay, so the list of IDs are pretty long. Like, whichever suits you. If you are working with PyCharm, community version, that is also fine.
PAUL: Okay, the main part is…
PAUL: based on whichever ID selection that you do, you have to click. And these installations are pretty much standard forward. It means that double-click done. Double-click done. Okay, so I think the installation of these IDs can be done by yourself.
PAUL: Or, if somebody really wants to know the step-by-step process of installing VS Code, okay, you can raise your hand, I can ask you to share your screen, if you don't have VS Code.
PAUL: Okay, so these are basically the forks. So, if I show you tray, okay, I'll be showing you all the major ones. I like TRA also.
PAUL: Okay, so… This is how the UI of trial looks like.
PAUL: Okay, so… this is also good, I feel.
PAUL: Then comes your wind surf, Okay, you can work with VINsUp also.
PAUL: So, I work with Windstop a lot, okay? So, this is how Windstop looks like. So, most of them will be just like your
PAUL: I can say VS Code. So if you have VS Code, nothing you need to worry about.
PAUL: So, I'll be just closing all those IDs. I hope you get the idea. You can use any one for this course, whichever you love.
PAUL: This option I'm giving to you. Okay, you select.
PAUL: Black box, I don't use black box.
PAUL: Okay, VS Code is the best for Python. VS Code is best for any programming languages, whether you are a web developer, data scientist, okay, so for any…
PAUL: I use Wins Upgrade. Is that good for cursor, for junior level? Yes.
PAUL: I know in organizations, like, people are using paid stuff, so, great.
PAUL: What is the difference between two different blue…
PAUL: the VS Code Blue and Green. The blue one that you have, it's a stable one, and the green one is always in development. That is a… so, new features are always released on the green one. When it becomes stable, then it will be pushed to the blue one. That is the only difference.
PAUL: Okay, for VS Code.
PAUL: So that is called the Insider's Edition.
PAUL: And you can see here, web… This wave is also available.
PAUL: Okay, so VScode.dev.
PAUL: So if you have some issues in your local machine, I suggest that, yes, you can work with this DevOps.
PAUL: Okay, so this is an online one.
PAUL: Okay, but here you have to do a lot of other installations also, like, if you want to work with Python. So this is browser-based, guys, completely. VScode.dev.
PAUL: Okay, and here, I think the extensions part…
PAUL: So, very specifically, you can install the Python extension there.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that this extension should be available to everyone. If you have installed VSports, just be sure, okay, you have this Python.
PAUL: Okay? So, this Python extension. You have to click on this extension, and you can install this.
PAUL: Because in this course, majorly, we'll be working with Python, that's it.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: See, anybody who cannot do the installation, let me know.
PAUL: please let me know, because the idea is, it's totally up to you, whichever idea that you want to use. Okay, you can go ahead with PipeCharm, VS Code, Kazasar, totally up to you. You just need one.
PAUL: Okay, so whichever you prefer, you can use.
PAUL: I'm a singer as I want to learn how to use VS Code.
PAUL: Okay, majorly, like, you will be… in the class, we'll be talking… like, there is, not really you need a course to learn VS2, okay? When I'll be doing it in the class parallelly, okay, it's pretty much easy. Create file, create folder, okay, those things we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Okay, Vikram, if you want to share your screen, okay, so you can do that.
PAUL: Which always is good to proceed with this course? You can work with Mac, Linux, or Windows. Everything is good.
PAUL: For deep learning, I prefer much more Linux, but right now, you guys are on RAG, so really, I feel that
PAUL: Mac or Windows, anything works good.
PAUL: Okay, Abhishek Zhop, I will come to you if there is an issue with Anaconda. So, guys, let me know if anybody, like, want to share your screen for Anaconda installation. Because I feel Anaconda installation can be done by anyone. So, Vikram, okay, alright, I will add you to panelist.
PAUL: Vikram is having some issues, okay, with respect. I think some options are coming, and he's asking.
PAUL: So, Vikram, I think you can start sharing your screen.
PAUL: Okay, only 4 people have the rest of me.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Do we need to use UV in VS Code? If your terminal is configured in that way, you can use it. I will come to UV, don't worry, in the second half.
PAUL: Rajesh Kum.
PAUL: Can I leave? I have installed, anything new we are going to do? CR Patel, please check the checklist.
PAUL: Okay, all right, now just go back, go back, go back once. So let's start from the starting part, okay? Just go.
PAUL: Okay, go back once more. Okay, go back, go back, go back.
PAUL: Okay, okay, now this is how it will look like. Once you have downloaded the package, simply, okay, this option will come. So you just click on that agreement, I accept the agreement, now click on next.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the default path where your VS Code is getting installed. So, you can see, like, app data, local, and programs. For Windows users, majorly it will be. Now click on next.
PAUL: Okay, so don't create not required, actually. If you feel that you need something in the start menu, you can select, but I feel it is not required. Now, click on next.
PAUL: Okay? Now, create a desktop icon if you feel that it's required, otherwise you can always open it through the Windows button. Now, add that open with code.
PAUL: Okay, this option is important. Okay, and even, open with code action to Windows Explorer directive. Go select, okay. Right now, you have selected everything, register code as an editor for supported file types, great, and add to pass. So, all the options right now, just select it and click on next.
PAUL: Okay? Well, right now, click on Install.
PAUL: Because sometimes a shell restart is required if you are doing the adding path, so now your installation will be done.
PAUL: Ajay is saying, I already have VSput, but didn't install Python like he's…
PAUL: then please do the installation of Python. Ajai Singh, first we need a compiler, the Python compiler, or basically the Python distribution. Then, ID comes into the
PAUL: Where is the checklist? CR patel, I think I have shared it so many times in today's class.
PAUL: Okay, okay, Jay is asking, hey Paul, QQ, I am UI developer, I'm very much interested.
PAUL: of my Gen AI terrain is teaching you to show if you can use RAG and Lansing. Yes, Jay, that's part of your syllabus.
PAUL: Shawaz is asking, can you please take up all the doubts and the problems later? Yes, I will be just looking into the chat.
PAUL: the actual doubt-solving, I will be taking it probably after the second one, so don't worry, okay? Now, this is your VSCO, and now going forward, like, most of the things will be there.
PAUL: Alright, so, Vikram, this is done. I think the installation of VS Code is very, very easy in Mac also. For Mac, if anybody wants to ask, please let me know.
Vikram: What about those packages, sir? PIP and… you said, right, UV?
PAUL: Have you installed Anaconda?
Vikram: Yeah, I do.
PAUL: Okay, then fine, like, using those, you'll be doing. So, for example, just open your Anaconda account.
PAUL: Just open your Anaconda account quickly.
PAUL: Just be sure you are sharing that screen.
PAUL: Will you be using Docker? Yes, I will come to Docker installation also. In the checklist, everything is there that we'll be using in this course.
Vikram: Oh…
PAUL: This is your Anaconda Navigator.
PAUL: Open the Anaconda prompt.
PAUL: Yeah, close this, close this. Rarely, we work with He acquitted.
PAUL: Let me quickly open an account navigator. Press the Windows button, and quickly type an account.
PAUL: How much does Cursor or Windstock charge, sir? Close to, like, $20 per month.
PAUL: Okay, so here, for example, if you want to install any package, okay, you can write here, like, paper install pandas or something like that. This is the main part. If you want to try it out, later on, I'll be showing you that, okay? So this is the part where you'll be writing all the commands, like, whatever the thing that you want to install within a particular project environment.
Vikram: Cheers.
PAUL: Alright, Vikram, now I will… you can stop sharing your screen.
PAUL: Okay, now let me start sharing my screen. So, I think this is our desktop tree.
PAUL: Alright, so now local IDs are done. Okay, is there anybody who cannot do anything in your local? It means that in your office laptop, everything is blocked. Okay, now I will come to the, like, optional now, these are browser-based IDs.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, Lightning.ai, this I prefer most of the times.
PAUL: Then you have Replit, again, which has a limited free version, but again, paid. Okay, then you have Firebase Studio from Google, this also, you can use it.
PAUL: Okay, so Lightning.ai, if… is there anybody in this course, like, who is using an office laptop and everything is blocked? It means that you cannot work with Python in local, you cannot work with under local. Is there anybody?
PAUL: Niti, Jan is telling yes.
PAUL: I'm using Office Laptop.
PAUL: See, using office laptop is not that. For example, you are using your office laptop, you cannot install Anaconda because it is blocked. You cannot install Python because it is blocked. Is there anybody? Like, for… I can't use Anaconda, rest all okay. Like, you can use Python I.O,
PAUL: Karsa is blocked on my office laptop.
PAUL: Like, say, can you access VS code in your local machine? Please let me know that.
PAUL: whether it's an Office laptop, can you install VS Code in your local VS Code with Python?
PAUL: Nithen, I cannot use Anaconda, Python is already installed, I have VSport, great. Okay? Like, if you don't have, because this is the last option that I feel for students.
PAUL: will be taking this course, which is, Lightning EN.
PAUL: Okay, so… Lightning AI.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the last one, because here you get free GPUs and other stuff, I don't work with collab, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, get started, okay, let me choose a top 10.
PAUL: You can see here ATR GPU monthly that you'll be getting. So, like, this is a good one. At any point of time, if you feel that you can start working… Okay, I don't think I have here in some other… I think I need to change my…
PAUL: You need an office email ID, otherwise it takes time.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be just showing you quickly Lightning.ai. If we are working with,
PAUL: some project where we'll be working with GPUs. Then only I'll be using Lightning.
PAUL: Okay, I think…
PAUL: I'll just wait, looks like a power cut from my side, okay? Just wait, and then 30 seconds to back up.
PAUL: In the meantime, in chat, you can let me know. I'm looking into the chat.
PAUL: So, Shavaz is asking, I already have an AWS CLI for office use, will we be able to use another AWS instance? Yes, in that AWS CLI, you just need to log out of your Office account. And for this particular course, whatever the things that we are doing, you can use that.
PAUL: Yeah, so, not a big deal.
PAUL: Alright, so… let me just show you once, like, exactly how Lightning ends. This is only for those… it means that you cannot do anything in your looker, and everything that you can do in your
PAUL: browser, okay? For Chromebooks. Anybody using Chromebooks in this class?
PAUL: I don't… I have zero.
PAUL: Credit, right now.
PAUL: Okay. But, alright, fine, I think,
PAUL: This account, I don't remember what happened to this account.
PAUL: But, if you create a new account.
PAUL: I can check it with some other ID…
PAUL: I think, like, whoever is having an office email, they can easily sign.
PAUL: That is the easiest way, because I don't know, like, for me, the credits are zero.
PAUL: Okay, as you can see here.
PAUL: I have zero credits. I've already used this month's quota, okay, but you guys can use it. Okay, that is the idea.
PAUL: Alright, so… browser-based IDs, also, I've told you about.
PAUL: Now, coming to the, main part, okay, because this part is done. Now, working with virtual environments will start after a break, okay, because this part will take time.
PAUL: Okay, because this is very, very important, working with virtual environments.
PAUL: Okay, so, like… This part we have done.
PAUL: The most important part, working with
PAUL: virtual environment. In the meantime, let me tell you why it is important to work with virtual environments.
PAUL: So, just think about, in this particular course, we'll be working with, like, let's take a random number, okay, like, 5 to 10 projects.
PAUL: Okay? Now, in one project, okay, so in one project, I am using 3.12.
PAUL: Okay, in the second project, I am using 3.13.
PAUL: In the third project I am using, Okay? Like, 3.14.
PAUL: Okay? Now, again, in the fourth project I'm using.
PAUL: like, 3.0. Okay, so something like this can happen. It means that for every project, there is a fixed
PAUL: Python version.
PAUL: Okay, and I have… I'm working with 5 different projects, and all of those 5 projects are having different Python versions.
PAUL: Okay? So the idea is to isolate this environment. The idea is that within an environment, you will be having a single Python version. Okay? So when I say that.
PAUL: Within is single.
PAUL: Virtual.
PAUL: environment. Okay. You will be having a… Single.
PAUL: Python version.
PAUL: Okay? So I can say that for every project, there will be a unique virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay? So… For every project, Okay?
PAUL: unique.
PAUL: Virtual environment that will be created.
PAUL: This is very, very important, because this will be your day-to-day task, every day, like, whenever we'll be working with each other. Okay? Environment. Like, 3.12 or 3.13.
PAUL: I'll be telling you, like, after the break, like, how to create a virtual environment, but for now, you have to understand this one.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that you can have as many as virtual environments, there is no restriction.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, just think, in this course, we'll be having close to, like, 40 classes, if I'm taking a random number. Okay, so probably, you can think around, like, I'll be creating around at least 5 to 10 different.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, in every class, it is not required to create a virtual environment, you can reuse the same, okay? Reusing virtual environments, I'll be talking about with the practical demos, but for now, you have to understand that at least I'll be using, like, 5 to 10 different virtual environments.
PAUL: In this particular course, at least. Okay, it can be more also, I'm taking a random number. The idea is, if I'm working with a specific environment.
PAUL: 3.12. I will create a virtual environment for that, and start working. Similarly, if I work with 3.13, I will create a virtual environment, and I will install 3.13 within that environment.
PAUL: So the idea is always keep your versions different, or keep virtual environments as per your projects. If you're working in 5 different projects, the idea is that you should have 5 different virtual environments. Is this part clear? What is virtual environment?
PAUL: The idea is that within a virtual environment, you'll be using a specific Python version. And for that Python version, what are the specific packages? So, for example, if I do a pip install Pandas, okay, so Pandas has a very specific version for 3.12, as well as for 3.13.
PAUL: So, if you are using a Python environment of 3.12, okay, then it will,
PAUL: install the Pandas for 3. Similarly, that specific version matters to us. So that's the purpose of using virtual environment, and it's very, very important, guys. Like, every Python developer is working in virtual environments.
PAUL: Okay? So, I hope you got the fundamental understanding of why virtual environments are important.
PAUL: Please let me know. Or some question, let me know in the chat, directly.
PAUL: Because these concepts are very, very important. After the installation, because I'll be showing you the practical part also.
PAUL: MJ's asking, is that the same as Workspace? No. Workspace is different. MJ, totally different. Sri is asking, what do we use notebook, then also we can use… yes. See? So, what happens? So, Sri, in that case, like, in your virtual environment, you'll be installing a package. Install Jupyter.
PAUL: Okay, now Jupyter, within the Jupyter, you have the Jupyter notebooks. So, yes, you can have, that Jupyter package within, like, different virtual environments.
PAUL: Okay, now Mohamed is asking, if when we set up two virtual environments, like 3.3, do we need also to set up both of them? Like, install them? Yes, Mohanak, Alugadi, okay, I'll be talking about that in the practical demo.
PAUL: Okay, how to activate the virtual environment, how to deactivate the virtual environment. Okay, so don't worry about that.
PAUL: Muntasar is asking sure, but how that ties up to VS Editor. I'll be telling you that, don't worry. When I show you the practical demo, everything I'll be showing you.
PAUL: Is this required during deployment? Yes. This is very, very important during your deployment.
PAUL: Because during your deployment, you'll be telling that, okay, so for this particular Python project, I have these packages.
PAUL: So, these packages needs to be involved, okay? So what happens? Just think about back in 2020, I was working in a project.
PAUL: During that time, I used probably Python 3.9.
PAUL: After 3 years, I have to upgrade the entire codebase.
PAUL: Okay, so in that case, I have to upgrade Python also.
PAUL: So, very, very important to maintain your Python versions during your deployment.
PAUL: Dinesh, can you please explain one second about the virtual environment? So, Dinesh, just remember, for each project or any type of task that we are doing on Python, for a specific version of Python, we'll be always creating a specific
PAUL: virtual environment. The idea is to isolate our work. Okay, so probably one project might be dependent on a specific
PAUL: version of Python and some other project might be, dependent on some specific version. So, we will always use virtual environment, where we'll be keeping an isolated Python version.
PAUL: Just remember, never think that inside a virtual environment, there will be two Python versions.
PAUL: Okay, that is not possible, guys.
PAUL: Okay? Inside a virtual environment, two Python versions is not possible.
PAUL: Okay, it has to be only one.
PAUL: Okay, now, Vivesh, is asking why we are not working with the latest version of Python always, because it is in the security phase. It means that there are a lot of bugs which are still not been solved. Like, every year in the month of October, a new Python version is released.
PAUL: Okay? But we directly don't start working. We always pick up something which is stable. The idea is people, whoever are working in production, you know that we don't pick up the latest stuff that is coming. We always look for something stable. If something breaks in production, then again, it becomes very hard to change the entire codebase.
PAUL: Okay? I hope you get my point.
PAUL: Now, are virtual environments, slash project? No. No, don't think about virtual environments as project. Rather than think about virtual environments or isolated Python environments.
PAUL: That we'll be using for a specific project. The idea is that for each project, we create a virtual environment, but virtual environment is not equal to a project.
PAUL: Why should we use virtual environments? Kika already told the idea is to isolate the Python environment based on different projects.
PAUL: We cannot work with a single Python version for everything.
PAUL: So, Abrahatika, I hope I have made my point.
PAUL: Rahul, to switch between the Python versions, I'll be talking about that in the practical demo after the break, don't worry. Mandeep Sohi, why we have to use different Python versions, not we keep the latest one every time? Nobody uses the latest one.
PAUL: Okay, if I'm an active developer, then also. Just think about, I'm working on a project. I know that, like, if something is released now, it will take at least one year to become scalable.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why we don't use the latest version. There will be a lot of bugs that needs to be fixed by the community.
PAUL: Okay, because there are so many developers who are working to fix those problems. From GitHub issues, we will look into that, and we will fix it. So, we never use the latest version. I hope you get my point.
PAUL: Yes, Pai Endi, you can use Rahul Parihar, no issues I have.
PAUL: Naesh is asking, I am no voice in Python, hope I am learning Python along the journey of this course. Yes, that is very much required. If you have zero Python, please start learning the Python. The courses of Udemy already were shared last time by, Kresh.
PAUL: Salman, is it possible to use same virtual environment across different project folders? Yes, Salman, you can do that. There is no restriction. Just be sure that then, your codebase is always compatible with those things. Okay?
PAUL: The number side is asking each virtual environment one Python version.
PAUL: one each ENV.
PAUL: Python versions has to be installed, yes. Like, within one virtual environment, you will be installing a specific Python version.
PAUL: Minu is asking, can we upgrade virtually, and we need Python version? Yes, you can do that. Upgrading, that is possible. Preeti Agarwal is asking, does it mean that we should have versions installed in the system?
PAUL: No, really, you don't need to install all the Python versions. It is not required. If you have one version, you can easily skip and switch to others also.
PAUL: Gagantree, do we need to install Python extension in local VS Code? Yes, Gagantrith, it is…
PAUL: Like, recommended, so if I show you my list, what are the things?
PAUL: That I have installed, okay, so am I…
PAUL: So, just wait. Okay, I will show you what are the extensions that I have.
PAUL: your Visual Studio Code.
PAUL: Beautiful.
PAUL: I'm just showing you what are the things that are available.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so you can use these extensions. Okay, I will just increase the font.
PAUL: So, in my system, there will be a lot of extensions, so really, you don't need so many.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: you… what you can do, this Python is important, at least you guys install this Python extension, this is very, very important. Okay?
PAUL: Other than that, I don't feel you need anything else, because,
PAUL: The rest of the things you can do step by step. Otherwise, you can use Jupyter also. Like, we'll be working with Jupyter Notebooks, so these two extensions that you can install for now. One is only Jupyter.
PAUL: and the other one is only Python. So don't get confused, open your extensions. If you don't have, you can directly search your Python.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, you can see here this Python, only Python, okay? So, this you can install.
PAUL: And the other one is Jupiter.
PAUL: Okay, so whoever has installed VS Code, or everywhere these two extensions are available, whether it's Cursor, whether it's Windsor, whether it's TRA, whether it's Kiro, everywhere.
PAUL: Okay, so please do the installation of these two extensions for now. One is the Jupyter, one is the,
PAUL: Python. Python and Jupyter.
PAUL: Alright, now let me look into some other chats, okay?
PAUL: Atul is asking, do we need to install all Python versions first? No, you don't need to install. Just keep one Python version, it will do the job. Rajesh, if you install package in one virtual environment, will that be also available? No. Rajesh?
PAUL: The idea is pretty much simple. I told you, virtual environment is an isolated place. It means that if you install something there, it is not accessible to other
PAUL: virtual environment. It has to be pretty much unique, okay? So, don't get confused about this one. The idea is that you should always install the packages as per the Python version. So, always keep those things separate. That's why we create virtual environment, to keep things separate.
PAUL: Okay, so just think about, I'm using a specific version of Pandas in one project.
PAUL: And in some other project, I'm using a different version of mine.
PAUL: then for sure, we know that, like, we can create the same version, or we can create different versions also. But the idea is that you should have two different virtual environments, because within a single virtual environment, I cannot keep both the version of Panda.
PAUL: Okay, it becomes a conflict then, and it creates problem.
PAUL: Alright, now, okay, let me just start the timer now. I will just start a 10-minute timer, and I'll be taking, and I'll be looking into the questions now.
PAUL: Okay, so I think you guys can see the timer, okay, I will just start a 10-minute timer, and then the practical part will start with the virtual environment. In the meantime, anything that you want to ask me in the chat, okay, I will take your questions from the chat.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I have started now.
PAUL: This is done.
PAUL: Shubaz is asking, can we create any number of virtual environments in a single project? No, Shubaz. The idea is that in a single project, you can create multiple virtual… multiple virtual environments.
PAUL: But at the end of the day, you will be using one.
PAUL: Max 2. I feel that most of the times it's 1. Okay, so in this course, we'll be working with, like, one project, one virtual environment.
PAUL: If you're an… like, I am an advanced user, so sometimes I do my testing for other Python compatibility versions, then I create multiple environments.
PAUL: In normal cases, only one virtual environment is required.
PAUL: iFace libraries, support, okay, alright, it happens, not a big deal. That's… okay, now…
PAUL: Any recommended paid tools right now, nothing. Paid tools is required. Most of the things will be free, guys.
PAUL: So don't worry about that.
PAUL: Okay, so… Fikrique, plus, can you check…
PAUL: Okay, can you check to see I have everything installed? Okay, I will come to that, because there are some other tools also, like Git and other things that needs to be installed.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be talking about it, so that's why in the second half, we'll be talking about the remaining tools.
PAUL: Saurabh Divadi, Docker Gitmash, we have not yet installed yet. Sarab will be doing that, don't worry.
PAUL: Sushant, I installed Anaconda, I could not get the…
PAUL: conda prompt in notebook. It's not condo, it's conda. Okay, please restart your terminal. Okay, sometimes a restart is required.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise I will look into that, okay, if you are having any problems. Abhishe, quick question, I'm a beginner, currently only familiar with Python with no background in AI. Yes, he will be able to follow up. It's not a big deal.
PAUL: There are certain concepts that I'll be talking about, if I might refer, which is not part of this course. So, like, after every class, please go through those concepts.
PAUL: Shubade Roy, it would be great if we can, see other colleague chats by what
PAUL: Okay, so Vadim, like, that we never disavail, we will, because the idea is that
PAUL: why you want to look into other channels?
PAUL: If you have any questions, you directly ask me. If I start opening the chat during the class, you will get continuously notification, and that becomes a distraction.
PAUL: For more than one year, many students have complained.
PAUL: Okay, about that. So, if somebody's asking about how to install Python in every class, do you think that it is relevant to
PAUL: Okay, so if you have any questions, directly ask.
PAUL: All right, Rahul Parir, I am on
PAUL: one new firewall, brief install Conda.
PAUL: Okay, yes, that is also fine, like, you can do using brew also.
PAUL: Home brew, that is fine to me.
PAUL: And later on, I will come to the Kamar route, okay? So, just good.
PAUL: Manasa is asking, what is the difference between Anaconda and VS Code? Anaconda is basically the provider of the Python distribution. VSCUD is an ID, where you write code.
PAUL: Okay, Manasa, I hope you get my point.
PAUL: Salvan, there is a default Python that comes with Mac, but that was not accessible, so…
PAUL: I installed 3.13, but when I type Python 3, it gives me the default one.
PAUL: just try to uninstall the default one, I think you can do that.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise, if you have, like, what is the default version, Salman, you can let me know. If it is above 3.10, it works, there is no problem.
PAUL: Okay? Otherwise, I will tell you how to work with custom things.
PAUL: Are you using NATEN? No, in this… in this course, NATEN, we are not using 3K. Please go through the syllabus before asking such type of questions. Mitesh is asking, last time when I was installing Git, it messed up my VS code, and I had to reinstall all. Looking forward for the detailed instructions.
PAUL: Sometimes it happens, because in VS Code, like, when you install Git, a lot of options that comes. Generally, for Linux or Mac users, it's just a brief install Git, that I feel, but for Windows, okay, it's really a lot of options that comes.
PAUL: We'll be talking about that, okay, so don't worry. Then comes, Ridvish Mashvari. Why do we need to install Python extension in VS Code?
PAUL: Okay, now, like, it tells you, like, if you miss something with respect to syntax, linting, in those things, it helps, with which measure. I hope you get my point. Okay, if you have written a wrong syntax, okay, those kind, it helps you.
PAUL: Can I manage with UV? Is CONTA required? Power and ESE can totally manage with UV? Okay, so Conda is not required even, like, I…
PAUL: I will not be using Conda, just because of memory issues from my side. Like, if you have Conda and UV both.
PAUL: Great, that also you can use.
PAUL: Can you please tell me the hours of Eastern Time? Exactly, I have to convert it, but later on, I think.
PAUL: Okay, so majorly the chats I have taken, okay, then comes few.
PAUL: Salman, okay, already told one.
PAUL: A point mask to newly install Python by changing the path.
PAUL: Okay, just have showed what is the default path, okay? Just check your shell.
PAUL: If you are on Mac, you know that for every, like… I think you might be using the ZSH shell. So when you write Python or Python key, actually, which command is getting activated? Okay, you need to have a look into that.
PAUL: Suresh, how do I access the recorded sessions if I miss something? We'll be getting it directly from the dashboard.
PAUL: Okay, Gagan, please, contact amounts work within
PAUL: Anaconda, prompt, or it can be used as Windows. You can work with Windows CMD also, okay? Just have a check. Sometimes, like, you get errors, or most of the times, you can work with Anaconda prompt.
PAUL: Excellent.
PAUL: Because sometimes for Windows CMT, you might need to do a restart and other stuff.
PAUL: How to install Jupyter in VS4, okay?
PAUL: Just install the extension for now, Devi Prasa.
PAUL: Okay, just install the extension for now. Click on extensions, and just write Jupyter and detect that.
PAUL: Okay, any recommended print tools? Not required for now, okay?
PAUL: Can you share your screens? Tell, stop, lock? Because I will just take a break, guys. Okay, just give me 5 minutes break. I will just drink some water, and then I will continue.
PAUL: Okay? So… Just continuously, I've been speaking, so just…
PAUL: So, just wait, I'll be back in 5, okay? Give me 5 minutes.
PAUL: Guys, don't write in the chat, I'm going to be looking into the… just give me 5 minutes, okay, and then I will start.
PAUL: Yes, Diram, please do the installation. RT, I can see your chat on King.
PAUL: Might have posted, but I might have missed it.
PAUL: Just do it.
PAUL: I will look into the installation issues after I complete the classics, just wait for…
PAUL: more 90 minutes of content, I can say, at least.
PAUL: Alright, Ma, so…
PAUL: Let me just minimize this screen. Okay, so whoever has installed VS Code after that, please do
PAUL: the installation of the two extensions, the Jupiter and the Python.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Yes, we'll be using the terminal of VS Code, don't worry, I'll be showing you all those tests.
PAUL: And you will be getting the session recordings, I don't remember.
PAUL: Where I have this. So, I think, you can go to the courses section.
PAUL: Okay, and I think… Here, you'll be getting all the recordings.
PAUL: Okay? Everybody.
PAUL: Who is asking for the recording, so go to me.
PAUL: Alright, so, now let's back to the part of the checklist where we'll be working with virtual environment.
PAUL: Very, very important, this part, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so for this, so let's start, because I don't have Wanda right now. Okay, so I'll be taking the participants, so I think, Ricky, you are there. Okay, I will stop sharing my screen, and Ricky, you can start sharing.
PAUL: Okay, so step by step, I'll be telling the commands, whoever has done, everybody please open Anna contact prompt for now.
PAUL: Okay, Suresh, I will look into that, don't worry, Suresh.
PAUL: Okay, I will stop sharing mine. So, anybody who, is working, I think, from the panelists, anyone.
PAUL: Three to four people are there.
PAUL: So, Ricky, please start sharing.
PAUL: Okay, the commands I've already given it in the Notion, you can copy-paste those commands also. Not a big deal.
PAUL: Okay, Ricky has started sharing his screen. Please let me know, can you see Ricky's screen? Okay, just write, yes,
PAUL: CLS.
PAUL: And hit enter once. Just the idea is to clear it, yes. I think, you guys can see the screen.
PAUL: Okay? Now, we will start working with how to create a virtual environment. As I have told
PAUL: A lot of times that, yes, virtual environment is necessary, and in this course, you'll be creating a lot of virtual environments. So, let's get started. So, right now, it's very specifically for people who have Anaconda in your system, okay? Please open Anaconda prompt, and you will see something like this.
PAUL: Okay, so please open Anaconda prompt. Don't open CMD and Partial and others. Okay? Because right now, I don't know that, Conda is available in those, but I know that within Anaconda Prompt, you will have the access, okay? Just press, Ctrl and plus plus, make the font a little bit bigger. Good at others.
PAUL: Okay, I think the font is visible for everything.
PAUL: How did he go to, command prompt? That is not command from Lalith, it is anaconda prompt. Please don't get confused.
PAUL: And for PC, for Mac, for Mac, you can directly open, okay? So, just wait. See. For Mac, I am sharing my screen. Please look into my screen.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, I think, yeah, you can see my screen. This is Matt.
PAUL: Alright, I will just change the background also.
PAUL: Let me just minimize all this stuff.
PAUL: Alright, for Mac, I think, for Mac, guys, can you see my screen? Okay, for Windows users, please look into Ricky's screen.
PAUL: And for Mac users, please look into mine. Actually, like, I cannot execute, because I don't have Conda only. But the commands are exactly the same, okay? You can follow the case. Just open your terminal, and just be sure you have, when you write conda, you get all the options in your Mac.
PAUL: Because I forgot I don't have that.
PAUL: So, I will stop sharing mine.
PAUL: Now, just open Notion.
PAUL: Quickly open Notion, you have the command.
PAUL: Contact create.
PAUL: You can just write conda space create.
PAUL: Okay, now, here, hyphen anywhere. Hyphen n stands for new guys, okay? Hyphen n stands for new. It means you are creating a new virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay, so that's one. And then comes the name of the virtual environment that you want to take. It can be VLB, it can be Ricky, it can be VIN, it can be BIM, it can be Red, it can be anything.
PAUL: It's totally up to you. So generally, what happens? The name of the project we give.
PAUL: Okay, like a RAD, or RAG project. Okay, so after hyphen N, you have to give the name of the virtual environment.
PAUL: And the name of the virtual environment, it's totally up to. No, no, no.
PAUL: Remove RAG, that VNB can be changed to RAG. Just write RAG. Remove VNB and write RAG.
PAUL: Keep it in small. Use everything in small whenever you are creating the virtual environment.
PAUL: REG. You can keep it in caps also, not a big issue, but I feel that you should always use small letters, okay?
PAUL: Right? Okay. And then, very specifically comes the Python version that you want to work, okay? You have to write Python, hyphen hyphen, then the version. So, for example, 3.13,
PAUL: 1, 3.
PAUL: Okay? Now, see guys, this is the mean command to create a virtual environment using condom.
PAUL: Okay? Using Conda, that's why I'm telling you. If you don't have Anaconda, then please don't execute this command. Okay, for Python compiler, I'll be showing you in the next step. So, don't worry about that. So, press enter now.
PAUL: Okay? That RAG name can be anything, based on your choice. Okay, now you can see that the… these are the following new packages which will be installed. This is the default that comes from contact.
PAUL: Okay? So, now, just press Y.
PAUL: Okay? And hit enter.
PAUL: Okay? Now it's telling you, to activate this particular virtual environment, what you can do, you can write on the activator.
PAUL: Okay, and if you want to deactivate, there is… you have to write contest deactiv, okay? Now, one thing, once he press enter, there is this base. The base will be changed to write, okay? Please hit enter.
PAUL: 3.11 is also fine, you can give any Python version. That's totally custom.
PAUL: Yogesh, getting… do you accept the terms and conditions? Please do accept them.
PAUL: Okay, in Mac, initially, like, if it is not added to the path, then only it will ask for contain it, so Bodhipp, that is fine. You can do a contingent.
PAUL: And then you can execute the project amounts.
PAUL: Okay, so now you can see the base has been changed to red, so base is the default virtual environment for Conda.
PAUL: If you are using Anaconda, or you are using Miniconda, the default virtual environment that comes, okay? So it will have, all the default packages in the base, but RAG,
PAUL: In this rack, I have nothing. Okay, so you can… what you can do, so let's try to install some packages here.
PAUL: For now.
PAUL: To install the packages, you can use two package managers, okay, pip or condas. For now, we'll be using pip. Just write pip space install condas.
PAUL: Okay, and hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so right now you can see the package Pandas is getting installed.
PAUL: In this particular virtual environment right now.
PAUL: So, like, see, installing of the packages is not necessary. The idea is you get the concept, that within this particular virtual environment, you have Pandas 2.3.3. Okay, if you want to know the version of a particular package, you can do pip showpandas, right? PipShowPandas.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. Now here, as you can see here, just scroll above a little bit, I think the version will be shown.
PAUL: Okay, here you can see the version is telling 2.3.3, guys.
PAUL: please focus this part. At any point of time, if you want to know the version of a particular package which you have installed in your virtual environment, simply, like, you can do a pip show partners, okay? Now, what you can do? Click on the plus tab, plus tab.
PAUL: First step, the idea is to open a new prompt, huh? That's why click on the plus.
PAUL: Okay, and this is opening your partial. Just check that, can you open with the drop-down or panacom down?
PAUL: No, the drop-down is there, no, beside the plus sign, there is a down…
PAUL: Beside the plus, plus sign, beside that, you have that drop-down option.
PAUL: Last thing is…
Ricky: I can barely see, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, from the drop-down, just check, can you see Anaconda prompt? Okay, you can see. Okay, just open the… yes, that one.
PAUL: Okay, and, close this, okay? Now, he's back to the base and bar. Increase the font here also, please.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the default environment. Okay, now here do pip show partners.
PAUL: Okay, just scroll above and see what is the version of Pandas that got installed. Can you see here the version is 2.2.3?
PAUL: Okay, it means that in the default one, this comes pre-installed. You have not done the installation. So in Anaconda, the default environment is always the case, you have to remember. Okay, and whenever you create a virtual environment.
PAUL: After that, you have to activate it, and you have to, very specifically use that particular package, okay? Now.
PAUL: Inside the base environment, not all the packages are available, so sometimes you might need to do the installation. Now, get back to your first tab.
PAUL: Okay, where you created the virtual environment rack, okay? Now, here I will install another package. You can just do pip install landscape.
PAUL: Lang Chain. Yeah. Hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so randomly, I'm just installing another package.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see here, this part is important. Now see, whenever you install one package, with that package, you have dependency packages.
PAUL: Now, these are, you can see, installing collected packages, Z standard, XSH hash, URL lib3, typing extensions, tenacity… okay, now, all these. So, let me see, can I mark it or not just wait?
PAUL: Just wait once, let me…
PAUL: Can I? Yes, okay, yes, thanks. Okay, now these are dependency packages. It means that if you install LandChain, these dependency packages will be available in your virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay, so you don't need to, again, reinstall any dependents. That is the best thing that you can do. Okay, so now, if you write pip show Langchen, quickly write that, and check what is the version of Langchen that got installed.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see the version is right now 1.0.5, okay? Now, get back to the second, window.
PAUL: Okay, where you have that base environment, and just try to…
PAUL: Right here, pip show Langchain. It is not necessary that LangChain should be available in this environment.
PAUL: Because, you can see here, it's selling packages not found.
PAUL: It means that…
PAUL: In your base environment, LanChain doesn't come pre-installed. If you want to install, you can simply do a fifth install LanChen, and then it will be installed. So right now, it is not necessary to install it in the base environment, okay? So simply, switch back to the first one.
PAUL: Okay, I hope everybody understood how to create a virtual environment, okay, and then how to activate that virtual environment, how to install some packages, okay, and then finally, you can do an
PAUL: deactivate.
PAUL: You write, you can write conda space deactivate.
PAUL: Okay, I will repeat these steps, don't worry, once more.
PAUL: for everybody.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, Agathika, your error is different? Okay, so, like, upgrading is not required. If you want, you can do an upgrade… upgrade, PIP also, because sometimes, like, if your version of Anaconda is old, in that case.
PAUL: It is required to upgrade the bill.
PAUL: Alright. Now, see, now again, he is back into base. From RAG, the environment has been switched. So once… now he has deactivated the environment, as simple as that.
PAUL: Again, if he wants to activate the environment, the command is conda space activate space rack.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: You have to remember. So, this is the way how to activate an environment. Yes, just hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, and now, again, you will see that. So, always look into the brackets. Within the brackets, what is written? It tells you which environment you are in.
PAUL: Okay? I hope this part is clear, and for most of you, it should be executing.
PAUL: PIP show Python, it's not pip show Python, it is pip show the package, like Pandas, like LandChain.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Don't write something wrong, and then tell me that, like, minu. It's not pip showPython. Once you have installed any package, like pip install pandas, okay, I'm just, repeating those steps, okay? So, just wait. You keep on sharing, I will just add and write those things for better clarity.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just open Zed, where is Z, Z, Z?
PAUL: Yeah. Okay, so see, guys, I'm writing the commands. Just look into my screen. I'm sharing my screen. Okay, so first of all, creating the virtual environment.
PAUL: Using content.
PAUL: So, first thing, the command is to create a virtual environment, conda, create, hyphen n, n stands for new, then the name of the environment, the rag, okay? Then comes the Python version that you want to select, it can be 3.13, 3.12, anything that you can get, okay?
PAUL: Once you have created this, then comes activating this environment.
PAUL: Activate.
PAUL: RHE, the name of the environment that you have created.
PAUL: Okay, so CTRL-Z.
PAUL: Once you have activated that environment, you will see that within the brackets, somewhere, like, RAG will be written. Okay? So, next.
PAUL: This particular, rag… Will be shown within the brackets.
PAUL: Now you have to do this pip install pandas, for example, that I have taken here.
PAUL: Okay? Then, I have executed PIP show pandas, which will show you the version of Pandas that got installed.
PAUL: Okay? If you want to uninstall the package, then you have pip uninstall Pandas, which will remove Pandas from the virtual environment.
PAUL: And then finally, if we want to deactivate the environment, Honda deactivateRAG.
PAUL: Okay, so RAJ is not required, just write contact yet. Okay, so these are all the steps.
PAUL: Okay, that we have done it. I will be sharing it in the chat also, for your reference. Anybody who is getting the error, don't worry, I'll be looking into everybody's asking, okay?
PAUL: Yes, the number say I'll be doing for Python, don't worry. First, I'm covering, Conda, then I will come to pure Python.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: You can see my screen also, you have to just switch the screen.
PAUL: Okay, I have shared it in the chat, all the commands, but, simply.
PAUL: Okay, now I've stopped sharing my screen, but, immediately, the things that are required for this, okay.
PAUL: I think, see, here the Python version is 3.13, but the Python version in base is different. Go back to the second prompt, okay, and just write the same command, python-version. You will see the version here will be different.
PAUL: That is the purpose of using virtual environment. The idea is that, here you can see, it's 3.13.5, and there it was 3.13.c.
PAUL: Okay, as simple as. So, when you create the virtual environment, you can give this exact version, okay, or generally, you can only pass 3.11 or 3.12, or 3.30.
PAUL: Anybody, like, who is getting an issue in executing the steps, please let me know.
PAUL: For map, you have to do conda init.
PAUL: Really, it is not required if you have it in your ZSS shell.
PAUL: Okay, see, guys, really, like, I don't think you can copy it from the chat, but the command is…
PAUL: whoever is getting the issue, don't worry, like, Java, Gore, okay.
PAUL: Just write… the idea is you don't copy and paste, you write it manually. I want you guys to write it. Spend one minute, but write it.
PAUL: Jadhab Kiran, it's Gonda, space create. It's not only create.
PAUL: So, please check the command. See, guys, open your Notion, okay? That's why I shared the Notion, so that you can look into. Ricky, switch to the Notion window once.
PAUL: Okay, please look into that notion, exactly what is written in the notion. See, here you have… I have given all the commands, like conduct, create, hyphen N, like VNB. Here, the name of the virtual environment is VNB. You can change that VNV to RAG. That's why I've given it VNB, your name, whatever the name that you want to choose.
PAUL: Then select the Python version, then activate. Okay, then, like, once you have activated, you can install any packages, and then finally deactivate.
PAUL: Okay? And then, a very specific command, conda remove, which is, like, you can delete the environment also. That's why I've kept it. Now, that's a destructive task, so we'll be doing it at the end.
PAUL: Okay, everybody please try this.
PAUL: Okay, Vikram, is asking, sir, why the Python version is showing different in 2DAT. You have to understand. Say, Vikram, the base environment comes pre-installed from Anaconda. It will have a specific version.
PAUL: Okay? Now, when we created the virtual environment, we gave it a very specific version, like 3.13 only, so it picked up 3.13.0.
PAUL: By default, it always picks up the zeroth version.
PAUL: Okay? So there, if you change it, so that's… that's the purpose of creating virtual environment, so that you will be having different Python versions in different virtual… virtual environments.
PAUL: I hope you get it.
PAUL: The idea is that in every project, we might be using different environments. So, we will be creating different virtual ENVs, or virtual environment in some programs.
PAUL: Do we need the current folder? No, Akash, the current folder is not required. You can be any path.
PAUL: Is it possible to pull pre-created ENVs from online? Yes, it is possible. We'll be talking about that, sir, a little bit late. Okay? I'll be telling you.
PAUL: like, how to pull, or something like that. How to check, installed packages. You can, okay, Ricky, just go back there.
PAUL: To your Anaconda prompt tab, okay? Now here, how to check the installed packages. You can do a pip list.
PAUL: Okay, do in the other one, other one, because here, I think a lot of packages will be there. Go to that rag environment, yes. Just right here, pip space list.
PAUL: If you do a pick list, it will tell you all the packages that you have.
PAUL: Okay, from here you will get all the packages with the version. But if you want to know about a specific package, then you can write fits, space, show, space, the name of the package, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay? Manoj Kumar, I hope you got your answer. Bye Jugavindan. Do we need always to deactivate before we remove? Yes.
PAUL: So, right now, I'm not talking about removing the environment, because it's a destructive task. Rather, you deactivate it. At the end of the task, we'll be talking… at the end of the class, I'll be talking about removing the environment.
PAUL: Hi, Paul, I don't see the plus icon to go to the base prompt.
PAUL: plus sign will be available in Windows Terminal, very specifically, okay?
PAUL: Otherwise, you can open a new instance of Anaconda prompt. Okay, so that also works. He is using Windows Terminal.
PAUL: Definitely.
PAUL: Can you please share the Notion link again? Abhishek? Alright, I'll be talking about that. Can you tell me about annotated type? Annotated Types is a package, basically.
PAUL: Okay, it's a package in Python.
PAUL: There are so many packages, guys. Really, we'll be working with more than
PAUL: 200 to 300 packages. So, really, like, once we start that.
PAUL: Okay, then we'll be talking about it. Kartike, after installing a library, also it is visible. No, I don't think so. Okay, so what you can do, Ricky, so right now, just show me the pandas. Pandas is spelling 2.3.3 here, okay? Now, Ricky, just right here, pay pun, install Pandas.
PAUL: Okay, it's selling, press Y, yes?
PAUL: Okay? Now Pandas has been uninstalled. Now do a pip list.
PAUL: Just check, I don't think Panda should be visible, see? PA packaging is there. Panda's is not there. Please have it checked.
PAUL: Okay? Kartike, Bhagavadi, like, after installing a library, it should not be visible.
PAUL: Otherwise, like, it's a problem.
PAUL: Anura recording, yes, it will be available.
PAUL: Akash, not getting the plus sign all right, already told.
PAUL: Okay, Prajwan, looks like most of the things you have done, so great, can take a sleep.
PAUL: Anurag, I need to leave, I can complete the remaining part, looking alright, fine, RTK, alright. Alright, guys. So, few things that I wanted, creating a virtual environment. Okay, after creating, activating it, then comes the part of installing one specific package.
PAUL: Okay? So, once you have installed the package, you can uninstall a package, and then finally you can deactivate the NVAR.
PAUL: Okay, Srizan, don't worry. Just, right now, just focus on the part where we are discussing about creating the virtual environment.
PAUL: Do library uninstall again? No. Like, just try to run the same command trick uninstall partners. Simply, it will say that, there is no package partners.
PAUL: Okay? Skipping Pandas as it is not installed, so you cannot uninstall a package which is not available.
PAUL: Okay, Sahil, I hope you got your answer. Always, guys, see, these are practical things. You can do the execution from your side.
PAUL: One more thing, if we want to see all the virtual environment, what is the command? Okay, alright.
PAUL: Now, somebody asked this question, okay, if we want to see all the virtual environments, then what is the command?
PAUL: Okay, alright, the command is conda space envis.
PAUL: conda space ENV space list.
PAUL: Hit enter.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, when you execute this particular command of condaENV list, it tells you, it gives you the list of all the activated, environments, okay? So, right now, there is a star sign. So, see, right now, we are using the RAG environment.
PAUL: So, very specifically for that RAG environment, there is a star, okay?
PAUL: So, this tar tells you that this environment is activated currently.
PAUL: Okay, so this star is very, very important.
PAUL: Okay, similarly, go to the second prompt, where your base was activated, and just try to execute the same command on the ENV list.
PAUL: Okay, Lalith, don't worry, I will look into your issue.
PAUL: PIPEX is a different package, Raja. We only be working with PIPEX and the scores.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see he is in the base environment, whose star is very specifically mentioned. Okay? Is this part clear for everyone? If you have 10 environments, how you to know that in which environment you are? Actually, you see, whatever thing is written in the bracket, it tells you that you are currently in this environment.
PAUL: But again, for a final confirmation, you can do a Wanda again with list, and you can always look into that star mark. Okay, that is the other way around.
PAUL: It's Gonda EN Village, Sarania. Please look into the screen.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: It's Conda ENV list. It's not Conda list.
PAUL: If… just write conda list, I will show you what happens.
PAUL: Okay? Now, Conda List is telling me the packages which are available through the Conda Package Manager. Now, these were not installed using PIP.
PAUL: In this course, majorly will be working with PIP.
PAUL: So, if you do pip list, it means that all the packages that are installed using pip. But if you do a condor list, then the packages which are installed using conda.
PAUL: So, right now, I don't want to put a focus on Conda list, because most of the time, we'll be working with pit list in this course.
PAUL: As I told you, both are different package managers. Conda is one package manager, pip. So when you do a pip list, all the packages which are installed via pip will be shown, or this Conda, okay? So that's why it was shown. I hope you get it.
PAUL: Alright, so now working with this particular virtual environment is done, okay? Now, you can simply, okay, you are already in base, go back to the first one, and just deactivate your RAM.
PAUL: Okay, guys, now I will start, because I hope that the fundamental, is done.
PAUL: how to create… okay, now, just write fonda deactivate only. You don't need to write the name of the environment.
PAUL: It's only Conda space deactivate.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. Now let's remove the RAG. Okay, so for that also, I have the command. I will now delete the environment. Because, like, when you are working for a long time, okay, you might have created more than 50 or 60 virtual environments, but you need to delete that. Okay, so for that, we have the command.
PAUL: Conda remove. Okay, hyphen N stands for which environment the name? So, right now, the name of the environment is RAG.
PAUL: And hyphen hyphen, all means everything from that environment that you want to build.
PAUL: Okay, so simply execute this command.
PAUL: Okay, now it will tell you, okay, the following packages and everything that comes pre-installed, it will be deleted. Press Y.
PAUL: Okay, so the environment that we created, yes, press Y.
PAUL: It's telling that it will delete this specific folder also. So, whenever you create a virtual environment, you can see the path. Like, users, Ricky, Anaconda3,
PAUL: where your Anaconda was installed. Inside that, there is an environment folder, ENVs. So, whatever the environment that you create, it will be within this ENVs folder. Always remember that. This is the default path of the environment that you are creating. Now to a condaENV list, you will see that RAG is not available.
PAUL: Okay, show the command to delete it. See, guys? You can open Notion, there also it's written. You can see, right now, no rack. Just,
PAUL: Press the up arrow key and show them the remove command also.
PAUL: on the remove hyphen N, the name of the environment that you have used to create. Okay, that has to be exact, guys. It matches. And then, hyphen, hyphen on.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: Okay, so whatever… see, after hyphen N, it's totally that name that you were given. This is not a standard, like, RAG. You might have given a different rag of your virtual environment. Okay, so based on that, you have to give the exact name for removing the environment.
PAUL: Now, Buddhist Sharma, just be sure you are passing the correct environment name, and just be sure you have that environment.
PAUL: Manuj is telling hyphen hyphen, all whites needed. It deletes everything. That's why.
PAUL: Everything is deleted.
PAUL: Otherwise, it will only delete the instance of the environment. It means that in your folder, directory, few other…
PAUL: House will be remaining, that's right.
PAUL: Hyphen hyphen all means entire cleaning.
PAUL: And you will get the… more storage also.
PAUL: If you don't use hyphen F and all, it only delete the instance, that's it.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think the counterpart is clear for everyone, please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: yes, target, okay?
PAUL: Because this is pretty standard, guys, like, these things we teach when we actually teach Python, that's all.
PAUL: Monish, can you please repeat again? Why, if not hyphen F and all?
PAUL: Obviously, the idea is that hyphen hyphen all removes everything, whatever the folder that you have from your actual EMVs installation piece. If you don't remove, few files are still there. Catch it from, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, and see, guys, one important thing that I want to show you, okay? Ricky, just stop sharing her screen, because there are actually so many commands. I cannot teach you in one class. Okay, the idea is that you should always look into the documentation, okay? And I will just show you that.
PAUL: Because going forward, documentation is very, very important.
PAUL: Okay, I think I should have an instance of that.
PAUL: So, these are common things. The idea is that you guys
PAUL: Okay, so conta remove environment, it's telling the deactivate command, fine. Okay, so managing environment. So, like, this is one link.
PAUL: Like, where everything you will be getting in detail.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see contact create, hyphen hyphen, name you can write, or only hyphen n stands for the same thing.
PAUL: Okay, it's basically the new environment that is the…
PAUL: So, I'll be sharing this link. Okay, so from here, you can get all the necessary commands that you see. Because I'm not covering all those, okay, I am only covering those things that I feel that it is required, okay? Now, for example, like, removing an environment.
PAUL: Okay, can you see here? Conda remove hyphen hyphen name, myENV hyphen hyphenol.
PAUL: Okay? So, this hyphen hyphen, all, everything is removed.
PAUL: You can see contro-env is this command also that you can execute. There are so many commands, but actually, like, I'm used to few of the commands, that only I am telling you. It is not so much required, okay?
PAUL: Okay, now…
PAUL: Using TXT files also, you can create virtual environment, but in this course, we won't be doing such things, so I'm keeping, right now, a few of the things limited. The idea is, later on, you can actually look into the documentation. You have to untest and see. I will tell you the day-to-day usage, but if you want to explore much more things.
PAUL: Simply, what you can do, always look into the documentation of a specific library or a package. Okay, so that's why I shared this particular link with you.
PAUL: What are channels? Channels are a provider of different type of packages. Channels is very, very important, only for Conda. When you do Conda install, then only the concept of channel comes. Okay, but in this course, we'll be doing PIP install, so the concept of channel doesn't come.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I'm not discussing channels. We used to discuss channels back in 2020, so right now, in 2025, you don't need it.
PAUL: Alright, so now this part is done, okay? So now I will be talking about VNE.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just start sharing my screen again. Okay, now I'll be talking about the VNB part.
PAUL: Because Anaconda part, the basics, you guys have already done, and you guys should be comfortable.
PAUL: As you can see here, like, Honda rarely tape majorly, and UV is totally optional.
PAUL: Okay, so what are the things that you have covered? I've told you about the browser-based online IDs also, working with virtual environment very specifically. Okay. Now, let's talk about VNB a little bit, okay, because I feel that
PAUL: This is something, like, for anybody who is not using Anaconda in your system, or Miniconda, for them.
PAUL: That's so… Just wait, okay. Let me just open my terminal.
PAUL: Yes, sweet.
PAUL: Yes, it is.
PAUL: I will just reduce the font a little bit. Alright, so for now, in my system, I have a Python 3, so very specifically for that, as you can see here, I have 3.11.6. This is the default Python that comes through my system. I'm not upgrading.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: Now the question comes, how to create a virtual environment, okay? So for that, what I will do… so let me just create… I will create a folder, okay? And within that folder, I will be creating a virtual environment.
PAUL: So, CD, I will go to my Downloads folder.
PAUL: Okay, and here I will create a new folder, MKDIR. Okay, then the name of the folder, like, ragtestDIR. Okay, this is a random folder name that I'm giving, guys. Okay, so don't think about… you can create your folder anywhere.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, now I have done… let me do a CD.
PAUL: Paste together.
PAUL: Okay. Now, you can see that I am inside this folder, RATTestDIM. Okay, so if I do a simple PWD, it will show the path. Okay, so similarly in Windows also.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is you can be anywhere, you can create a folder anywhere. I'm just using terminal, I'm not using the UI. In this course, I will be always using the terminal, you have to understand.
PAUL: Now, for example, if I want to create a virtual environment only using Python, okay? So, right here you can see the…
PAUL: Python version, okay, now this command, the same thing that you can execute here. Okay, but in my case, it is Python 3, the default one.
PAUL: Now comes creating the virtual environment. Okay, so as you can see here, this is the command.
PAUL: Okay, so what I will do, I will copy this command.
PAUL: And I will paste it here.
PAUL: Okay? Now here, this is the name of the… it can be any name, guys, you have to understand.
PAUL: Okay? So, in my case, I'll be passing 3 in your case. I don't think 3 is required, only Python will help.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: python-m, VNV, and RAG is the name of the virtual environment that I want to build.
PAUL: Okay, so… alright, I think that…
PAUL: All right, this rack got created, this rack folder that I have. Okay, so I know that, this rack environment that got created in, in this particular, I can say, folder, very specifically.
PAUL: Okay? So I am going to repeat these steps for everyone. What we are doing differently now, we are just using Python to create a virtual environment, rather than using content.
PAUL: Okay, so see, there are multiple ways of creating virtual environments. As you can see here, one is Conda. This I have already taught you guys. Okay, the next is using the VNP package. I know there are many students in the class who are not using Anaconda. This is for them, guys.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that you have something.
PAUL: Okay, and, very specifically, like.
PAUL: And how to activate that also I'm just showing in here.
PAUL: Okay, can you see this rat came into the picture? So now, this is the…
PAUL: RAG environment that I've created.
PAUL: Okay, so what I will do, again, I will delete the stuff, again, I will recreate, so that you guys don't get confused.
PAUL: Okay? So… I will just do a deactivate for now.
PAUL: Let me delete this rack completely, okay?
PAUL: Plug it.
PAUL: See you guys.
PAUL: Again, I am showing you from the starting point what are the things that we have done. I think my screen is visible.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: See, guys, now I am creating a virtual environment directly using Python.
PAUL: In Python, there is a concept of VENV, using VENV. VENV status for virtual environment. So, using that, I'll be creating. Now I am inside a RAT. Okay, so I am inside the RAT test directory. Okay, so if I do, this is my absolute path.
PAUL: Okay? This is my absolute path. I think everybody understands what is path
PAUL: Yes, Srikai is asking what is the difference between quanta and pip commands?
PAUL: Conda is a different package manager, okay, and PIP is a different package manager. In Python, you have multiple types of package managers.
PAUL: Okay? So, don't, majorly in this course, you'll be using PIP, so please follow this.
PAUL: So, right now, I am not using Conda. In my system, you know I don't have Conda, okay? So, the command to create a virtual environment using pure Python.
PAUL: Okay, it's as simple as this one. You have to write
PAUL: like the Python? Okay, so, like, in your case, it will be Python only, I think. If it's Python 3, then right. Always, have a check with this one, the Python version.
PAUL: Okay? Always do this. If you're not getting any results here.
PAUL: See, here. Python not found. Then use Python 3. If you have Python, nothing to worry about.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just do a clear. Now, the command to create the virtual environment.
PAUL: This is the simple command.
PAUL: python3 hyphen M, okay, hyphen M is basically using which package that we'll be doing, so this is the package, VENV. And then this is the name of the virtual environment folder that will be created in this rack test directory.
PAUL: Okay, inside this folder only, this virtual ANV will be created.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, now, if I give RAG1, Okay.
PAUL: And now, if I do an LS, as simple as that, you will see that Rank 1 got created. Now, this is the virtual environment folder.
PAUL: Now, if I want to activate this environment, because right now, this environment is just created. It is not activated, okay? So, for that, I will simply do a… see, now this command changes according to operating system, okay? Like, in Mac, this is the command.
PAUL: Okay, so I think it's RAG1. Let me add RAG1 here.
PAUL: Okay? You can see Ragwan came. So, now my virtual environment is activated, and here also you can do the same stuff. Like, pay, install, panda. Okay? Just to show you.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see that, yes, Pandas is getting installed.
PAUL: The same things that was done in Conda, the same things that can be done here also.
PAUL: Okay, it's taking some time to do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, it's telling that, okay, there is a new version of PIP from 23, it's telling me to upgrade, but it's not really necessary.
PAUL: Now, what I will do… I will just deactivate this environment.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, if I do a clear, okay, you will see that that bracket gone now. It means that the environment is deactivated, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: First of all, check the Python version, Nitjal, Narula, okay? The same thing now, I will be doing it in Windows, okay? For Windows, Ricky, please start sharing your screen.
PAUL: Okay, I will stop sharing mine. Now, let's do it on Windows.
PAUL: It's the same standard thing, there is no… nothing new.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right. Now, just do CLS, clear everything, for now.
PAUL: Okay, and right here, deactivate.
PAUL: conduct deactivate.
PAUL: The idea is to even deactivate the base environment, so that you guys don't get confused.
PAUL: Okay, all good. Now check your PI conversion once.
PAUL: Alright, guys, see, now…
PAUL: We are not using conda. The Conda environment was deactivated. Okay, now try to, pass that, same command. Python.
PAUL: write their Python.
PAUL: Space hyphenam.
PAUL: Okay, space, VNV. So, using this VNV, you create the virtual environment, so this is important. Then space, a random name that you can give.
PAUL: Alright, now, this is very, very important. Once you click this, this will be created inside this Reiki folder.
PAUL: So, always, just be sure where you are.
PAUL: Okay, because it's better, Ricky, I think, if you create a folder, and then you execute within that folder.
PAUL: Just create a folder in the invite, just a new folder anywhere.
PAUL: Okay. Anywhere you want to do it. Just create a new folder.
PAUL: Because then, a lot of folders will be shown in your name, Ricky user folder, that's right.
PAUL: Okay, guys, so the same thing he is doing right now is just creating a new folder. So generally, what happens when you work with a project, you'll be creating a new folder on it.
PAUL: Within that folder, you keep your virtual environment. Okay? So, please create a new folder.
PAUL: Okay, and then do a CD and go inside that folder.
PAUL: Yes, if people are using Conda, here you don't need to execute this. This is only for people who are not using Condar and a Conda, so…
PAUL: Like, you can try this out, because going forward, if you feel that after one year, yes, you do need Conda, you can remove. Okay, so you have created a test folder inside Rikki, there is a test folder.
PAUL: Okay, now he is creating it here, okay? Now, yes, press enter.
PAUL: Okay, now this wrap will be created. You can do a DIR.
PAUL: DIR, okay, and you will see this rack folder that got created, okay? Now, to activate this, very specifically, like, source is for Mac only. For Windows, it is different. So, switch back to Notion. The command is…
PAUL: I think it's, a rat.
PAUL: backslash script slash activate. In that way, copy paste that command system.
PAUL: Okay, for Windows, just check, yeah, go below, go below, huh? For Windows, yes, the command prompt. It's written, no, myENV, above that, above that.
PAUL: evolved, yeah.
PAUL: Copy that, and change that to rank.
PAUL: Because RAG is the name of that, and I think it should be activated.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, hit enter. Can you see? RAC got activated now.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, he can write a deactivate, and he can switch off. Write, deactivate and switch off the activated environment.
PAUL: Pretty much standard, guys. I hope this part is clear.
PAUL: Jagaphate is asking how to have different Python versions in two different TNVs. Create two different TNVs, and inside that, you can actually create that. Okay.
PAUL: Now, he has deactivated, okay? Now, by default, what happens, I am telling you, okay? Everybody, please focus here now what, we are doing in the practice.
PAUL: right here, python-F1 version, and check the version. I know it's 3.13.5, but again, just for a confirmation that we're done.
PAUL: Okay, now activate the environment, up arrow key, press 2 times, okay, and…
PAUL: Check what is the Python motion.
PAUL: Yes, hey, Hunter?
PAUL: Okay, now check what is the Python version.
PAUL: Okay, can you see? This is the same version right now. So, here,
PAUL: Basically, okay, what happens? The default Python version, it picks up.
PAUL: You have to understand this particular, thing. So, like, what is the default Python version that you have installed? Okay, that gets always picked up.
PAUL: Okay? So, this always happens. So, in Conda, you do have the flexibility of changing it, but here you always use that default.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, like, this is one way, but I feel that it does the job most of the times.
PAUL: Okay, so, alright, fine, now you can do a deactivate. So, if you're using Python, always remember, what is your typical Python version? Using that only will be… can you change it? No, because you have a very specific version. Otherwise, you have to install that particular version.
PAUL: There are other ways of changing, but I'll be telling you those things, okay? Don't worry about that.
PAUL: Like, how we'll be doing it in the practicals? These are all basics.
PAUL: For right now, if he wants to, delete this environment.
PAUL: Simply delete that rack folder. As simple as that.
PAUL: always delete the rack folder. Like,
PAUL: You can delete it from the EY, or you can delete it from the terminal, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so directly delete this rack folder.
PAUL: As simple as that. So, the environment will be gone.
PAUL: Okay, so it's the same thing. If you try to, activate the same, you can see that it will throw an error. Try to show it in the terminal. Just, there. Use the activate command.
PAUL: Okay? Now you will simply get an error. You can see the system cannot find the specified.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: Alright, so this part is done, guys. How to create environment, because I feel that in this way, you don't have the flexibility of changing the environment always. In Conda, you have the flexibility, okay? Now, I will come to something called as UV.
PAUL: This is something new. This is 2025 standard. Till now, the things that I have taught you, it has been widely used.
PAUL: before 2025, okay? But the idea is to learn the new standards, okay?
PAUL: Alright, you can stop sharing, people.
PAUL: Okay, so… Alright, now let me start sharing my screen.
PAUL: So, optional VNV, this also we have covered, how to create virtual environments, how to delete it, pretty much standard format, okay? Now, there is something called as UV.
PAUL: Okay? So now, what is UV? Okay, so UV is a package manager which is written on top of Rust. Rust is a separate programming language.
PAUL: But Rust is very, very fast. Python is very, very slow, right? I don't like Python, really. I like C, I like C++, even Java is better, Go is good, but Python, really? A bad language. Okay? With respect to speeds, very specifically, guys. Okay, the speed of Python is bad.
PAUL: Now, there is a project called as UV, so that's why I was showing you the UV dots.
PAUL: Now, this, I want you guys to install.
PAUL: Okay, because we are doing us so many things, but the idea is that you should know everything, okay? So, as you can see here, what is the speed of EV? Generally, if you are working with PIP, so it takes 4.63 seconds, but if you're working with EV, the speed is 0.06.
PAUL: So you can see, this is super fast.
PAUL: So that's why I love UV already. Okay? Now, what we will do, we will be installing UV in our system.
PAUL: So, as you can see, what are the main highlights? A single tool to replace everything.
PAUL: Okay? Then, 10x to 100x faster than PIP, provides comprehensive project management and other stuff. A lot of other features are there. The core part is, this is super fast.
PAUL: like, one is papers, like a car, then you can think about UV as just like a rocket, or a jet. Okay, like, super fast.
PAUL: Okay? Now, the idea is to do the installation. Say, everybody, please.
PAUL: go to this particular link, okay? So, installation.
PAUL: It is supported in every type of operating system. If you already have UB, you can skip the steps. Guys, the idea is that for new users, or whoever is doing it for the first time, for them only, time, okay? Please open this particular link.
PAUL: That I have shared.
PAUL: Because other installations are straightforward. This installation, I feel that this is somehow, complex, okay? So, you… can you see this particular command for Mac?
PAUL: And for Windows, this particular command.
PAUL: Guys, you have to just copy this command, okay? Now…
PAUL: First of all, let me start with the Windows users, okay? So, you have to copy the… here you can see this command is for PowerShell, guys, very specifically.
PAUL: In the command, it has been told, it is for PowerShell.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that for Windows users, you have to copy this command and paste it in your cache.
PAUL: Okay? So, now I will stop sharing. I think, Ricky, do you have UV in your system? Please let me know.
PAUL: If you don't have.
Ricky: Not sure.
PAUL: Okay, just check, no. Just, open your PowerShell. Okay, for now, and just write UV space hyphen hyphen version. You will get that ID.
PAUL: Same command I have to write in VS Code, yes. In VS Code, I'll be talking about, because you have to select which shell, Rajesh Kumar, that you need to work with in VS Code.
PAUL: Right now, the idea is to work with your core, terminal. So, if I… right now, this is my screen, okay, if I go here.
PAUL: And if I write UV hyphen hyphen both.
PAUL: Okay, you will see, for me, I have a very specific version in my system. Okay, so for me, the installation is done. In your case, you have to do the installation, because for Mac and Linux, it's very easy, guys.
PAUL: Okay, you have to just follow… you have to paste this command under.
PAUL: But, I will come to that later on. Okay, first, let me do the Windows installation, and then I will ask you to do it for Mac.
PAUL: Okay, so I will stop sharing.
PAUL: And Ricky, I think you are on Windows, so you can start sharing.
PAUL: Because there are a few other commands that comes only for Windows users, that you have to execute.
PAUL: Because Windows is always a bit of pain, that I think. Why not use Bree on Mac?
PAUL: Okay, I think if there is, you can use…
PAUL: preview also, just check that preview is available, like, preview install UV.
PAUL: Okay, that also you can try. I don't think they have released it, but let me check.
PAUL: Bree reinstall, I don't think.
PAUL: Preview and stall, you re…
PAUL: Just check, because I am not done. I use the official documentation which is given.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: They have it, alright? If you have their habit, please do it. You can do that way also.
PAUL: But I always use the official installation tools.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Ricky, so, guys, so let's do it for Windows, okay? So, again, now this is a PowerShell. Close the other windows. The anaconda prompts are not required.
PAUL: Okay, keep only your partial.
PAUL: Now, in the command, it's written PowerShell, guys, so he needs to execute this one. Okay, what he can do, just press enter.
PAUL: Okay, now, automatically, the download will start.
PAUL: After this, I think it tells you to command, that's why, so let's wait.
PAUL: Okay, yes, these two commands, set, path, run.
PAUL: The second one, impartial, and the other one is yield.
PAUL: then UV will be accessible in your command prompt, as well as in your parse. Copy the second, entire thing, copy it.
PAUL: This is important. See, guys, you have to just copy this thing and paste it here. Paste it here.
PAUL: Okay, now this is very specific for Windows only, hit and time.
PAUL: Okay, now open a, copy that from CMD.
PAUL: The first one, copy that. Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, and open a command prompt.
PAUL: Okay, from the drop-down, you'll be getting command prompt, yes.
PAUL: Okay, and paste it.
PAUL: Okay? Now you have done it here also. Now check UV space hyphen hyphen portion, and please increase the font.
PAUL: Okay, so the installation is very, very easy.
PAUL: But you have to do this copy-paste just to access version, version, right, version.
PAUL: Okay, so now he has us. Go back to your partial and execute the same thing. It should be accessible in your partial as a command.
PAUL: Do that again.
PAUL: Okay, alright, here also UV is available, okay? Do that again, okay, Fikri. Go back to that official documentation.
PAUL: Okay, just,
PAUL: the command that has been copied, see. For Windows, this PowerShell command is there, and the clipboard is there, you have to just click on it.
PAUL: Okay? So, and paste it in your PowerShell. I hope you get it. It's pretty much easy. Just copy-paste the command, and after the execution, in the PowerShell, it will tell you two commands. One for command prompt, and the other one for PowerShell.
PAUL: Okay? Just execute these two commands in the respective shells, and you are good to go.
PAUL: Okay. Next, I will come to Matt, so Muddhasar, after this, you can share this.
PAUL: Alright guys, so for Windows, I think this is pretty much standard thing. There is nothing such complex.
PAUL: If I do with pip install UV, with which mash worry, that also you can do. Okay, but you have to remember with which, when you do pip install UV, UV is not global, rather than UV becomes local.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, that is the only difference. Now, I have done a global installation.
PAUL: Okay, if you do a pip install UV within a particular virtual environment, okay, that becomes pretty much a local version. That's the only difference. I don't want to talk about that right now, but you can do that as well.
PAUL: Alright, why use the command prompt set path? Now, see, two commands are provided, one for command prompt, because sometimes I feel you guys might use command prompt. If you're not using command prompt, then don't execute it.
PAUL: The idea was that, by mistake, if you open a command prompt or a partshell… okay, so that's why I told you open that and…
PAUL: It's totally up to you, if you use only partial, because I don't… really don't like partial.
PAUL: My priority is always, come out prompts, then pass. That's it.
PAUL: Alright, so Windows users, please let me know that the installation is done, so that we can proceed ahead for the Mac users.
PAUL: What could be the reason? You have to add that path, Murlin. After doing that, you can see, Ricky has highlighted this white. You have to execute these commands, then it will be available.
PAUL: Vickery Mosa, no. Please, just do that, otherwise I will look into that issue.
PAUL: Otherwise, restart the search. Sometimes you need to close, and then again, restart. That also happens sometimes in a few Windows systems.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise I will look into the issue, don't worry.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Jadhab, Kiran is asking, every time we use UV, I need to install… no, no, no, it's a one-time thing.
PAUL: Only one-time installation. Others, you don't need to.
PAUL: How to upgrade UV on Mac.
PAUL: I think it's… yeah, I just look into the documentation once, because upgrading…
PAUL: Somewhere it will be written.
PAUL: With respect to upgrade.
PAUL: I have not upgraded for last… Upgrade…
PAUL: Just try UV hyphen at an upgrade.
PAUL: Okay, so I think that will do the job most of the times.
PAUL: Okay, because once you have really done it, you don't need to upgrade, because most of the things written here are much more towards the version, towards the Pythoning version. That, yeah, really, we don't need for this.
PAUL: These things we'll be talking later.
PAUL: You can see here how to upgrade a Python version. So, everything is there in the documentation if you go through this. So, later on, like, when we'll be doing the live practicals, we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Alright, now, I think for Windows users, it is done. Now, let's switch to Mac users and do the installation, okay?
PAUL: And whoever is facing the issue, don't worry, I will look it up. Muddha, sir, you can share this.
PAUL: Mdlesa, are you there? Or anybody on…
PAUL: After restarting the VS Code, it's wrong. Alright, great. That's why sometimes the restart of the shared is required in…
PAUL: Windows. That's the main problem that I see always.
PAUL: Alright, you can copy that stuff. Okay, huh, hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so for you also, you can see both the things have been done. Just,
PAUL: To add, okay, restart, either restart your shell or run this. Run this for now. I feel that this is much better. Use the first one. I don't think you are using fish. I think you are using ZSH, and…
PAUL: Bash. So, the first command, source, umha, that one, that one.
PAUL: Copy that. Only the first one.
PAUL: Local bill E… Yeah, correct. Hated.
PAUL: Okay? Now write your wish space hyphen as much.
PAUL: Version, version.
PAUL: Okay, so for you also, like, Mac, the same stuff, like, that command is also not required, but you need to restart the terminal. Okay, then… so for Mac, it's pretty much easy, guys. Okay, there is no such…
PAUL: Rocket science, just copy and paste it down.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Krishna, tomorrow will be starting the actual content for Rev. Okay, so tomorrow, no installation. Directly, your focus on the content.
PAUL: Okay, UV self-update for UV. Alright, people want to do an update.
PAUL: Okay, because, just increase Ctrl plus plus.
PAUL: Madhasar, please increase that font always.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: For others,
PAUL: Okay, so I think everybody can see. For Mac, it's pretty much easy. Similarly for Linux. Linux also the same stuff.
PAUL: In Linux also, Linux and Mac, exactly the same step that you need to go.
PAUL: Alright guys, now can we start working with the virtual environments and UV? Please let me know.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, don't do an UVIN. This is a project initialization, market.
PAUL: Okay? So, you can now stop sharing. Okay, now I will start sharing and show you, like, how I will be working.
PAUL: Am I good?
PAUL: Now, for this entire course, okay, like, I'll be using a very specific terminal, okay, which is referred to as… I don't know. In my other batches, I have two students. Okay, I'll be executing most of the things. Now, this is available for Windows. Previously, it was not available.
PAUL: Now, this is RAP.L. Now, why I love this? Because it remembers everything, all the commands and everything, I really don't need to remember.
PAUL: Okay, so I'm sharing this link. Whoever is interested in using this particular terminal, okay, they can install it in their system. Because for my entire course, what I will do? See, I will do something like this.
PAUL: Wrap, adjust quit.
PAUL: I think, I'll wrap it up.
PAUL: Alright, yeah. So, let me just open a new one.
PAUL: Okay, so this is how this terminal looks like. Okay, now, this is a much more advanced terminal as compared to Windows Terminal, or the default terminal of Linux, or the default terminal of Mac.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be using this tool always.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, I feel that this is much better whenever I work with different systems, okay? It always remember all the commands. Okay, so that's why. And the auto-suggestion is really good. Okay, most of the things that you will be doing, it is connected with
PAUL: a model, basically, an EI model is available. So, if I ask it…
PAUL: Like, what is the… Capital off.
PAUL: Let's example France, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so simply… so right now, what will happen? Behind the scenes, there is a model. The… okay, now that model you can see right here, the capital of France is Paris. So right now, so this is an AI-enabled terminal. The idea is that you guys should use AI-enabled things, so that's why I'm telling you.
PAUL: Okay, is it free? Yes, it is free. But it has a paid plan also.
PAUL: Okay, so… Tell me… Something about…
PAUL: question, okay, so if I ask this… so right now, behind the scenes, an LLModels.com, right? So, start a new conversation, you can see.
PAUL: Okay, so Krishna asks, really, I love this term. That's why. I don't need to open a lot of stuff, I feel that most of the things are done. Okay, and even I can execute my commands. I hope you get it.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to use AI-enabled features. That's why I'm telling you, please install
PAUL: This wrap. Okay, you can download for Mac, download for Windows. Okay, please do the installation of this.
PAUL: Okay, and the idea is, simple, you can actually, like, create an account. This terminal really looks bad. If you look into the terminal, the default one, this is very bad.
PAUL: Okay, so I always use this AI-powered terminal. Okay, it gives me most of the features. I think you can get, like, 50 prompts, okay, like, 50 credits, the free credits. But really, we don't need the paid version, the free version does the job.
PAUL: Okay? Every one of you, please do install. Then I will start working with UV. Okay, because here, when I'll be working with UV, I'll be telling you, like, these are the commands that we need.
PAUL: Okay, let me just clear all this stuff.
PAUL: Okay, everyone, please do, like, if… I think this installation, I don't need to show, you can do double-click, double click, and done. I think you guys are smart for that.
PAUL: Because this is just a terminala software.
PAUL: For everything, I don't need to show you next, next, next.
PAUL: Yes, can you guys do it? Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Satish Tiwari is asking how to install. Just download it.
PAUL: Whether you are on Windows, whether you are on Mac, just download it. As simple as that.
PAUL: Yes, please do a sign-up. Here, I feel that you should sign up. Why? You can do the sign up later on also. The idea is that all the commands that you execute are saved in your account.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, I feel that you should have an account error.
PAUL: Okay, so just think about, I am doing a complete formatting of my system. I will just log into my account, then automatically I get all the companies. That is the best thing about RAM, that I see.
PAUL: Rahul Parika, yeah, Omai ZSH does the same thing, but Omai ZSH is old. I have used it in 2021, 2022, 2022.
PAUL: Okay, but from 2024, I've been using, this one, from the second app.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Alright, so this is done. I installed Wrap and did the sign-up, but how to use the AI? Enable terminal. There is no way, see,
PAUL: There is… simply, you have to just click, guys. Okay, so let me just show you.
PAUL: So, for example, I am right now in my… you have to just write your question, like, what is lynching?
PAUL: Explain. Okay, so I'm just writing the question, okay, and I will just hit enter.
PAUL: It automatically detects, okay?
PAUL: Like, whether, you are basically, whether it's a command or not.
PAUL: So, it automatically detects that. So, really, it's not a problem.
PAUL: Okay, now if I just think I want to go to a specific folder, okay, something like this. Okay, now this is a specific folder that I have.
PAUL: Okay, now here's git understand. So it detects the command and your form, whatever you want to call. It says for 7 days trial, after that, it becomes free. So really, the 7 days trial is basically for the paid stuff.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So I feel that everybody should be using this
PAUL: terminal, because for this entire course, I'll only be using the default terminal. I don't use, really, the other ones. I will be always using RAW.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now, coming to working with UV.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's come to working with UV. You can see, so these are a few of the steps of installing UV that I have given you the official one, but there are some other steps also.
PAUL: So, really?
PAUL: You can follow this, okay? So here are some additional things. Now see, guys, what I will do.
PAUL: CD dot dot, okay, CD dot dot A.
PAUL: Now, I will create a folder.
PAUL: MKDIR. Okay, today's RAG.
PAUL: Coors…
PAUL: 1, okay? So, now I will go inside this folder, you can see automatically CD came, it's using AI, so it's smart.
PAUL: Now, the idea is to use UV to create virtual environments, guys. Okay, so UV…
PAUL: Okay? Then, if I press,
PAUL: Okay, I don't want this installed.
PAUL: Okay, can you see here, as simple as that, using UV, I'm just creating a virtual environment, right?
PAUL: Okay, so… This is a simple command, and it picks up the default Python, okay? So, UVVNV,
PAUL: VNV? Okay, now what will happen? So, this is the name of the virtual environment, guys.vnv. It can be any name. You have to understand, I can pass here rag also.
PAUL: But, in Python, we always keep a standard of using .vn. Okay, so this is just a standard that we do for, okay? Now, if I create, can you see that? Using, Cython 3.13.2, okay, the environment got created, and using this… okay, so if I do an LS writing.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, it's not showing because I have used dot. Dot means hidden folder. For that, I have to do an ls-8. Okay, now you can see there's .vnv. Okay, now to activate this environment, this.
PAUL: It's pretty much easy. Now you can see that, here you can see .vn, this part, at the top.
PAUL: Okay, and then you can install your package, like pip install pandas, or anything, or simply you can do a deactivate. That also does the job. Okay, so pretty much standard.
PAUL: Okay, so once try to do this, then I will tell you how to do Python-specific stuff.
PAUL: First, try the basic one, guys, then I will tell you how to work with very specific Python versions.
PAUL: Yes, everybody, please do sign up after installing RAM. It's suggested, command as well, yes, they do suggest.
PAUL: We won't, be using Visual Studio.
PAUL: Yes, we'll be Visual Studio, but the commands will be same, no?
PAUL: There won't be changes in the commands.
PAUL: AKA, whoever is asking. Just remember the command will always be the same, whether you were in VS Code, whether you were in Carsar, whether it's in BidSum.
PAUL: UV isn't specific to Pythoners, we can make it specific, okay? Now, what I will do, see guys, now I will delete the environment, now I will create a different environment.
PAUL: Okay, RM hyphen RF… Okay, now let me just delete this, virtual environment that I created, okay?
PAUL: Now, I will create a new virtual environment.
PAUL: For that, it's pretty much simple. You have to follow UVVNV. This is the one. Okay. Then, the name of the virtual environment. Okay, for now, let me change the name to RAM. Okay, I'm giving the name of the virtual environment to RAM, okay? And then, like.
PAUL: Before this, I will be just adding the tag of hyphen hyphen Python, okay? Like, whichever Python version that I want. So now I will change to 3.12, guys, see.
PAUL: Can you see now? 3.12 it picked up?
PAUL: Okay, and then simply, see, I can activate this rack bin activate, okay?
PAUL: So now you can see your rack, this virtual environment got created. Okay, now let me just deactivate. As simple, now you can use… okay, now let me just change it.
PAUL: to something else.
PAUL: So, now I'll be showing you to create a different one. Okay, so RAG… okay, let me pass, Raga's there, and let me pass here 3.14.
PAUL: Can you see? Now, 3.14 is getting downloaded. In my system, there was no 3.14. So right now, what it is doing, first, it is downloading the Python from the internet.
PAUL: Okay, and then it will create the environment with that.
PAUL: Now, this is the best thing, so I work with UV. With UV, you can easily, like, download any version of Python. That is one of the best things that I think.
PAUL: So I want you guys to work with… now you can see the, speed of the internet is slow from my side, I see. Okay, so sometimes it might take time.
PAUL: And this is a newer version, 3.14.
PAUL: So, it's taking some time to download the Python. Once the Python is downloaded, later on you can reuse it again and again.
PAUL: Okay, sidekresh, don't worry, I'll be looking into the issues.
PAUL: What is RAGAS? RAGAS is just the name of the virtual environment, guys. Be smart.
PAUL: Last time I used RAG, this time I've used RAGAS.
PAUL: Okay? Now see, what is the version that I am using? 3.14. This is an alpha version, that's why you have that name.
PAUL: Okay, now here I am passing C2. Okay, can you see here RAGAS? So, Ragas is the virtual environment that got activated.
PAUL: Okay? So, simply, I can deactivate. Now, if you tell me, Paul, I want to use 3.15, okay, so, let me just delete all those stuff, okay?
PAUL: Alright, okay. Now, if you change it to 3.15,
PAUL: Really, I've never tried 3.15. Okay, so Raga…
PAUL: Okay, so right now, my UV is not, so much updated. I think because of that, it cannot pick up the 3.15, but later on, like, I think it will be updated.
PAUL: Where is the problem.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, this is not available.
PAUL: Not the exact…
PAUL: Alright, leave it for now, okay? But later on, I know that if I update my UV, okay, I will be having access to that. I have two instances. Actually, I want to delete this one, and I want to use this one.
PAUL: Alright, fine, let me just clear. So, I think everybody can create the virtual environment, please let me know. Is RAP free? Yes, RAP is free.
PAUL: There is a paid version also, but it is…
PAUL: Yes, you guys are using the latest version of UV, that's why 3.15 will work.
PAUL: Actually, I have not updated it.
PAUL: I think for the past 6 months. That's why I'm getting it.
PAUL: Okay, so in Windows, it's confusing. Why it's confusing in Windows? I think for Windows also, it should work. Okay, so let me do it on Windows. Okay, Ricky, you can, just start sharing, you can let me know that, whether it's working or not.
PAUL: Okay, so let's check in Windows.
PAUL: I think the command should be same, there should not be any difference.
PAUL: Sile is the same command for Windows, okay? Yes. So, just check here, UV is available or not, first of all.
PAUL: UV space iPhone version.
PAUL: I don't know, I'm feeling a little bit of lag, okay? Just, I will switch off the video for a few minutes, and then again, I will switch off.
PAUL: Okay, so… yes, UV is available, make it full screen. Make it full screen, and make the font more bigger, because I know a few people will say that it is not visible. Make the font more bigger, because I feel that.
Ricky: Oh.
PAUL: It's a little bit distorted.
Ricky: I don't think that plus plus works.
PAUL: Ctrl-Shift plus Check?
Ricky: couldn't they say.
PAUL: Love it.
PAUL: Ctrl plus plus, because I feel the font works in Mac with Command plus plus.
Ricky: No, for some reason, the rep.
PAUL: Okay, okay, okay, probably with, okay, fine. Alright, just try to pass the command. Ctrl-M++, Matthew Histor.
PAUL: Command will work for Mac, guys, he's on Windows, so he has to work with Ctrl-M++ check.
PAUL: Alright, fine. If it is not working, the core idea is to…
PAUL: Use Ctrl plus, okay, but it's not working for him, I don't know. It happens sometimes, but leave, guys, focus on the command. Write that, command that I have shared. Okay, just write UVVNV.
PAUL: Ctrl plus crawler in mouse, okay?
PAUL: Okay, leave red part, so let me just see if it's working or not. Now, write hyphen FN Python.
PAUL: the version of Spyton Gibbspace, right? Let's go with the older version, like 3.11.
PAUL: Okay? Now space, the name of the virtual environment.
Ricky: with Python, don't we have to give equal equals.
PAUL: No, no, no, here you don't need to give. Only in conda you need to give it public.
PAUL: Okay, now space, the name of the environment that you want to get.
PAUL: Any name that you can think of.
Ricky: That's true.
PAUL: Okay, you are given test already. Hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, can you see? In your system, 3.11 was not there. Because of that, first it downloaded, okay? Now, copy that activate test to script slash activate.
PAUL: Yeah, copy that stuff and paste it. Your environment will be activated.
PAUL: Mmm, it's telling that?
PAUL: Okay…
Ricky: Maybe I can click here, or…
PAUL: No, no, no, it's not about clicking. I think, okay, from the drop-down, just check from the drop-down which cell you have selected. I think it's partial because of that, the execution policy, okay.
PAUL: Same for me, in partial, it happens. From the drop-down, go to drop-down.
PAUL: plus plus on the top plus, and from check, you have CMD or not.
PAUL: Only Bash, shell, you have Bash. NVIDIA Workbench is not required.
PAUL: Actually, then you have to set the policy, okay, then run the command which is given below. The AI is suggesting, yeah.
PAUL: This EI is suggested, no.
Ricky: here.
PAUL: Press the, right arrow key.
PAUL: Where's the right arupy, writer rupee.
PAUL: Right arrow key. Automatically, that entire command will come, yeah, hit enter.
PAUL: Yup.
PAUL: Press, yes to, yes to all.
PAUL: A. Okay, now check that Test Scripts is working or not.
PAUL: Yeah, same command, try to execute. That is the good thing about RAP, it tells you what to execute and what.
PAUL: Okay, can you see now? Test 2 on top?
PAUL: Because now it is activated, Ricky uses, yes, that is the path, actually. You can do a deactivate, right deactivate, and the one, it will be deactivated.
PAUL: It's not showing only test 2, rather than it's showing the complete path.
PAUL: It should work.
PAUL: Yeah, hit enter. Can you see now it's gone?
PAUL: So, in Windows, guys, it is working.
PAUL: Whoever was telling it's not working.
PAUL: That command, please share it in the chat box. Okay, because I feel that a few people might get stuck. Yes, this which AI suggested, yeah. That is the good thing about RAM. Anything you get stuck, automatically it gives you the suggestion.
PAUL: There was no error, there was just some permission stuff. I'm sharing that in the chat.
PAUL: Okay, so this was the command.
PAUL: Okay, like, if you get that error, or policy error, unauthorized access, then only you need for that.
PAUL: Yeah, Fikrimus, I will come to you, don't worry.
PAUL: If you have this error, please execute. I hope everybody understood it pretty much. If you get the error in the PowerShell, simply run this particular command that we have shared it in the chat, give the permission, then it will work fine.
PAUL: Yes, I will take questions at the end, Salman, don't worry. I know many people will have a lot of errors. I need time for that.
PAUL: Still failing, okay?
PAUL: permission, then I just pre-show.
PAUL: This is permission cannot, or open your partial as an admin if you don't have the permissions.
PAUL: Sometime it happens. If you are not an administrator in your system, you might get in.
PAUL: Yes, you can do the same thing, Kartike, in DS code also. Okay.
PAUL: And their own.
PAUL: I generally don't use VS Code, because in VS Code, you won't be getting the EI suggestions.
PAUL: You have to always remember the commands. If you're good with commands, great.
PAUL: Yes, that's the name of the environment, ASMA.
PAUL: Okay, getting this. You have to copy that and paste it in your term.
PAUL: Alright, so this part is done, I will take it, because most of you are telling, yes, it's working fine.
PAUL: Can you write prompts directly instead of command? Yes, you can write… just try to type something, like, what is the capital of India, or something like that, okay? I think it should work.
PAUL: Okay. Yes, it is working fine.
PAUL: So you can write your prompts also.
PAUL: Yeah, wrap did not complete. Generally, it should complete, it will recognize it.
PAUL: Other way, from the drop-down, also, you can use it.
PAUL: like, you can select the mode. There are different modes that you can activate. Later on, see, really, with respect to rap, I don't want to teach rap. The main part is
PAUL: Fans are working.
PAUL: Later on, when we'll be working with prompts, I will tell you what are the different modes and others in here. Okay, because this is a tool.
PAUL: And it's not really related to that, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so this part is done, I will take it away, so I think you can stop sharing now.
PAUL: Now, let me start, sharing my screen.
PAUL: All right, okay, now let me see whether it's lagging or not.
PAUL: Now, a few other tools are there, guys. Everybody, please do install these tools also. Don't leave the class. Okay, they are pretty much standard, tools that you'll be using.
PAUL: Okay, so UB part is also done, okay. Now, yes, you have the version control system. So, Git, you need to download Git, okay? So, if you don't have… how many of you have Git? I think most of you might have. In your organizations, you are working with that.
PAUL: Git. You can do a brief install git for Mac, as simple as that. For Windows, there is an installer that you can use. You can see.
PAUL: I'm sharing the link in the chat.
PAUL: GitHub Desktop after Git… if you want to, really, GitHub Desktop is not required, okay? Deefer. Like, you can use the GitHub Desktop, it's a good tool.
PAUL: Okay, yes, there is a default Apple Git installed, yes, that will work for mine, so nothing to worry about.
PAUL: Okay, but, for Windows users, if you don't have it.
PAUL: Very specifically for them only, I am telling. Okay, please install… okay, here you will see, click here to download the latest version. It was released 11 days ago. We can use the latest version.
PAUL: Okay, simply you can click on this one. Our .exe file will be downloaded into your system.
PAUL: Okay, how many of you don't have Git in your system? Please let me know with a yes or no in the chat.
PAUL: Omizsh does not does the same thing wrong.
PAUL: Here, it has a very specific database, it is connected with your account, it saves all things, okay? That's the only difference.
PAUL: If you don't have, okay. Please do download it, first of all.
PAUL: Okay, for Mac users and Linux users, it comes by default. Okay, so really, you don't need to think about it, but for Windows users, please do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Now, let's take… because after this, okay, let me see what are the other tools that are remaining.
PAUL: AWS CLI, we can do it later on again. This is a markdown guide.
PAUL: Docker also, you need to install, okay, as you can see, Docker, this also, you can download it.
PAUL: This is WSL setup for Windows. In Windows, if you want to do the WSL, I have the link. You guys can check it out.
PAUL: Okay. Other than that, I don't think, CLI tools, we can install it later on in class, in, like, tomorrow I won't be using AWS CLI. Okay, but tomorrow I'll be using RAP, okay, working with virtual environment, those things are necessary, and Git also I'll be using.
PAUL: Okay, if I keep something in Git, it means that for every class, I'll be sharing a GitHub repo with you guys.
PAUL: So that's why Git is important. Please do the installation.
PAUL: Ricky, do you have Git in your system?
Ricky: I have good bags.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, that's the same thing. Like, when you install Git, Git Bash comes with it.
Ricky: Okay.
PAUL: Anybody who want to share their screen, who don't have Git in your system, they can raise your hand. I can ask you to share your screen. You can let me know in the chat, I can.
PAUL: Okay, done 1.
PAUL: Okay, but Dhanworth has not raised a hand.
PAUL: I don't have anybody. MJ…
PAUL: Okay, Dhanvagant, you have raised your hand, okay, I will add you to the panel. Let's go through the installation process, because in Git, really, you get a lot of options.
PAUL: And it might be a little bit confusing for first-time users.
PAUL: I have Mac and not… you can do a simple, see. For Mac users, brief install GitDone.
PAUL: Okay, so it's pretty much easy.
PAUL: You can see Breeze Install Kit for Mac.
PAUL: So, for Mac, it's really just a single command and nothing more. In Windows, this process, I feel that it's a little bit complicated.
PAUL: I'll be using Docker Desktop, very specifically, that I have planned. Probably I can use ProDemand also, but, for now, Docker Desktop, searching.
PAUL: The idea is that Docker client should be there, okay?
PAUL: Really, like, through Polyma, if you are getting the Docker client, it is fine.
PAUL: But I need the Docker client. It means that Docker space hyphen hyphen version, when you do it.
PAUL: Alright, so, let me see… I think…
PAUL: Psy, okay, side, your screen is visible.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, sir.
PAUL: So, you have downloaded it.
Dhanvanth Sai 8C03: Yeah… But be good over here.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah. Yes, it's double.
PAUL: In the taskbar, yes. Okay, so guys, now we are starting the Git installation in Windows, okay? So, it's telling that in C, program files Git will be installed, okay? This is fine, it will take around 345MP, okay? Now, additional options. Now, see, guys, please focus on this one.
PAUL: Really, this part cannot be zoomed, so please don't ask. Okay, so focus here. First of all, additional icons on the desktop, really not required. Then comes Windows Explorer integration, open Git Bash. Okay, now this is fine. Open Git GUI, this is fine.
PAUL: Working with Git LFS, which is the large, file support. Okay, this is fine. Associate.git configuration file, this is fine.
PAUL: Okay, now, check daily for, great updates. You can really, like,
PAUL: Select the last two options also.
PAUL: I think you have Windows Terminal. Okay, so guys, see, what are the options that have been selected? Okay, so majorly, like, we have selected all the options from the below. Okay, I don't think… scroll down below, just check whether there are any other options.
Dhanvanth Sai 8C03: That's it.
PAUL: Okay, nothing. Alright. So now, guys, simply, we have not selected only the first option. Other than that, all the options that we have selected. Now click on next.
PAUL: Okay, good, fine. Yes, next.
PAUL: Okay, now here it's saying, use the VIM, this is fine. VIM is fine.
PAUL: Okay, because how many of you know about VI, VIM, VEO? There are different types of text editors.
PAUL: Okay, VIM does the job, otherwise, like, I will teach you in class, it's better, okay? So, use the first option, yeah, default one, yeah. Okay, please use VIM, yes. Now, click on next.
PAUL: Okay, now let Git decide. Keep this option, everyone. Let Git decide.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, next.
PAUL: Okay, now here that comes, okay, use Git from Git Bash only, Git from command line, and also from third-party software. This is the one that you need to, recommended one. The second option that you need to select, which is the default one, okay?
PAUL: Now, click on Next.
PAUL: Open bundle SSH, this is fine, the first option, again, the default one. Next.
PAUL: Okay, so, use the native Windows Secure Command Channel library. This is fine. Again, click on Next.
PAUL: Okay, now, here it comes, like, check out Windows style commit unique style line endings. This is a default one, you can use it.
PAUL: Most of the things are default, you don't need to actually check it out. Yeah, click on next.
PAUL: Use Minty. Yes, this is also fine for Git Bash. Minty is there. Yes, next.
PAUL: Okay, fast forward and much, this is fine. Next.
PAUL: Okay, Git Credential Manager, next.
PAUL: Enable file system catching, yes, install, now click on Install.
PAUL: Okay, now the installation will start. So, a lot of default options are there. Okay, you have to use those default ones only. In the starting point, only all the options, except that add to desktop icon. Just kept them.
PAUL: have been using Veeam here. Veeam, like, anybody who is working in industry, I think.
PAUL: Everybody is working the same, at least with Linux-based servers and others.
PAUL: Yeah, launch Gita Bash.
PAUL: Alright, now just, here you can actually pass a few Linux-based commands, so you can type your ls.
PAUL: Write here some Linux commands, yes.
PAUL: Click enter.
PAUL: Okay, now you can see. Okay, so where you can write PWDCD, so all Linux-based things that you can do. Okay, and…
PAUL: With that, you can, like, simply… now you can easily start cloning different type of libraries. Okay, so in your… open your VS Code once.
PAUL: Okay, click on the third, third one, third one.
PAUL: Hug.
PAUL: Exactly.
PAUL: Okay, so it's telling, now close it, I think it was not closed, kill this VSput, and open again.
PAUL: Okay, so actually you need to reload VS Code, so completely kill it and open it again.
Dhanvanth Sai 8C03: Now, you want me to close this?
PAUL: Kiss.
PAUL: Close this one.
PAUL: Okay, now again, open VS Code.
PAUL: Close as one, closer. I think the esports should be.
PAUL: Click on VS Code, click on VS Code, yeah. Somewhere, like, probably is.
PAUL: Okay, now click on that third option. Okay, so here you can see now, initialize a repo and publish to GitHub. These options should be there, because most of the times, I'll be sharing a GitHub repo, and you guys will be cloning them, that's all.
PAUL: Okay, if you have these two options, really great.
PAUL: You don't need to worry anything about it.
PAUL: Manoj Kumar, it's… for Mac, it's where you installed.
PAUL: Alright, this part is also done. Now, in the next step, what you can do, you can download Docker Texture.
PAUL: I only have clone repository thing. Yeah, Genej, that is fine. He has actually opened a folder. Because of that, he's getting those two options. If you…
PAUL: If he will just close that, you will get that clone option. Don't worry about that.
PAUL: So, this part is done now, just open the browser and try to search for proper text.
PAUL: Because you'll be working with Docker Desktop a lot.
PAUL: Do you have Docker installed? Anybody? But it shows open folder, I will come to that, don't worry if anybody is getting it.
PAUL: JACS said that is fine. If anybody is getting that clone repo, initialized repo, everything is fine.
PAUL: These are simple steps, okay? So, like, if you have problems, you can let me know, okay? At the end of the class, I can ask.
PAUL: Rancher desktop? Yes, that is also fine. See, I need the Docker client for the Masaurus. That is the main thing.
PAUL: Yes, I'll be showing you the steps initially, when we start working on projects, Jane, don't worry about that.
PAUL: Okay, so people, everybody please install Docker Tech also. If you don't have Docker Tech.
PAUL: Please do download Docker Tech.
PAUL: And you can see it installed off a desktop on Windows.
PAUL: So, for every operating system, it's here. So, simply for Mac also, Okay, so…
PAUL: Directly click on the first option, rather than… you can get it from the Microsoft Store also, but this option is there, which will help you to download that.
PAUL: For our map, also, you can see.
PAUL: Docker Desktop for Apple Silicon and Intel chip. You can install this.
PAUL: And for Linux also, you have that. In Linux, really, it is easy. You don't need to think about that alone.
PAUL: Okay, so you can do simple an APT gate install docker in that room. You can do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, you can see FPT get installed with the genome terminal after that. By default, you will have the genome terminal if you are working with Ubuntu. You have to just, do this.
PAUL: After downloading the Deviant package for…
PAUL: So let's start with the Windows. I feel that Windows… please download this one, and then same double-click. If anybody wants to share their screen, let me know, for Docker Desktop.
PAUL: Yes, you can use Spotman also, no issue.
PAUL: Findroid. Innovation.
PAUL: Okay, want to share later on, Sagari, so when I start taking the doubts, then I will ask you to share.
PAUL: Rajit Khanna, hi Paul, need to drop off, I got recorded, yes, he'll be getting the recorded session.
PAUL: Yes, we need a container runtime engine. That is basically the Docker client that I'm referring to.
PAUL: Okay, so from here, according to your operating system, please do download, and you have to do the installation. Anybody wants to share their screen for Docker Tech? Simply, you can let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Right now, we don't need Docker, really. I don't think in the initial
PAUL: a few weeks, you need talker. Later on, also, you can do it.
PAUL: But the idea is keep it installed in your system. That is the main thing.
PAUL: Okay, Asma Sultana, you want to share it? Alright, fine. Asma Sultana, I will add you to the panelist, and then you can start sharing.
PAUL: Sudh Nair is asking, Paul, sir, I see add folder to workspace in VS Code for a good… yes, that is fine. Add folder, that option is also fine, but in the cloning option, you should get something like an repo and other.
PAUL: Can you share some GitHub tutorials? It is already attached with the software checklist.
PAUL: Docker tutorial is there, UV tutorial is there, I think. Then you have your… get all the tutorials from Chris Sir's channel, I have added it.
PAUL: So, quickly, if you want, you can go to them.
PAUL: Asma Soldzana, please start sharing. You are in the panelists.
PAUL: I mean, cloud CLI installation.
PAUL: When you're working with cloud, then I'll be showing you step-by-step mode.
PAUL: Okay, all the cloud in AWS. AWS CLI, skipped that part. Today, we won't be doing that.
PAUL: Because when we'll be discussing AWS at that particular point of time, I'll be teaching you how to do the AWS CLI installation. But for now, not right now.
PAUL: Soltana, are you going to share, or anybody, like, who wants to install desktop, they can share simply.
PAUL: Modrasal, you update your if you want to share for a bit.
PAUL: Yep. You can start sharing.
Mudassar Hakim: On… on it.
PAUL: Keep your office stuck by minimum.
PAUL: Yeah, minimize this.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, so… what do I need to do now? Terminal?
PAUL: please, just, minimize your Teams and other office stuff, yeah. Minimize all the stuff.
PAUL: Okay, Victor.
PAUL: Just open your browser and search for Docker.txt.
PAUL: Docker Desktop, have you downloaded it?
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, mmm… But just a second.
PAUL: Sorry, Docker.
Mudassar Hakim: Yes, yes, sorry.
PAUL: Okay, Ashwarya, just, wait after this, just raise your hand in the meeting.
PAUL: Just radio.
PAUL: Yeah, Apple Silicon sign. It will take some time, this package is a bit.
PAUL: For beginners, Docker desktop I recommend, but once you are comfortable with Docker, really, you don't need the desktop. Everything can be done from the terminal.
PAUL: Yes, everything is recorded, don't worry.
PAUL: This entire session.
PAUL: Yeah, that's why, like, what happens if something's confidentially shared in the screen? Then I will ask the editing team to cut stuff.
PAUL: So, that's why. It's for everyone. If you feel that something you have shared, okay, then you can ask me, simply call, please corrupt that part from the recording, I will delete it.
PAUL: In the meantime, Ashwarya, you also please download for Windows. If it is downloaded, please.
PAUL: If Docker installation is restricted for you.
PAUL: You need the Docker runtime. That's the main thing. Now you have to check, because…
PAUL: There are others also, like…
PAUL: Rancher Dopper is also there, Borderman is also there. Other alternatives, Rajesh, you have to live.
PAUL: Because I want to keep it generic, because most of the things I'll be looking get on here.
PAUL: Docker hyphen hyphen version.
PAUL: Okay, yes. Probably a restart is required. Docker takes your services to restart as well.
PAUL: And one important thing in your BIOS, everybody has a system. I think everybody knows about BIOS.
PAUL: in your BIOS, virtualization should be installed.
PAUL: Yes, Rancher, desktops, Polyma, okay, fine. These are the other alternatives, I'm just… okay, I will later on show.
PAUL: Okay, so that is it. What is BIOS?
PAUL: Really, guys, like, what is BIOS?
PAUL: You have your system, you have a motherboard. On top of that motherboard, you have a BIOS.
PAUL: Where you have your entire hardware setting. From there, virtualization needs to be available.
PAUL: That I cannot show you.
PAUL: Okay, in Windows, like, whether you have an Intel processor or an AMD processor, you have to go to that,
PAUL: BIOS settings you need to enable. By default, it is always enabled, but sometimes it is not enabled.
PAUL: Excellent.
PAUL: Yeah, it's simple drag and drop, and nothing.
PAUL: Mac, it's that only. Once drag and drop is done, directly you can go to the Docker and you can open it.
PAUL: It should come.
PAUL: No, this is fine, simple, drag and drop also works in Mac.
PAUL: Use the first option by Google, Docker Desktop for Windows 6, 86 and 64.
PAUL: Yes, docker.app, I think. It should show Docker Desktop, actually. Okay, open that. The logo is that same.
PAUL: Okay, accept.
PAUL: Use the recommended settings.
PAUL: Yeah, give you a passport.
PAUL: Don't allow statement anymore.
PAUL: Alright, in your case, it is done. Okay, the installation is done. Few is just those welcome set up that you need.
PAUL: Like, work email address, this you can skip also, not necessary. Okay.
PAUL: Yes, so, see, on below, you can see engine running.
PAUL: This is the main thing. Engine should be running, that's fine.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, so you can see this green color signal, and even on the top also you will be getting, on the top bar in Mac, that Docker desktop as well.
PAUL: At the top.
PAUL: Yep.
PAUL: And the first, for first icon is for Dexter. The first icon.
PAUL: decimal. Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
PAUL: Now, yes, 4 years done, now…
PAUL: Ash for here, if you want to share your screen, you can go ahead. Now, this is for Windows, guys.
PAUL: So today's class is mostly run, so after this part, I will start taking your doubts, whatever the problems, one by one. You guys can share this.
PAUL: Have you downloaded it?
Aiswarya Goriparthi: No, I haven't.
PAUL: Okay, that should have done okay. So, just, check, from the left-hand side to go below.
PAUL: Check that, Docker Desktop.
PAUL: Docker Desktop. Explore Docker Desktop. Explore Docker Desktop.
PAUL: Yeah, click on that.
PAUL: Okay, now here, otherwise, let me just search that, optionally and share the link with you.
PAUL: Because docker.lap copy link… In the chat, I have shared one, link. Okay, please click on that.
PAUL: In the chat I have shared directly, it will start the download.
PAUL: I've shared it in the chat, the link to download, just click on that directly.
PAUL: And your downloads should start.
Aiswarya Goriparthi: This one?
PAUL: In the chat, I've shared the link.
Aiswarya Goriparthi: Okay.
PAUL: Check the chat, boom chat, boom chat.
PAUL: I have already shared the link for Windows.
PAUL: Anybody else who want to share their screen, like, explore it?
PAUL: It's not available. The core idea is that's it. Whenever you go to that page, okay, so here you can see, under this option, Windows Install. So from here, you will be getting this.
PAUL: Okay, as simple as that. Here, the first option, Windows, x86 and 64.
PAUL: You can do it from Microsoft Store also, but I won't…
PAUL: For you guys to do it.
PAUL: this option.
PAUL: Just download this one, and then again, the same stuff. Next, next, next, and another concert.
PAUL: And here you can see, in Windows, there are a lot of other steps. Okay, so you can see here, administrator privileges and installation. Okay, so this particular guide that you have to find.
PAUL: Now, Hyper-V backend, whether you have it or not, I really don't know. But, really, like, WSL is required.
PAUL: Because, really, like, Docker was built for Linux-based and Mac-based systems. Later on, the support came for Docker
PAUL: So, this particular link that you actually need to follow.
PAUL: And go step by step.
PAUL: Okay, so anybody else who want to share their screen? Because for Windows, it might take some time, so really, I don't want to jump on. You can go through that entire webpage, and you can look at it.
PAUL: Jagaphat is asking, asked me to share a screen. Jagapati already.
PAUL: Alright, now I'll quickly start sharing, Jagobat.
PAUL: I have added you.
PAUL: It can start shaking.
PAUL: Because that's 12.40 to… I have to take the doubts also, so please start quickly, guys.
PAUL: Initial sessions take time. Going forward, I know that the session will be done by 12.
PAUL: Okay, so these are some installation classes, so…
PAUL: really takes for initial setup, the idea is that everybody is on the panel.
PAUL: Okay, use WSL2 instead of Hyper-V recommended, yes, go for the first step, click on OK.
PAUL: We will never be working with Windows containers, we'll be always working with Linux-based containers.
PAUL: Alright, now, let's wait for this. This process takes time in Windows.
PAUL: Pawan, do we have to create the Docker account? No. Docker account is…
PAUL: Right now, not required. If you're pushing your own image to your own account, then only I will suggest. But really, now it is not required.
PAUL: Alright, okay, now it looks like it will take time, nothing that I can do, so let's wait.
PAUL: Okay, now, with respect to problems, now I'll be start… now I'll start the doubt-clearing part, guys, everyone.
PAUL: Okay, so for doubt clearing, like, whoever is having issues, they can raise their hand. First of all, from the panelists, anybody wants to share who has a problem, like Vikram, Ricky, Mundasar, anyone else.
PAUL: Because I will move everyone to the participants now. That's right. Anybody has any problem, let me know.
PAUL: Yes, you have to close and restart it.
PAUL: It happens. With desktop and other stuff, you need that.
PAUL: It will take time, this process of installing DockerText for daily text.
Mudassar Hakim: Paul, we were, looking at that, session breakup last time we have mentioned, right? If you could just kind of break down all.
PAUL: Yes, yes, like, I was working on that in a few weeks I have done. Okay, that part I will complete, and I will update it initially.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
PAUL: Don't worry, like, tomorrow, that… but I've given a task to an intern, he was actually doing.
Mudassar Hakim: Nice.
PAUL: to re-verify the stuff, and I have to find it.
Mudassar Hakim: Awesome. And also, Paul, if it's possible, definitely the things we are doing in the class, but if it's possible, you can add some assignments and exercises.
PAUL: And later on, when I start teaching, like, every weekly task I will wouldn't.
Mudassar Hakim: So, at the end of the session, you know, we have some stuff to try.
PAUL: ideas, after 2 months, like, we'll be forming groups also, okay? Like, 3 to 4 people. Because really, I know, like, when I say one guy, he doesn't do it. I know, when I create a group, out of that 4, only 2 or 3 months.
PAUL: That is a common pattern we need. So that's how you'll be forming the group. But once the basics are covered.
Mudassar Hakim: Right. I mean, that is needed, of course. I mean, creating a portfolio is a very important thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Modo Mario.
PAUL: She's asking for coupons. No, ma'am. See, this month, all coupons are done. Next month, again, we'll be sharing the coupons.
PAUL: I think we can…
PAUL: Yes, Munish Naware, for Docker, he mentioned that virtualization should be enabled at a BIOS level, exactly.
PAUL: Okay, if you have restrictions in your company laptop, then you can use it in a virtual machine.
PAUL: Second.
PAUL: Even for working with virtual machines, or VMware, or VirtualBox, your virtualization needs to be enabled in this.
PAUL: Okay, this is done, okay, close and restart. Okay, this part is done. Yeah, close and you have to actually restart the system. That's it.
PAUL: Alright, now, okay, so there is nobody from participants, okay? I will move everybody.
Vikram: Hey, Paul, we come here, so are you going to annotate any other stuff? Like, are you going to.
PAUL: No, no, nothing. Now I will just, start taking the doubts and installation.
Vikram: Oh, I'm logging off.
PAUL: Okay, hold on.
Vikram: Yeah, thank you. Now the installation part is done, Ashwari, I don't need… I mean, you've been teaching.
PAUL: Let's start with Salman. Okay, you have any doubts, Vikram?
Vikram: No, no, I'm good.
PAUL: Muddhasar and Vikram, I will move to…
PAUL: Bitcoin also will change over to Attempt D.
PAUL: Okay, Asma, Aishwarya, Ganwat, any doubts?
Asma Sultana: Oh, good.
Dhanvanth Sai 8C03: No pun, I'm good.
PAUL: Okay, so Sarma, let's start with you, then we have Dinesh and Josan.
Salman: 3 people I have unmuted. You guys can let me know if you want to reshare this.
Salman: Yeah, thanks, Paul. Thanks. One question. Paul, I have one question, like, when we install UE, can we install it inside the Python virtual environment, or I need to install it at the.
PAUL: Yes, like, and that is not a global installation, so what happens?
Salman: And you can do a piped install UV.
PAUL: That becomes a local installation, the global one.
PAUL: There are other features of UV also that, later on, that I'll be discussing. Like, directly, you can do UV, add the name of a package.
PAUL: Okay, now, for those advanced features, I feel a global installation is required. That's why I taught you that.
PAUL: Rather than even, like, for beginners, simply, they create a virtual environment, and inside that, they do a quick install.
PAUL: But again, a lot of features are not enabled in that case, so I feel that it's better to go ahead with a global installation, okay?
Salman: Okay, and I have some questions, you know, at, you know, for… related to RAG design-level questions, so shall I ask it here, or provide.
PAUL: Don't ask, drop me a link. If you want, drop me a meeting.
Salman: Okay.
PAUL: to look into the installation. My mail is app at the redfishnight.in.
Salman: Okay, yeah. I'm working on, you know, RAG applications where I have some questions, so I'll just drop you an email.
PAUL: Yeah, okay, I have shared the email.
Salman: In the chat, okay, so you can…
PAUL: Alright, next, Dinesh, or Josan, anyone?
PAUL: Dinesh?
PAUL: Josan, two people have asked to unmute.
Joesan: Paul, I don't have any questions.
PAUL: Okay, alright. See, people who don't have any questions, don't raise their hand, okay? I get confused.
PAUL: Let's go to Kaushik.
PAUL: Bashik?
PAUL: Satish Kiwari.
PAUL: I'm just unmuting, randomly. Daksh Gupta.
PAUL: My problems cause you. Okay, alright, solve it.
Daksh Gupta: audible?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, Dutch.
Daksh Gupta: Yeah, so basically, I would like to know that, are we going to use the terminal of the VS Code, where we can write all the things, or we are going to use the wrap, right? So, I'm a little bit confused.
PAUL: feed.
PAUL: I won't be using the VS code a lot.
PAUL: I use it sometimes, but actually, when I'm in a class, if I'm using 50 commands.
PAUL: That day, I'll be using RAF function.
PAUL: If I'm only using one or two commands, then probably VS Code terminal is…
Daksh Gupta: Okay, but can we use this in our office one? I'm not sure, because.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, everybody is using RAM.
Daksh Gupta: Can we install it? Because we need to install it first then only, but we don't have the admin rights to install it.
PAUL: See, if you don't, cannot, if you cannot install it, simply use the VS Code.
PAUL: Okay. I told you about this because the idea is that it remembers all the commands. If you are executing in the first day, even after 30 days, 1 month.
PAUL: two months, it will remain. Otherwise, you have to manually type it. That's the only thing.
Daksh Gupta: But one thing that Warp, how it is connected to the VS Code virtual environment, all the things, because we are giving.
PAUL: Wrap is not connected. You have to understand. Shells are connected. Wrap is connected through a shell, which is the bash, or ZSH, or inventory CMD, or partial. Similarly, VS code is connected to the shells. So, VS code is not connected to Wrap, you have to understand.
Daksh Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: I hope you get my fun.
Daksh Gupta: So, by the shell, both are connected together, and whatever the instruction we are giving over here, it will be running on the VS Code, right?
PAUL: It will be running on the VS Code.
PAUL: VSput is the ideal. Nothing runs on VSput.
Daksh Gupta: Bate.
PAUL: actually the compiler, or probably if you're doing a debugging operation, then it might be running on that ID, but most of the things will be, like, on compiler. So, I can write the code in VS Code, then I can just execute it in VS Code also, terminal, or probably in any type of terminal, like…
Daksh Gupta: Got it, got it. Okay, okay, thank you.
PAUL: Hold on.
Satish Tiwari: Yeah, hi, Paul, Satishias.
PAUL: Yeah, Satish word.
Satish Tiwari: Yeah, my cousin is the same in…
Satish Tiwari: In Rapids, we are creating a new project.
Satish Tiwari: Is it… Deb in my local or, in cloud?
Satish Tiwari: Weird…
PAUL: No, no, everything is… see, guys, RAP is just a terminal app, nothing more.
PAUL: In Windows, there is an app called as Windows Terminal.
PAUL: Okay, which has basic features. I told you about the app, which has little bit advanced AI features. That's the only difference. Other than that, there is no difference.
Satish Tiwari: So it'll be…
PAUL: For example… yeah, yeah, go ahead first, go ahead.
Satish Tiwari: So, if you are committing any code in my repository, then directly it will be committed, right? Correct?
PAUL: Not directly, at least you have to do, no, like…
PAUL: Git commit hyphen name? Yes, yes.
Satish Tiwari: The same thing, the same command, whatever we are writing, let's cod.
PAUL: Exactly, correct. The same thing that works in Windows. Now, here, if you look into, if you got an error, like in PowerShell, it suggested, you know, you have to run this command, then it will be solved.
PAUL: Okay, now that is the best thing, like, if you get errors, it suggests, okay, now this can be a possible solution in, so that's why I feel it's good.
PAUL: Whereas in Windows Terminal, you have to copy-paste that command and search in browser again in Google. Okay, that's fine.
Satish Tiwari: Okay, I have installed, but I don't know… My age… Our rat is not working.
Satish Tiwari: Are you sharing my screen?
PAUL: Okay, she can share the screen, I can add you to the panelist.
PAUL: Next, argil, Ajay, Krishanu.
PAUL: Then comes Utpama, Piranjada, few people I have unmuted, so one by one, you guys can do it.
PAUL: Hello?
upama: Hello, I have… I'm Utmaneu.
upama: Hello? I am facing…
PAUL: Wait, wait, wait, no, wait. Now I'm looking into Saty screen, then I will take the question, okay?
upama: Okay.
Satish Tiwari: You guys getting…
PAUL: Mamanu, Ridvish, a few people are there, so one by one, I will come through.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Type here something.
Satish Tiwari: It's not incorrect.
PAUL: Yeah.
Satish Tiwari: Suppose if I want to create a new folder, then how are you doing?
PAUL: you want to create a new folder. So you can just write here, first of all, just be sure where you are. Just write PWD. You will get the correct path.
Satish Tiwari: We don't reconnect.
PAUL: Okay, now hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so this is your path. Now, right here, MKTI, create a new folder.
PAUL: It's just like a normal terminal. Nothing fancy. Just AI is connected, that's…
Satish Tiwari: Okay, got it.
Satish Tiwari: All right. Yeah. Yeah.
upama: Can I share the screen?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: I will add you, yes.
PAUL: Yes, after Permano, like, Ridvish, Ajay, like, anybody who wants to share their screen, first of all, like…
upama: Yeah.
PAUL: aka's Rob.
PAUL: what AKs?
PAUL: Hi, Keith.
Ajay: Oh my god.
Ajay: finishing.
PAUL: Sikiri… Sikhri Musa, raise your hand. If you want to share your screen, please do raise your hand.
upama: Can you see my screen?
upama: Yes, I can see your screen. Yeah, I… I just, installed this Docker desktop. So, it was asking for the email ID for personal or work. I chose the personal.
upama: And then it restarted. Then… but, you can see, you told me… you told on the class that engine should always be started, but on the left-hand side, you… on the bottom, where I'm showing.
PAUL: Yes, the engine is stopped. I know, I know. You have to do a WSL- and update this command, try to execute it.
upama: I, I have… I've copied.
PAUL: Done.
upama: Yeah. Copy, and show me, like, what is the output.
upama: Where's outdoor restart?
PAUL: Have you executed? No, no, no, no. Before restarting, have you updated WSL? Tell me.
upama: No, no, I have not updated WSN.
PAUL: You have to do… first, you have to update, then only you can execute.
PAUL: Open partial, and copy-paste that command, and just check what are the things that have been shown.
upama: Okay, okay, okay. And, I miss certain class, in that this wrap, wrap. Should we have to sign up… sign up in the wrap itself?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes. I suggest everyone to do a sign-up, because all the commands that you are executing, it will be connected to your account. If you format your system, later on, again, reinstall wrap, so it becomes a sync. So that's why it's good.
upama: Okay, okay. Thank you, Lynn, I'll try it.
PAUL: execute this WSL hyphen hyphen update, it will show you certain things. Once WSL is updated, then Docker Engine will start, okay?
upama: Okay, thank you.
Ajay: All right.
Ajay: Paul, can you give me access to me?
Ajay: I'm sure it must be.
ARGHYA: Yeah, Jay.
PAUL: Okay, so…
ARGHYA: Or let me know.
PAUL: went up.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let people know.
ARGHYA: Yeah, yeah, so… Yeah, I will add you.
PAUL: It's a pleasure.
ARGHYA: Schoenberg.
PAUL: Do you have questions, or you want to share your screen, Ari?
ARGHYA: I had questions, but…
PAUL: Okay, go ahead. Questions are faster. Go ahead, 10.
ARGHYA: So, Paul, thanks for the session. I missed the last… this is actually my first session today.
ARGHYA: I, I won't.
PAUL: switch session.
ARGHYA: last session, I think.
PAUL: Wait, wait, right now I'm taking our business.
PAUL: So, the introduction session.
ARGHYA: Yeah, I missed that. I… I don't agree.
ARGHYA: So… Couple of questions, right? So, I have…
PAUL: Boy.
ARGHYA: developing a new RAG application for my… personally, even for some of my organization needs. So, one of the challenges is, that I faced, is, the chunking strategy.
ARGHYA: So, are you going to go into depth into… Yeah.
PAUL: Like, I don't know, like, how many years of experience is that?
ARGHYA: Are you asking me?
PAUL: Yes, yes, I'm asking you.
ARGHYA: By 12 years.
PAUL: So, okay, see, I will be talking about more than at least 6 type of chunking strategy. I'll be talking about a very specific library called as Chunky. I'll be talking about a child-parent relationship chunking strategy.
PAUL: that we are using it in production. I'll be talking about those things, don't worry. When I say rare.
ARGHYA: Right, right, right. Right, so I'm not.
PAUL: I will go in depth.
ARGHYA: I, I, I.
PAUL: I'm going down.
ARGHYA: And, just a suggestion, because this topic doesn't get covered a lot.
ARGHYA: There's a lot of times when we have to chunk huge XML files, right? So, or JSON is a quick… I mean, even we can take this argument for JSON, but if there is some specific chunking strategy for huge nested XMLs and stuff like that, so can you, can you.
PAUL: Now, it depends upon the same. Data types, I cannot right now say.
PAUL: I have taken… I will be taking one example, probably, like, 5 different types of files, probably Markdown, VDF,
PAUL: Python, I can mix all those things to make the context, but yes, you can let me know that, Paul, can you take this? Because, see, before showing something, I have to test it from my end also, that's it.
ARGHYA: Right. The reason why I'm asking this is these are real-time business problems. So, most of the.
PAUL: Thanks, love you.
ARGHYA: We are trying to work on something. It's some, weird.
PAUL: are, like, very deeply nested data that we are working with. Oh, that's fine. Like, you can… one thing you can do, like, if you see that some part or some sample data you can share with me.
ARGHYA: Okay. I'll try to, I'll try to show you.
PAUL: 10 metric.
ARGHYA: Okay.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: already. Now, you see, for this BIOS, go to your BIOS, whoever is sharing the screen yesterday.
PAUL: How many are biases setting this together?
Ajay: Oh, this bio…
PAUL: I was…
Ajay: I said.
PAUL: BIOS, maybe you have to restart your system.
Ajay: How'd go.
PAUL: F2 or F3?
Ajay: Okay.
PAUL: get into the motherboard settings. Now, from the motherboard settings, you have to enable mouse.
PAUL: You have to enable virtualization from the.
Ajay: Oh, it makes sense that I will take care.
PAUL: Okay.
Ajay: The another thing is, I tried to run this command. It is failing, but other commands are working.
Ajay: Can you guide me why it is failing this command?
PAUL: Just, okay, now this, you are passing. Just, do a clear, clear, clear. Just do a complete CA, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, the prompt part is not working, probably, like, when you ask something to the…
PAUL: Okay, and now, write your deactivate. You don't need a base.
Ajay: deactivate?
PAUL: Yeah.
Ajay: No, I just want to put on, like, what is it? Any kind of a sentence to… Okay, trying to pass…
PAUL: to pass, try to write what is the capital of France, England, anything like that. What happens, what is there? Let me see.
PAUL: There is no integration of RAP with VSport, guys, so don't get confused. Dinesh, the question that you are asking.
PAUL: RAP is a separate terminal, we escort terminal separate.
PAUL: Okay, it's telling that, it is not, recognizing, okay, just open a new tab, because it's actually not recognizing. When there is this mark, it means that
PAUL: No, no, no, don't do that. On top, there is a plus button.
PAUL: And also, please sign up.
PAUL: Because once you sign up, then you will get the access to AI.
Ajay: Okay, okay.
PAUL: We have not signed up. Please do the sign up, then you will have access to it. Right now, it's just the terminal. That's why I told everyone to sign up.
Fikri Musa: Okay, so…
PAUL: Without a sign-up, access to AI only will add up.
Fikri Musa: all.
Ajay: Okay, you want me to close it and reopen again?
PAUL: First, do sign up, then reopen it. Okay, it should be connected to an account. EI access is given to an account.
Ajay: Then, then it should work, that's what he says, right?
PAUL: Then it will…
Fikri Musa: Hey, Paul, can you help me? I'm trying to share my screen with you, because I was having trouble from, like, the very.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fikri Musa: How do I share my screen with you?
PAUL: There is an option.
Fikri Musa: Okay, sure, there we go.
PAUL: button, yeah.
Fikri Musa: Oh, there we go, share. Okay.
Fikri Musa: I was trying to, first use, UV,
Fikri Musa: First, I was, this is what I was trying to do, but I got basically lost when I was trying to use UV, when I was actually trying to install it.
Fikri Musa: installation document, is it… was it right here, I believe? I believe it was right over here where you told us to go a couple.
PAUL: This is the official installation document.
Fikri Musa: To do it. So I believe… I believe this was the one you told us to copy it, right?
PAUL: Yes.
Fikri Musa: Okay, we do a copy over here, and we go to PowerShell, is it?
PAUL: Yes, partially.
Fikri Musa: Okay, we go to PowerShell, and then, I guess we copy and paste this one, right?
PAUL: Just hit enter. Hit enter, yeah.
Fikri Musa: Okay, because sometimes it was taking me longer.
Fikri Musa: I think my computer…
ARGHYA: I wanted to make. It's easier if you use wrapper, so I just… what I did was I just pulled Warp or WAP, we just installed UV for me, and it… it already.
PAUL: Welcome back.
Fikri Musa: particularly dreaded. Okay.
PAUL: I didn't get…
Fikri Musa: I didn't get the warp. Yeah, my warp, I never signed up for it.
PAUL: Okay.
Fikri Musa: Okay, so how do we go to that second step? Remember that second step you said?
Fikri Musa: After this?
PAUL: Actually, like, after the installation, that part is shown. Okay, so what you can do, just check Ubispace hyphen hyphen version, just check whether it is available or not.
Fikri Musa: Face…
PAUL: Because that particular command comes after the installation.
PAUL: Or you have to kill it. Okay, now UVA is available. So really, like, now you can create an environment from here. So really, the next step is not required, because it is accessible.
Fikri Musa: Okay.
PAUL: Madrid.
Fikri Musa: I need to learn.
Fikri Musa: Okay, how do I use, which one is it? Warp. My… okay, Warp, I need to sign up. How do we use Git? I got into… I got into Git, and I think I believe I signed up for it, and, I need to see Git, and basically have a clone to, to upload the.
PAUL: Click on the third icon, that is the main gate icon.
PAUL: third icon, from Larry.
PAUL: Yes, definitely.
Fikri Musa: I'm lucky.
PAUL: Below that, below that. That is the files. Below that, there is a search. Below that. The third one.
PAUL: You have git, no, that's why cloned Report option is coming.
PAUL: Yes, yes, you opened, yes. This is correct, it is installed in your system.
Fikri Musa: Okay, so just click this.
PAUL: Yes, if you want to, right now, if you want to clone any repo, then you can do that.
Fikri Musa: Okay, what else do I need to know? .
PAUL: Git is working fine in your system, so nothing to worry.
Fikri Musa: Okay, okay,
Fikri Musa: Warp, I basically need to sign up for it. What was the last one we did?
PAUL: Oh, yeah. DockerTech on.
Fikri Musa: Yeah, I never signed up for rap, and then it was the last one, shoot. And then.
PAUL: Docker desktop, that only stuff.
Fikri Musa: My… yeah, my dock stuff wasn't working either for some reason. I think it was stuck.
PAUL: open.
Fikri Musa: I, I…
PAUL: It happens sometimes here, like, in Windows, a little bit of problems. What is there?
Fikri Musa: The error is right here, it doesn't start up right now. I restarted my computer.
Fikri Musa: Does it start.
PAUL: I opened up a texture.
Fikri Musa: Yeah, seems like it's something wrong with it. Maybe I need to restart my computer again. Yeah.
Fikri Musa: What else do I need to learn? I don't know what I did wrong, I don't know.
Fikri Musa: My Docker is not working. What does Docker really used for? What is that we use that for?
PAUL: kind of…
PAUL: containerization of the application. So just think about, we have built something on Windows. The idea is to make it available to everyone. During production, we majorly work with Linux-based systems, okay? So, we'll be creating an image, and that image, we'll be deploying it in some type of AWS EC2 instance directly.
PAUL: So I'll be keeping this image in a registry, and then from registry, I'll be pulling it in production.
PAUL: through a CI-CD pipeline.
Fikri Musa: Okay, so I need to learn more about that, because it doesn't seem I really… I really understand.
PAUL: I attached a video in Notion.
PAUL: From there, you will get an overview.
Fikri Musa: Okay, from where, where's the video?
PAUL: Notion, notion, notion link I shared, no, initially in the class.
Fikri Musa: Okay, can you please share the motion links? Because most of us have to restart our computers, and we don't have all the links.
PAUL: That's why I told everybody, please, do that convert it. Bookmark it, just wait, I will share it.
Fikri Musa: Yeah, show us the ones that we really need.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, just wait, I'm sharing, just…
PAUL: Okay, yeah, I think, yes, I have shared it again. Please keep it bookmarked. Everybody keep this bookmarked.
Fikri Musa: Which ones do we need? Do we need all of them bookmarked?
PAUL: Just keep this link. This is a main link where you'll be getting the resources and other stuff.
PAUL: Just give this page a bookmarked.
PAUL: Yes, Grish, you can drop nothing of those. This is mine, like, if you want…
PAUL: To drop a meal for that only revenue.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Hello?
PAUL: Now go below, into the tools and installation, you will be getting the videos also that I have attached.
PAUL: But initiated.
Fikri Musa: Okay.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Hello? Yeah, hi, Juan.
PAUL: Yeah, Riddish.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Yeah, so Paul actually have two questions. Number one, this WAP that we have installed, this is connected to, when we are, querying something, is this LM installed in our local system, or is it in cloud? Because if I…
PAUL: API. API.
Ritvij Maheshwari: record. Two…
Ritvij Maheshwari: in the organization, would there be any issue if I talk to my IT, they will directly tell that via… means in my organization, even ChatGPT is blocked.
Ritvij Maheshwari: So, in that case, I can't install this, right?
PAUL: Yes, then if API calls are blocked to a wrap, because generally, when there is a firewall, internet firewall, you add specific entries, like for ChatGPT and others. If there is an entry which is blocked for a wrap, if I feel then you cannot use it for sure.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Okay, Paul, the second question is that, the trainings that you have provided, the modules and everything, the thing is that, I have started those trainings, but let's say,
PAUL: How would I?
Ritvij Maheshwari: The, Udemy training, the modules that you have?
PAUL: Okay, okay, okay. The thing is that you have given 3 modules, and it is impossible for me to complete that in the next coming classes. Nobody needs to complete it, we have just given it as an add-on.
PAUL: I'm telling you, don't need to watch a single video there. The idea was, if you don't know Python, then just go through the basics of Python. That is the basic requirement.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Okay.
PAUL: The videos are not related to the things that I'll be teaching.
PAUL: Two things might be related, but majorly more like autogen. Of course, AutoGen is not, like, pattern.
PAUL: like man sharing. So, those are additional courses, the ideas that you explore.
Ritvij Maheshwari: Got it. And there would be no correlation. Got it. Yeah, that's it. That's it from my side, yeah. Thanks.
PAUL: I'll write that question.
Fikri Musa: Can you please do us a favor? How important is RAG with… well, in regard to the rest of what AI has?
PAUL: When you actually include, data science, when you include, tomorrow, I'll be talking about data science.
Fikri Musa: Okay, okay, okay.
PAUL: That is tomorrow's class, like, Introduction to RAG, what is RAG, pros and bows are RAG, such papers are RAG, everything.
PAUL: From tomorrow, that will be tough in the morning.
PAUL: Okay, anybody else? Okay, Rajat is there, Monisha's there, Siran is there.
PAUL: Any others? What too quickly, please, step by step.
PAUL: Alright, do you want to share anything? Please let me know, fake free Muslim, because others want to share this. Others want to share. Srivam, raise your hand, okay?
Monish Naware: Yeah, well, you can hear me?
Monish Naware: You sure?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, I think it's Monish, no?
Monish Naware: Yeah, so, I just wanted to reinstall VS Code as well as Warp, right? I'm having trouble, I've signed up for Warp, but I'm having trouble signing in again. That's something I'll look into it. But during the course, which ID we'll be using heavily? Is it VS Code or Warp?
PAUL: I really see. I cannot say which IDE. I use different IDs in different classes.
Monish Naware: The idea is, you should know VS Code.
PAUL: I use Major League Wind Surf.
PAUL: Or try. Okay, these two. Okay, now, since some classes, I use Kiro also.
PAUL: I've never used VSport Original, I use VS Code Insiders.
PAUL: That's the thing.
PAUL: If you know one ID, easily you can switch to another, it's not a big deal.
Monish Naware: Yeah, so that's fine, right? So if… as far as we have VS Code,
PAUL: Because I… I use paid plans of VenSub sometimes, so, like, I use VenSub much.
Monish Naware: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so we're like…
Monish Naware: Absolutely.
PAUL: The thing that I am doing, the same thing can be replicated in any end.
Monish Naware: Beautiful.
PAUL: Stop.
Monish Naware: Thank you.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: Yes, next, anyone can go Srigam or anybody else. Yeah, how do I go ahead and share the screen here?
PAUL: Okay, Sriram, I will add you to the panelists just wait.
PAUL: I was strong.
PAUL: Okay, then Rajat, Kiran, You guys can let me know. I have questions.
PAUL: Would you all agarwan.
PAUL: Yeah. Everybody I have done, because from, you know, we have time, because…
PAUL: 1.45, the other mentor will log in, that's right, with you guys. We have minutes.
Rajat Sharma: Bob.
PAUL: Yeah, Paul, I have questions. Yeah, yeah, Rajat, please go ahead.
Rajat Sharma: Yeah, thank you for, first of all, for conducting this course. I watched the first session.
Rajat Sharma: I got to know the audiences also working in enterprise organizations, so good to hear, like, the use cases from there as well.
Rajat Sharma: Bob, a couple of questions, related to installation, like.
Rajat Sharma: we have dependencies sometimes on the front end as well, so how do you combine Python with some front-end, and then make the…
PAUL: Now, really, see, that is a full-stack stuff that you were asking me.
PAUL: My job is really, like, see, if I'm talking about a backend, your backend services are totally different, your front-end services are totally different. I never mix both of them.
PAUL: I hope you understand the concept of microservices.
Rajat Sharma: Yes, yes.
PAUL: we never keep both the things in a single application. My database is running in some container, my backend APIs are running cobweb in some container, okay, through…
PAUL: orchestration, everything is connected. So, like, if you have a very specific UI of React or Next.js running, okay, that is totally separate. My backend APIs will be connected.
PAUL: Probably my database APIs will be connected.
PAUL: Okay, so both the things, I never keep it in a single container. I keep things separated always.
Rajat Sharma: Okay, I've heard about, like, CMake, so I thought, like, maybe we can…
PAUL: The creatures are different.
PAUL: See, generally, that is a big difference. Here, also, little bits. See, again, for CMake, I have to teach you.
PAUL: to do the installation. Little bit things are there, because I know CMET is a problematic thing in Windows. For that, you need to install VS build tools and other stuff. But really, Mac and Linux are very, very easy. Just one command and everything is installed.
PAUL: I can show you some level of automation that we do from the Python backend stuff, generally for environment setup, for,
PAUL: like, environment setup, package installation, for those type of stuff, we do use CNE.
PAUL: Okay, but really, but, again, like, not every developer is using it.
PAUL: We use Siemen because, see, really, if somebody is learning today, or, like, one year back, they won't be using it. But who has been using Python for a long time? Like, 6 years, 7 years, those guys you see.
PAUL: Like, I use CMake in production, because using one small thing, I actually… I call my entire script.
PAUL: There are certain scripts that I use through Bash and others that I call. So, yes, it is good for automation that I think.
PAUL: Okay, for automation, for Docker builds that I can use CMA.
PAUL: But, really, that back-end automation, not front-end.
PAUL: Because I'm much more a back-end engineer, I really don't work with front-end things.
PAUL: My job is to provide the APIs to the front-end team, and based on that, they generally consume the APIs data.
Rajat Sharma: Thank you.
Rajat Sharma: Another question is, like, in our organization, we use Azure DevOps.
Rajat Sharma: So, as you told… mentioned, like, in the course, we'll go ahead with the CI-CD approach as well.
Rajat Sharma: So, what do we use in this course, and what learnings I can take for Azure.
PAUL: We'll be using GitHub Actions. Majorly, we'll be using GitHub Actions. For Siri, I will check.
PAUL: Because you can plan with Argo CD also, or some other… because there are so many tools. In the data science part, okay, there are a lot of CICD tools, very specifically.
PAUL: For that. But, Major League Kyle?
PAUL: Jenkins I don't want. I feel Genkills is pretty old. Majorly all the organizations are using GitHub, so majorly it will be done with GitHub Actions.
PAUL: and AWS. Probably, like, I'll be taking the repo, I'll be building the script, I'll be pushing the image to a registry. From the registry, I'll be pulling that to a specific instance, and within that instance, I'll be running it, or probably, like, what I can do, I can take it as an
PAUL: target service, like, container. So, these are all, like, a, majorly, it will be container-based. I don't want to move to Kubernetes, it's a costly service.
PAUL: to launch, okay, but majorly, I will keep things majorly with respect to containers.
PAUL: I hope you got my point.
Rajat Sharma: Yeah, I got your point. Yeah. Another question is related to, like, I don't want to go in-depth, but simple things.
Rajat Sharma: We are already using a RAG, but now we want to enhance the complexity. We have a lot of PDF documents.
Rajat Sharma: And they're very complex, so they have some factual information, numbers in the figures related to products or manufacturing process.
Rajat Sharma: And…
Rajat Sharma: I came across techniques like vision language models, or OCR. Maybe OCR are not good. So these are the…
Rajat Sharma: And internet is so confusing, you don't get the proper.
PAUL: Like, guidance, how to proceed.
PAUL: No, no, don't think about it. Like, if you have a problem in a specific component, always let me know. Generally, like, based on VLMs, VLMs is, like, it's… what I can say, it's computationally very expensive task. It means that to run a VLM, I need a very good instance, first of all.
PAUL: Light-based VLMs are not very good. Now, for OCR type of tasks, generally. Now, the question comes, can you go ahead with API-based systems, or you need to actually install an OCR engine?
PAUL: That's the main thing, because if I feel that I can use an API-based system. Right now, the best one simply that you can go ahead with is Mistral OC. Or probably, like, if I want a local OCR engine, you can try out. Pattern OCR is good.
PAUL: Okay, a few other OCR engines are there from Snow Labs, OCR, that is also good. Okay, so now we have to decide that what type of system that you want.
PAUL: Based on that, you have to take the decisions.
PAUL: So, like, whenever you have a component-related question, like, in your pipeline, like, this is a component, you can always drop me. I can let you know that these are the three alternatives, and these are the 8 alternatives always.
Rajat Sharma: Okay, sure, yeah. We are using in our organization Azure, stack for RAG approaches.
PAUL: Generally, like, see, if you are going with Azure, I feel Azure Doc Intelligence is pretty good.
Rajat Sharma: Okay.
PAUL: There is a service, previously the name was Azure Form Recognizer, I think.
Rajat Sharma: The biggest change has been to that documented television.
PAUL: That service I have also used, like, I think last year I mentioned. But after that, like, for the past few months, I've been using most Mestral OCR a lot.
PAUL: Okay.
Rajat Sharma: Yeah, thank you, thank you so much, yeah.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: But…
Rajat Sharma: No.
Jadhav, Kiran: I apologize.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: I haven't finished MSD?
PAUL: Okay, first, get an go. Okay, then I will come to it.
Jadhav, Kiran: You don't have an option to share screen, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, I have to add you to panelist. Okay, in the meantime, who wants to ask the question, let me know in the chat, rather than sharing this in who wants to ask only question. Please let me know in the chat, quickly I will answer.
PAUL: Others, like, okay, nobody wants to ask any question about that training.
PAUL: I want to ask question, Rajesh Kumaru, so let me know.
Rajesh Kumar: Hello?
PAUL: Yes.
Rajesh Kumar: Okay, so I don't have permission to install this Docker desktop. What other options I have, then?
PAUL: Leave it, like, if you don't have, later on I'll be telling you. There is the Rancher Tech Stop is there, Olima is…
Rajesh Kumar: Isn't it enough to have Visual Studio Code and all the.
PAUL: It is enough, it is enough. See, enough is defined by… it's not defined by me. How much enough is for you, it's not for me.
Rajesh Kumar: And I feel like I should be able to complete all your assignments, or whatever you're teaching, that's… I should be able to follow.
PAUL: So that part will be done. Right now, Docker is not required. Later, if Docker is required, I will tell you that we can switch to, like, AWS and other stuff. If in your local system it is blocked, it is not a big deal. Try to check at least, like, Rancher Techstop and Columa. A few other students have suggested that, so that part you can check, okay?
Rajesh Kumar: Okay, that's fine then, because Warp and this docket…
Rajesh Kumar: Desktop is not allowed for me. I tried.
PAUL: No, it's fine. Like, I know, there will be many candidates. Actually, like, if you're using office laptops, you cannot run so many things.
Rajesh Kumar: I cannot say. Like, in class also I'll be teaching, you cannot use such things.
PAUL: In models, you will be blocked and other stuff. That is the main problem, like.
PAUL: Okay, in that case, probably you can switch to an online instance, and there you can export most of the stuff.
PAUL: Okay.
Rajesh Kumar: Models are not blocked, right? Models can be used, because we can install the packages in Visual Studio.
PAUL: you can do. For model downloads also, if they block certain servers of having such the model.
PAUL: Nursing.
Rajesh Kumar: Okay.
Rajesh Kumar: Okay, and apart from that, I already have this, Copilot installed, integrated with my Visual Studio course.
PAUL: code. So that can be also…
Rajesh Kumar: That is a fine, right?
PAUL: See, like, I am, like, you can… that is just a client.
PAUL: A little client.
PAUL: with that, what you are using, totally, like, it's fine. You can use, like, GitHub to buy.
Rajesh Kumar: Okay, so for time being, I can manage with VS Code, and…
PAUL: is, like, I think your Docker will come probably after one month, so don't worry. Your initial class will be, most of the things, it will be executed.
PAUL: When we'll be probably dealing in a project? Then there can be problems, and then switch to an online instance.
Rajesh Kumar: Yeah, because in my company portal, I saw they were asking for some… it's a Docker business they had.
Rajesh Kumar: And that needs a lot of approvals.
Rajesh Kumar: To install it.
Rajesh Kumar: They don't have Docker-free version.
PAUL: Tomorrow, we'll start with the RAC part, guys. What is RAC, the main fundamental thing, okay?
Rajesh Kumar: Thank you, thank you, yep.
PAUL: moderate language.
PAUL: Yeah, I bought it.
Jadhav, Kiran: Paul regard, if you're able to see my screen, when I… when I log into WAP, right, it is asking me for create new project and open repository. Should I go for the default one?
PAUL: Nothing you need to click.
Jadhav, Kiran: Okay, so it's a default one that we need to do, right?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, those things are right now. We don't need to explore.
Jadhav, Kiran: And regarding the Git installation, I have completed my Git installation, but for some reason, it is going into Anaconda,
Jadhav, Kiran: All right.
Jadhav, Kiran: Drive where it is being installed.
PAUL: That default, like, see users, username and account. Okay, just right here, like, PWD, hit enter.
PAUL: Yes, it's inside C Users MKI, I think.
Jadhav, Kiran: Yeah.
PAUL: MKR is your username.
PAUL: No, anapunter 3 now, because this… the path is slash MKR, so it's not inside… anapunter 3 looks like an environment to me.
PAUL: Is it an environment?
Jadhav, Kiran: No, it is, see, my anaconda environment looks something…
PAUL: close. No, no, no, just close. Kill it and reopen get bash once. This is a get bash action.
PAUL: I think for the dash.
PAUL: Looks like that becomes the default path query.
Jadhav, Kiran: Yeah, that's becoming the default part here.
PAUL: Really, like, see, I want to be working with Gridbash a lot here, so really it's not a…
PAUL: Probably. Okay, sorry.
PAUL: Because I feel this is the name of the user, generally, it comes sometime.
PAUL: Anaconda City.
Jadhav, Kiran: And my… if I see my Anaconda prompt, right, when I click on Anaconda prompt, this is… it's taking this path.
PAUL: Just do a Condai envi list, show me.
Jadhav, Kiran: Here, in, in research?
PAUL: dear, huh.
PAUL: Generally, within the brackets is the name of the environment.
PAUL: Conda ENV space list.
PAUL: Space list.
PAUL: the base environment is only activated. This is why this anaconda is being shown.
PAUL: Because… Because I can see the star mark is in base.
PAUL: roughly.
PAUL: Now, see, because, based on this, I know that, like, base is equal to anaconda 3 in your system.
Jadhav, Kiran: Correct, yes, agreed.
PAUL: Now, why it has been done so really, like, little we try to debug. Because I know everything is working, but in your system, Anaconda 3 is equal to base. So that's why Anaconda 3 is being redirected to this particular base environment.
Jadhav, Kiran: So, in this case, if I have to integrate my Git Bash to.
PAUL: There is no… no, no, there is no problem with this one. Just open the third button, I think third, second button.
PAUL: Left-hand side, second button, the clone option.
Jadhav, Kiran: Yeah, okay.
PAUL: Yeah, everything is working fine, nothing you need to change.
Jadhav, Kiran: Holder.
Jadhav, Kiran: So, this I need to do publish to GitHub.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, nothing, nothing, nothing you have to do. When I will teach you to publish to data.
Jadhav, Kiran: Okay.
PAUL: Right now, I'm not taught anything, so I…
Jadhav, Kiran: Sure, so I don't have any issues in my installation part as is.
PAUL: Yes, yes, everything is working fine. It's just that text was being shown.
PAUL: That's not a problem.
Jadhav, Kiran: Okay, here. Thank you.
PAUL: Yeah, sit down.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: Paul, yeah, I've so far, done the Python, this installation. I finished installing Anaconda, I went through the N100 variables, added this
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: paths, right?
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: And then I went and installed VS Code 2. I need another UV, and the other next following steps, you know, the steps you have mentioned here, this for virtual environment, I need… I need some help with it.
PAUL: You can watch the recording later on, because if you ask me to repeat that content, that is not possible. If you ask me you have a problem with it, then I can help you out.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: It's awesome.
PAUL: Follow, basically.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: Basically, you're attending.
PAUL: Yes. So this is the main content that we have done.
PAUL: If you have any problem, you can let me know tomorrow that Paul is it. When I was watching the recording, this is the problem itself.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: Okay.
Sriram Venkatasubramaniam: No, no, this class, what happened, I thought, the Eastern time kind of mixing, I got, lost by, like, an hour or something, I lost the time that there.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
Amit Singh: Walter, am I audible?
PAUL: Yes, you are audible?
Amit Singh: Okay, I think audio was not working. Can I ask… can I go ahead now?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, border, golden.
Amit Singh: Okay, so, rest of the stuff is done, just wanted to confirm if my Git is properly installed or not.
Amit Singh: Not good at Git, and Docker Engine has stopped.
Amit Singh: it was trying to communicate to WSL, I got some message, and then after that, like.
PAUL: I've added you two panelists, share your screen.
PAUL: Okay, Manoj Kumawat, Harshit, Jagapati, PAG774.
Manoj Kumawat: Yeah, hi. Hi, Paul, this is Manoj.
PAUL: Yamond.
Manoj Kumawat: Yeah, I had a question. Yeah, I had… no, I had a question regarding using the virtual environment. Virtual, actually…
Manoj Kumawat: a virtual cloud.
Manoj Kumawat: Rather than using my desktop.
Manoj Kumawat: So…
PAUL: Virtual cloud. Virtual cloud means something, like, which cloud do you want to use?
Manoj Kumawat: I'm thinking of Oracle Cloud, do you suggest, Different one?
Manoj Kumawat: Because desktop, I don't want to use…
PAUL: Okay, in every cloud, you will get an instance. Within that instance, you can get a Linux instance, and you can do everything.
PAUL: I have no problem, later.
Manoj Kumawat: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, you can do that. I have no issues with that. Just, like, say, if you are taking up something hard, you have to be smart to do those things. Now, you cannot ask.
Manoj Kumawat: Yay!
PAUL: Paul tells me this in at abrasion. That is the main idea. The things that I will be executing in my system can be executed in any instances.
PAUL: That's how I will be keeping it checked. So, yes, through Raquel Cloud, Linode, DigitalOcean, from anywhere. In any type of major cloud providers, most of the things will be there.
PAUL: But you have to take care of that system setup and installations.
Manoj Kumawat: Yeah, that's fine. System setup and installation, I'll take care of it, meaning installing the visual studio and other, installable applications, right? So, that I'll take care of it, but the thing is.
Manoj Kumawat: only want to know whether Oracle Cloud is something… it's good, and it is. They do say that it is AI-enabled.
Manoj Kumawat: I'm not sure what AI.
PAUL: Really easy. I have not worked a lot with Oracle Cloud. I'm majorly the AWS guy, GCP guy, Azure guy. I have not worked really with Oracle Cloud, so really.
Manoj Kumawat: Cool.
Manoj Kumawat: So, so, see, this is just a free account, okay? Which they, for 30 days, they are giving $300 credit to be used in the Oracle Cloud. After 30 days, maybe I can shift to AWS, if they have… they are providing something good. Over there, then, yeah, that would make more…
PAUL: GCP also provide you, like, close to $300 credits. Azure also provides you when you sign up.
PAUL: Oh, okay, okay. So which one?
Manoj Kumawat: So, which would go hand-in-hand with the… with your, teaching?
PAUL: And I won't be using any cloud, I will be using it only for deployment purposes.
PAUL: Okay, so really, like, you can use…
PAUL: Yeah, so you can use, like, GCP or Azure. You can get an instance, at least, of a 4GB RAM.
PAUL: Majorly, the task will be done, but for some classes.
PAUL: You need higher RAM, probably 16GB.
PAUL: So it depends upon the model selection by me, but majorly, most of the tasks can be done.
PAUL: So…
Manoj Kumawat: So the reason being why I'm going with the cloud version is because, majorly, I am on the go, meaning, like, I'm not in front of my desktop.
Manoj Kumawat: But I need a way to, you know, execute…
PAUL: Start using… then start using Lightning AI. That's why I showed in today's class Lightning. Lightning EA, you will get a Lightning EA.
PAUL: there, start using that. Explode that one, that is a good surface.
Manoj Kumawat: Lightning AI.
PAUL: Yes.
Manoj Kumawat: Okay.
Manoj Kumawat: Okay, I'll take a look at that, thanks.
PAUL: Yes.
PEG07774: Okay, Paul, I have a quick question, can I ask them?
PAUL: Quick question, go ahead then. Yeah, in the meantime, we were sharing Docker desktop, even.
Amit Singh: Oh, this is me. If I start to restart this engine, I tried this fault.
Amit Singh: So somehow this is… I mean, nothing is happening over here.
PAUL: Click on this one, enable Docker Terminal.
PAUL: Because it should show some element, that's all.
PAUL: Without… if it is not showing any error, then it becomes prominent.
PAUL: Interact with your host machine, execute directly from buffer text.
PAUL: Because I enable Doppler terminal…
Amit Singh: Nothing is happening.
PAUL: Delete and try to open once again.
PAUL: Try to kill this application and open it up.
Amit Singh: Or, should I close that with?
PAUL: Yeah, kill it, that's why I called kill.
Amit Singh: Something like rm-rf, where do I do that? Where do I do that? On the terminal?
PAUL: Yeah, open Task Manager and kill that!
PAUL: Open Task Manager in Windows.
PAUL: Like, what is the command? Ctrl-Shift-Delete, I think.
Amit Singh: Oh, I'll close this page itself, right?
PAUL: Lose the application, not the page.
PAUL: This is the application which is running. You have to kill it. Ctrl-Shift-Escape. Okay, Ctrl-Shift-Escape.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay.
PAUL: People are telling after killing and opening, it worked for me, so… Right.
Amit Singh: Just a sec.
PAUL: Generally, it takes a system restart completely, sometimes to happen, and that is one main problem.
PAUL: Alright, page 0774, you have a question, please quickly go ahead with the question.
PEG07774: Please, thank you, Paul, for your time.
Amit Singh: And.
PEG07774: So, I am install…
PEG07774: Yeah, I have installed the… on the Real Studio, I've installed the GitHub, and it is showing me open folder clone repository. Is it where we need to be, or am I missing a step here?
PAUL: Correct, correct, correct, open folder or clone repository, you are pretty much correct. There is no issue.
PAUL: So generally, when you start a project, these are the two options. You need to create a folder or clone any report that I'll be sharing in class in future.
PEG07774: I should click on Open Folder, or just.
PAUL: for the… No, no, no, you don't need to click on anything. When we start the work, then you need to…
PEG07774: Okay, sir, got it. Okay, thank you very much, sir.
PAUL: Love it.
Jagapathi: Paul shall let go.
PAUL: Excuse me.
Jagapathi: So, I'm gonna try to activate the…
Jagapathi: which are enrollment in using UV command, it is asking me to execute… set the execution policy.
PAUL: Yeah, that command that, was shared in class, just please don't…
Jagapathi: I did that, but it still keep on warping for almost an hour now.
PAUL: I tried, closing it on the…
PAUL: Because, see, even I didn't know. Okay, so, like…
PAUL: Okay, share your screen, because if there is an execution policy issue, it means that OS level something that you have to do, like shell level.
PAUL: Totally.
Jagapathi: Okay, Paul, I cannot share at the moment, probably I'll try by killing it later.
PAUL: Okay, alright, fine.
PAUL: Next, anyone said Harshit Krishanu.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Nepal.
PAUL: That's usual.
PAUL: Yeah, okay, cool.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Yeah, so I did install, Docker Desktop and, showing engine running.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Is that correct? Like, any step do I need to do for this?
PAUL: If engine running is showing, then everything is done.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Okay. Yeah, it's funny. Thank you.
Amit Singh: Paul said.
Amit Singh: Yeah, I'm getting an error, it says, Docker Desktop is unable to communicate with Windows subsystem for Linux WHL.
PAUL: then you need to… do you have WSL in your system?
Amit Singh: Yes, that version I checked on the command prompt.
PAUL: Just update your WSL. Sometimes that happens, please update your WSL once.
PAUL: Because in WSL, there has been many updates. WSL hyphen is an update. Using that command in partial is checked.
Amit Singh: I tried that it's not getting updated also.
PAUL: Show me, show me, show me, show me, you are in panelists only start.
PAUL: Anybody else? Because there is… Virtual is gone.
Sid: So that was…
PAUL: Yes, etc. Yeah, Amit, you can start sharing in the meeting.
Amit Singh: Yeah, I'm just sharing, sir.
PAUL: Yes, I've done.
Sid: Yeah, so I'm getting the same issue. I'm not able to install the WSL, after installation of the Doppler desktop, so if you could have…
PAUL: WSLs aren't responsive. Dopper is trying to communicate.
PAUL: This is a different problem. It means that your WSL is not being connected.
PAUL: Just check, like, try to update your WSA, the CLT, because that's why, because this process is a little bit different in Windows. That's why please follow this, install Doppler desktop on Windows. Again, I'm sharing, because there are a lot of steps. It's really hard for me to exactly pinpoint what is the issue.
PAUL: I know the major issue is if there is some issue with WSL in the process. If you face WSL issue, Docker Desktop will never run at you.
PAUL: Okay, that's why I'm sharing. You have to debug this. Try to quit, and try… if you try to open again. So, first of all, try to work with WSL. Check WSL is working fine. In WSL, at least try to pick an operating system like Ubuntu or anything, and try to see that it is working fine or not.
PAUL: That's the only thing.
Amit Singh: Okay.
Amit Singh: So, alright.
Amit Singh: It says it is already installed, so how do I ensure that it is working?
Amit Singh: I mean… You seem to pick some OS and then work on that.
PAUL: Yes, go to Microsoft Store, okay? So, if you open Microsoft Store, from there, you can actually install Ubuntu. If WSL is there, then only you can install Ubuntu. That is also another connection.
Amit Singh: You can open.
Amit Singh: Ubuntu I had, I had installed earlier.
Amit Singh: Okay.
PAUL: Because you have to check, because this is a WSLE.
Amit Singh: Yes, it is wrong.
PAUL: and then your Docker desktop will start working, that's it.
Amit Singh: Okay. Another issue I had with Parth, or Rob, rather, is that I'm unable to communicate with that.
Amit Singh: I think, the antivirus…
PAUL: Have you signed up?
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, all mails and all that I got. You can stop sharing this DockerTextiles thing and share me that.
PAUL: What is the issue with RAM?
PAUL: And really, like, in RAP, we'll be only working with commands. Really, even I don't pass so many props. The idea was to show you why
PAUL: Rough as compared to normal teams.
Amit Singh: Yeah, got it, got it. It's not taking the auth code, actually, I think that is where I'm stuck.
Amit Singh: Authentication code, when it comes after signing up, no? It gives an authentication code to…
Amit Singh: allow you to enter into RAP, to launch it, I think. That is not happening.
PAUL: So, basically provide… connecting your account from local to… to browser-based, I think, authentication.
Amit Singh: Check it through a different browser or something like that, that you want.
PAUL: Because really, like, exactly… because I know it's sure to work, that's fair.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay.
Amit Singh: And… Can I share again for Git? I think.
PAUL: Yeah, please push me.
PAUL: We have time, I have… 10 minutes.
PAUL: Not 10, I think 5 minutes, but make it quick.
Amit Singh: Yeah, yeah. So, this is fine, as far as, is concerned…
PAUL: This is the wrap page.
Amit Singh: Pardon?
PAUL: This is the wrap page. Do you want to sign in or sign up?
Amit Singh: No, no, not the wrap. Can you see my, Windows or the screen?
PAUL: No, I cannot see. I can see only your rapid.
PAUL: Jagaphati, you want to ask anything? See, guys? Quickly, please let me know. Paul, can I share my screen for a minute, or docker?
PAUL: Weekly… okay, I am adding you to panelists, but remember, like, we have just a few… Jagapati, you have raised your hand, really, you have questioned, please let me know.
PAUL: Otherwise, please, Pavankana, Krishanu.
Sid: Okay.
PAUL: I shouldn't…
Sid: Now, I can see the share option.
PAUL: Yes, yes, start sharing, don't… I think you were in Panelist, no?
Sid: Yes, yes.
PAUL: Yes, yes, then start sharing. If you're in panelists, don't ask me. That Paul can answer. Start sharing. Multiple screen sharing is an event.
Sid: Okay.
Sid: So I'm sharing my screen, so I installed Docker, then it shows the same command, somebody else was also showing. But when I install this, it is failing, actually.
Sid: So what I need to do here…
PAUL: Yeah, really, like, this is Windows, so direct solution. This is… the item is not recognized, WSA. You don't have WSL in your system.
PAUL: That's why it's still not getting recognized.
Sid: Okay, so…
PAUL: Install WSN.
Sid: Okay, I need to install WSL again.
PAUL: I shared the documentation, please look into that documentation once.
Sid: And the image.
PAUL: docker.com.
Sid: Okay.
PAUL: There you have the step-by-step to install WS and all those things.
PAUL: Because right now, WSL is not available in your system, so Docker Desktop won't work. You have to do the installation of this one, WSL.
Sid: Okay, could you ping the link again?
PAUL: It's already in the chat, okay?
Sid: We started after Docker.
PAUL: Okay, again, I appreciate it. Please do.
Sid: Thank you.
Sid: Thank you, I'll go through it.
PAUL: Anybody else? Krish, I know people, please? Otherwise,
PAUL: Askai Soltana, you have raised. Go on.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Before tomorrow's session, do we need to refresh every 12 weeks?
PAUL: No, no, no, nothing.
PAUL: Tomorrow, just a simple introduction, theoretical fact, not so much back.
PAUL: Okay, thank you. So, nothing you need to worry about. Tomorrow, like, simple, the things that are… the idea is much more theory.
PAUL: And then, from next week, we'll start much more with the practical stuff.
Pavankanna Polavarapu: Thank you.
Amit Singh: Oh.
PAUL: Yes. No, no, no, see, you don't need to open GitGUI, Ameth.
Amit Singh: So then, Paul, sir, how does this look? Like, I mean…
PAUL: it's only OpenVS Code.
PAUL: gate you don't need to open, it's just there. Okay.
PAUL: Okay. In VS Code, and you should have that clone option. To make that clone option enable, I told everyone to install database.
PAUL: That's the only thing.
Amit Singh: No, tell me.
PAUL: That clone option, that third option.
PAUL: Third option, yeah, yes, yes, yes. When you click on that.
Amit Singh: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now you can see scanning for Git repository, so it… I know that Git is there in your system.
PAUL: Okay, this is fine, nothing to worry about. Yes, yes.
Amit Singh: So it'll work, right?
PAUL: Yes, it will work. Right now, as you can see, these are the recent changes based on… so everything will work, don't worry.
Amit Singh: Perfect, perfect. Okay, I'll find out about the WSL, or maybe I'll uninstall and reinstall it.
PAUL: Yes, just try that. Go through the official documentation of that.
Amit Singh: Yeah, sure.
PAUL: Thank you, thank you so much. I have issue with Docker on multiple try-up restarts, it worked. Thank you, okay. Windows, like, really, a lot of restarts are required, but at the end, if it is working, it's good.
PAUL: Anybody else? See, guys, now I have to close the session so quickly, you can let me know.
PAUL: Anybody else? Krishanu, Santra?
PAUL: Nobody is?
PAUL: Okay, looks like, no more. Amit, you can stop sharing. I'll just stop the sharing. All right, guys, so tomorrow, we will continue with the first, like, the journey from 2021. We'll start with the research paper, then fundamental things about RAC, the core components.
PAUL: pros and cons, why RAG, why not LLM? Okay, so all those things will be…
PAUL: talking about, okay? So, pretty much the fundamentals, but I feel that everyone should
PAUL: Okay, so, like, that's why you enrolled, because this course is only for RAM.
PAUL: Once you start knowing the basics, so it will be good. So please attend tomorrow's class, don't miss it.
PAUL: All right, guys, so bye-bye, everyone. Thanks for joining.
Amit Singh: Thank you, thank you, Paulson.
PAUL: Amit Ghana, U, Demi, you were asking?
PAUL: Okay. Can you reply to my mail? Okay, Garyji, once you have dropped, I will look into your mail and I will get back.
PAUL: Amit Kumar, any rad. Rakkos is there.
PAUL: And right now, I'm recording one live course. Okay, that course, I think next month, we'll be providing you match, okay?
PAUL: Alright, guys.
PAUL: So, bye-bye, everyone, thanks for joining.